<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="crane" name="Kakita Master Artisan" id="crane_kakita_master_artisan">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>artisan</Tag>
      <Tag>crane_artisan</Tag>
      <Tag>advanced</Tag>
      <Tag>crane_advanced</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills/>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="The Master's Touch" rank="1" id="crane_the_masters_touch">
        <Description>
The Master Artisan transcends the social demands of art
to focus on creating works of lasting magnifi cence which
transform those who witness them. You may attempt to
create such a work or performance with a chosen art Skill
roll at TN 40. A success results in a creation or performance
that awes everyone who witnesses its fi rst public appearance.
You gain 5 points of Glory, +1 additional point of
Glory for each Raise called on the roll. Everyone in the
audience at the art’s unveiling/performance gains one bonus
Void Point (which can exceed their normal maximum)
for the next 24 hours; if you successfully called at least
4 Raises on the roll, they gain two bonus Void Points instead.
(The effects of this technique cannot stack.)
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Mastery Unbounded" rank="2" id="crane_mastery_unbounded">
        <Description>
At this level of skill, the Master Artisan’s skills become
truly legendary. You gain a bonus of +2k0 with your chosen
art Skill rolls. If you are trained as a Kakita Artisan,
you may select a third chosen art from your School Skills.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Perfect Art" rank="3" id="crane_the_perfect_art">
        <Description>
The final secret of the Master Artisans is a level of excellence
that transcends the normal bounds of mortal capability, producing
art that literally comes to life. Once per month when
creating a work or performance with one of your chosen arts,
you may spend two Void Points and then roll [chosen art] /
Awareness at TN 50. With a success, the art comes to life—
birds fly off a painting, the characters of a play manifest on
the stage, the statue of a Fortune comes to life, and so forth.
The specific nature of the manifestation, and what action
it takes after appearing, is chosen by the GM—but it
will always be helpful to you, and will usually be something
awe-inspiring and extraordinary. The manifestation
normally lasts only a few minutes, but if you successfully
call four Raises on the skill roll it will last for one hour.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements>
      <Requirement field="void" type="ring" min="5">Void Ring: 5</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="awareness" type="trait" min="5">Awareness: 5</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="*artisan" type="skill" min="8">At least one Kakita Artisan chosen art Skill must be Rank 8 or higher</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="crane" type="tag">Be a member of Crane clan</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="rpg" type="more">
		If you are trained as a Kakita Artisan, you must have the Great Potential in the Skill of one of your chosen arts.  If you are not trained as a Kakita Artisan, you must be a Crane with both the Prodigy advantage and Great Potential advantage in either Acting, an Artisan skill, or a Perform skill.  This single skill becomes your chosen art for the purposes of this school's techniques.
	  </Requirement>
    </Requirements>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
