<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="phoenix" name="Asako Inquisitors" id="phoenix_asako_inquisitors">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>monk</Tag>
      <Tag>phoenix_monk</Tag>
      <Tag>advanced</Tag>
      <Tag>phoenix_advanced</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills/>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Eye of the Inquisitor" rank="1" id="phoenix_eye_of_the_inquisitor">
        <Description>
The Asako Inquisitors are taught to focus their will to
disrupt the unnatural magic of blasphemers and criminals.
You are considered one Rank higher in your original
Shugenja School for the purposes of casting spells. Nonshugenja
Inquisitors instead gain one Kiho, for which you
must meet all prerequisites.
During a skirmish you may use a Complex Action to
prepare a disruption of enemy magic. At any point later
in the same skirmish when an opponent is casting a spell,
you may as a Free Action force him to make two additional
Raises on his spell-casting roll. These additional Raises
have no effect other than to raise the TN of the roll. Once
this is done, you must take another Complex Action if you
wish to ready another disruption.
     </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Trials of Jade" rank="2" id="phoenix_the_trials_of_jade">
        <Description>
An Inquisitor finds the weakness in his enemies and exploits
it, bringing them the Emperor’s justice. When casting
any spell, you may spend a Void Point for the spell to
count as jade or crystal for the purposes of reducing or
defeating your target’s Reduction or Invulnerability traits.
If you cannot cast spells, you may instead make a melee
attack as a Simple Action instead of a Complex Action
when facing an opponent you know has violated the Empire’s
laws regarding the legal forms of magic.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Conviction of Purity" rank="3" id="phoenix_conviction_of_purity">
        <Description>
Those who commit the unpardonable sin of breaking the
Emperor’s laws concerning magic are unable to stand
against you. You are considered one Rank higher in
your original Shugenja School for the purposes of casting
spells. Non-shugenja Inquisitors instead gain one additional
Kiho, for which you must meet all prerequisites.
You may now prepare a disruption (as per your Rank One
technique) as a Simple Action instead of a Complex Action,
and opponents whose spells are disrupted require
three additional Raises rather than two.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements>
      <Requirement field="void" type="ring" min="4">Void Ring: 4</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="*any" type="ring" min="3">Any Ring: 3</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="*any" type="ring" min="3">Any Ring: 3</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="lore_law" type="skill" min="4">Lore: Law: 4</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="lore_shugenja" type="skill" min="3">Lore: Shugenja: 3</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="rpg" type="more">
Must be able to cast spells of Mastery Level
4 in one element OR have the ability to make melee
attacks as a Simple Action and possess the Phoenix
Sacred Weapon (the Inquisitor’s Strike). May not
be Tainted
      </Requirement>
    </Requirements>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
