<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="spider" name="Daigotsu Bushi School" id="spider_daigotsu_bushi_school">
    <Trait>strength</Trait>
    <Honor>1.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>spider_bushi</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="hunting" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="intimidation" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="jiujutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="kenjutsu" emphases="Katana"/>
      <Skill id="kyujutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="lore_shadowlands" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>bugei</Wildcard>
        <Wildcard>low</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="The Way Of The Spider" rank="1" id="spider_the_way_of_the_spider">
        <Description>
The Daigotsu Bushi must walk the fi ne line between using the
Taint to power his body and hiding its effects in public. At the
beginning of each Round, you may choose to either reduce
TN penalties from Wound Ranks by your Strength Trait Rank
plus your Taint Rank until the end of the Round, or increase
your damage rolls by the same amount. Additionally, the TN
on any roll made to detect the presence or effects of the Shadowlands
Taint on you is increased by 10.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Aura Of Blood" rank="2" id="spider_aura_of_blood">
        <Description>
The presence of the Daigotsu Bushi can be unsettling to those
who are unprepared to face it. You may spend a Void Point as
a Simple Action to activate this Technique. While this Technique
is active, you and all of your allies within 30’ add +2k0
to the total of all damage rolls. This lasts for a number of
Rounds equal to your Taint Rank plus your Strength Trait
Rank. This bonus is not cumulative with other applications
of Aura of Blood. Using this Technique while under its effects
refreshes its duration.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Ashura's Wing" rank="3" id="spider_ashuras_wing">
        <Description>
The Daigotsu Bushi moves and strikes as swiftly as ash borne
away by the wind. You may make melee attacks as a Simple
Action instead of a Complex Action.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Devouring Wrath" rank="4" id="spider_devouring_wrath">
        <Description>
By the power of Fu Leng, the Legionnaire feeds
on the strength of his enemies. Any time you
hit an opponent in melee, you immediately
regain 5 Wounds. This can potentially grant
additional Wounds beyond your normal
maximum, but this bonus will not increase
over 20 Wounds. Excess Wounds are
lost at the end of the skirmish.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Inhuman Assault" rank="5" id="spider_inhuman_assault">
        <Description>
The wrath of a Daigotsu bushi is like that of a rampaging
beast. Once per skirmish, you may launch into a series of
bone-shattering blows by making a melee attack as a Complex
Action. This attack ignores the bonuses and effects of
armor (including Reduction from armor) and any Stance the
target assumes. If the strike hits, the target cannot gain the
bonuses of armor or Stance to his Armor TN for a number of
Rounds equal to your Taint Rank plus your Strength Trait. If
your opponent is in the Full Attack Posture, he still retains the
-10 Armor TN penalty.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
    <Outfit koku="3" bu="0" zeni="0">
      <Item>Light Armor</Item>
      <Item>Sturdy Clothing</Item>
      <Item>Daisho</Item>
      <Item>Any 1 Weapon</Item>
      <Item>Traveling Pack</Item>
    </Outfit>
  </School>
  <School clanid="spider" name="Chuda Shugenja School" id="spider_chuda_shugenja_school">
    <Trait>willpower</Trait>
    <Affinity>nonvoid</Affinity>
    <Honor>0.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>shugenja</Tag>
      <Tag>spider_shugenja</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill rank="1" id="calligraphy" emphases="Cipher"/>
      <Skill id="hunting" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="lore_maho" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="lore_shadowlands" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="spellcraft" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="stealth" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>any</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells>
      <Spell id="commune"/>
      <Spell id="sense"/>
      <Spell id="summon"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="1" element="anynodefic"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="3" element="maho"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="2" element="mahonodefic"/>
    </Spells>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Blood Like Water" rank="1" id="spider_blood_like_water">
        <Description>
The Chuda have existed for centuries, hidden among the people of Rokugan
and concealing the true nature of their dark arts.
When casting a maho spell, you may declare one
Raise to conceal the corrupted nature of the magic.
The spell functions exactly as normal, but there will
be no outward sign that it is anything other than traditional
elemental magic. You may declare a second
Raise to reduce all Shadowlands Taint normally acquired
by a maho spell to only one Point, regardless
of the spell’s Mastery level. Alternatively, you may
sacrifi ce one point of Honor to reduce all Taint normally
acquired by the spell to one Point.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
    <Outfit koku="3" bu="0" zeni="0">
      <Item>Robes</Item>
      <Item>Wakizashi</Item>
      <Item>Knife</Item>
      <Item>Scroll Satchel</Item>
      <Item>Traveling Pack</Item>
    </Outfit>
  </School>
  <School clanid="spider" name="Daigotsu Courtier School" id="spider_daigotsu_courtier_school">
    <Trait>perception</Trait>
    <Honor>1</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>courtier</Tag>
      <Tag>spider_courtier</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="acting" rank="1"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="courtier" emphases="Manipulation"/>
      <Skill id="etiquette" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="meditation" rank="1"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="sincerity" emphases="Deceit"/>
      <Skill id="temptation" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>high</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Insidious Whispers" rank="1" id="spider_insidious_whispers">
        <Description>
Every student of the Daigotsu Courtiers is accomplished at
the art of masking his nature, preventing his true intentions
and capabilities from being discovered by others. You are
skilled at hiding your intentions and the symptoms of Taint.
You gain a Free Raise when using Sincerity (Deceit). Any
rolls made to detect your Taint (such as the techniques of the
Kuni) have their TN increased by an amount equal to 5 x your
School Rank. You add your School Rank to your Honor Rank
whenever another is attempting to discern your Honor Rank.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Cracks In The Wall" rank="2" id="spider_cracks_in_the_wall">
        <Description>
The Daigotsu courtier is taught to drop subtle, seemingly innocuous
conversational hints that disrupt the focus and attention
of those around him. Any time you are engaged in
conversation, you may spend a Void point and make a Courtier
(Manipulation) / Awareness roll (as a Simple Action) at TN
25 to force everyone within 20 feet of you to suffer a penalty
of –1k1 to all their Etiquette and Perform Skill rolls for the
next hour. They are not aware of the source for their lack of
focus. This effect cannot be stacked.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Darkness Cannot Be Trapped" rank="3" id="spider_darkness_cannot_be_trapped">
        <Description>
At this rank, the Spider courtier is taught to defl ect attention
and blame from himself, spreading disharmony among his
foes while avoiding the price of his own actions. Any time
you are the focus of suspicion or accusation, you may spend
a Void point as a Simple Action to try to shift the blame to
someone else who is present at the moment of the accusation.
You must make a Contested Roll of your Sincerity (Deceit) / Awareness
versus the victim’s Sincerity (Honesty) / Awareness
in order to make the shifting of blame stick. (If your attempt
seems weak or poorly justifi ed, the GM can award bonuses
to your victim’s attempt to defend himself.) With a success,
everyone who heard you will believe your target is the real
culprit, until presented with evidence to the contrary.
This technique cannot be used to get out of situations in
which you are clearly and inescapably guilty (e.g. standing
over the dead magistrate with a bloody knife in your hand),
nor can it shift blame to someone who is not present.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Touch Of Sin" rank="4" id="spider_the_touch_of_sin">
        <Description>
At this level of training, the Spider’s mastery of manipulation
and misdirection allows his words to twist the thoughts of
others, temporarily leading them into weakness, aggression,
and confusion. A number of times per session equal to your
School Rank, you may speak with someone for a few minutes
and then make a Contested Roll of your Courtier (Manipulation)
/ Willpower against their Etiquette (Courtesy) / Willpower.
If you succeed, they acquire one of the seven Consumed
by Shourido Disadvantages (your choice) for a number
of hours equal to your School Rank. By calling two successful
Raises on this roll, you can infl ict a second Consumed by
Shourido Disadvantage of your choice on the same person for
the same period of time. (You cannot use this technique on the
same person twice in the same day.)
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Embrace of Darkness" rank="5" id="spider_the_embrace_of_darkness">
        <Description>
The final lesson of the Daigotsu Courtier School teaches
its students to lead their enemies into paths of aggression
and violence. By speaking with someone for at
least fi fteen minutes, you may make a Contested Roll
of your Sincerity (Deceit) / Awareness against their
Etiquette (Courtesy) / Perception. If your target currently
has one of the Consumed by Shourido Disadvantages,
you gain a +5k0 bonus to this roll. With a success,
you may convince your target to treat some other person,
group, institution, or clan as their enemy. This cannot be
used to turn someone directly against his lord or the Emperor.
Subject to that limitation, the target will continue
to believe in this enmity until presented with evidence
to the contrary.
This technique cannot be used against the same
person more than once per month.
          </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
    <Outfit koku="3" bu="0" zeni="0">
      <Item>Sensible Clothing</Item>
      <Item>Wakizashi</Item>
      <Item>Calligraphy Set</Item>
      <Item>Traveling Pack</Item>
    </Outfit>
  </School>
  <School clanid="spider" name="Order of the Spider Monk" id="spider_order_of_the_spider_monk">
    <Trait>agility</Trait>
    <Honor>1.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>monk</Tag>
      <Tag>spider_monk</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="athletics" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="jiujutsu" rank="2"/>
      <Skill id="lore_theology" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="meditation" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="polearms" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>any</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="The Dark Path" rank="1" id="spider_the_dark_path">
        <Description>
The Order of the Spider teaches strength and mastery of oneself,
even the darkness that hides within the soul. You gain
a bonus of +1k0 to the total of all attack rolls made using
unarmed strikes or with polearms. You also add twice your
School Rank to your Armor TN against all melee attacks.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Drawing In The Strike" rank="2" id="spider_drawing_in_the_strike">
        <Description>
Mastery of the body is a step to the path of power, and this mastery
affords tremendous endurance to those who reach it. You may
select any non-Void Ring. You gain Reduction equal to this Ring,
plus your Rank in the Shadowlands Taint, if you possess any.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Speed Of Darkness" rank="3" id="spider_speed_of_darkness">
        <Description>
The alignment of body and mind allow tremendous speed.
When using a polearm or an unarmed attack, you may make
melee attacks as Simple Actions rather than Complex Actions.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Guarded By Chi" rank="4" id="spider_guarded_by_chi">
        <Description>
Following mastery of the body comes mastery of the soul. When
you learn this Technique, you may select any one non-Void Ring.
You add twice your Rank in this Ring, plus your Shadowlands
Taint Rank (if you possess any), to the TN of any spell being cast
against you. You may choose to suppress this effect if you wish.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Darkness Unleashed" rank="5" id="spider_darkness_unleashed">
        <Description>
True mastery of the self requires drawing upon the darkness
within. You gain an additional number of Void Points per day
equal to your Shadowlands Taint rank or your Earth Ring,
whichever is higher. These may be spent exactly like normal
Void Points, except they may also be spent to add a bonus of
+1k1 to the total of your damage rolls.
        </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
    <Outfit koku="3" bu="0" zeni="0">
      <Item>Light or Heavy Armor</Item>
      <Item>Sturdy Clothing</Item>
      <Item>Any Heavy Weapon or Polearm</Item>
      <Item>Traveling Pack</Item>
    </Outfit>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
