<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="dragon" name="Hojatsu's Legacy" id="dragon_hojatsus_legacy">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>dragon_bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>alternate</Tag>
      <Tag>dragon_alternate</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Strike When You Cannot" rank="4" id="dragon_strike_when_you_cannot"><Description>The student of Hojatsu's last technique learns how to use intellect and aggression to disrupt an opponent's rythm in an iaijutsu duel. During the Assessment stage of a duel, you may take a Free Action and spend a Void Point to force a Contested Kenjutsu /Fire roll with your opponent. If you win the roll, your opponent cannot spend Void Points on the Focus roll for that duel.</Description></Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Skills />
    <Spells />
    <Requirements>
      <Requirement field="iaijutsu" type="skill" min="5">Iaijutsu 5</Requirement>
      <RequirementOption text="Replaces Mirumoto Bushi 4 or Taoist Swordsman 5">
        <Requirement field="dragon_strong_and_swift" type="rule" />
        <Requirement field="dragon_master_of_steel" type="rule" />
      </RequirementOption>
    </Requirements>
  </School>
  <School clanid="dragon" name="Student of Hitsu-Do" id="dragon_student_of_hitsudo">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>monk</Tag>
      <Tag>dragon_monk</Tag>
      <Tag>alternate</Tag>
      <Tag>dragon_alternate</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="The Way of Fire" rank="2" id="dragon_the_way_of_fire"><Description>The practitioner of Hitsu-do learns to harness his inner Fire chi, using it to empower his strikes - but this has a price, since such use of one's own Fire is also harmful. When making an unarmed attack, you may opt to call on your inner fire, but you suffer Wounds equal to your Fire x2. (Any Wound Penalties from this damage are applied after your attack roll is completed.) In return, your unarmed damage for that attack has a base DR of 0k[Fire] instead of 0k1. (This does not stack with the unarmed damage bonus from the Advantage Hands of Stone.) For mechanical purposes, using the Hitsu-do technique as using a Mystical Kiho.

Special: The Hitsu-do makes it easier for its students to master the ways of Fire. Your Fire Ring is considered to be 1 Rank higher for the purpose of learning Fire Kiho.</Description></Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Skills />
    <Spells />
    <Requirements>
      <Requirement field="jiujutsu" type="skill" trg="Hitsu-do" min="4">Jiujutsu (Hitsu-do) 4</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="fire" type="ring" min="3">Fire 3</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="dragon_the_gift_of_the_lady" type="rule">Replaces Kikage Zumi Rank 2</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="rpg" type="more">Must have access to a Hitsu-do dojo</Requirement>
    </Requirements>
  </School>
  <School clanid="dragon" name="The Transcendent Brotherhood" id="dragon_the_transcendent_brotherhood">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>monk</Tag>
      <Tag>dragon_monk</Tag>
      <Tag>alternate</Tag>
      <Tag>dragon_alternate</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Apotheosis of Fire" rank="2" id="dragon_apotheosis_of_fire"><Description>Members of the Transcendent Brotherhood seek to use pain as a means of achieving clarity of thought and spirit. Once per day, you may spend at least one hour in deep meditation and make a Meditation / Fire Roll against a TN 20. With a success, you harden yourself against physical harm done by fire and heat, although you still feel all the pain of being burned. (GMs may opt to impose partial or temporary TN penalties to represent the effects of the pain.) For a number of hours equal to your Fire Ring, you are immune to damage from normal, mundane fires and heat (not magica or extreme natural heat sources such as molten lava). One Raise on this Meditation roll will make you immune to magical sources of fire; two Raises will make you immune to damage from any source of fire, even a volcano. While experiencing the pain of being burned, and for ten minutes afterward, your intense focus and clarity of thought grant you a bonus equal to your Fire Ring to the total of all Awareness, Perception and Intelligence-based Trait and Skill Rolls.</Description></Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Skills />
    <Spells />
    <Requirements>
      <Requirement field="fire" type="ring" min="3">Fire 3</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="earth" type="ring" min="3">Earth 3</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="meditation" type="skill" min="3">Meditation 3</Requirement>
      <RequirementOption>Any Tattooed Order 2<Requirement field="dragon_blood_of_the_kami" type="rule"></Requirement><Requirement field="dragon_the_gift_of_the_lady" type="rule"></Requirement><Requirement field="dragon_swift_fist_subtle_heart" type="rule"></Requirement></RequirementOption>
    </Requirements>
  </School>
</L5RCM>