<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="crab" name="Kaiu Engineer School" id="crab_ob_kaiu_engineer_school">
    <Trait>intelligence</Trait>
    <Honor>4.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>artisan</Tag>
      <Tag>crab_artisan</Tag>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>crab_bushi</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="battle" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="craft_armorsmithing" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="craft_weaponsmithing" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="defense" rank="1"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="engineering" emphases="*any"/>
      <Skill id="lore_architecture" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="war_fan" rank="1"/>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="The Kaiu Method" rank="1" id="crab_the_kaiu_method">
        <Description>
A student of the Kaiu Method is taught
the many basic essential disciplines
the family uses to serve the Crab. You
gain a bonus of +1k0 when making any
School Skill Roll. When spending a Void
Point to augment a School Skill Roll, you
gain a bonus of +2k2 instead of +1k1.
These effects are not cumulative.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Path Of Stone" rank="2" id="crab_the_path_of_stone">
        <Description>
The Kaiu are feared on the battlefi eld for
good reason—they are the masters of both
construction and destruction. When constructing
any large structure (temple-sized
or larger), you may make an Engineering Skill
Roll at TN 25 to add an additional number of
Wounds to the structure equal to your School
Rank x 100. Also, when commanding a siege engine,
you may re-roll once any of the siege engine's damage
dice that roll below your School Rank.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Path Of The Shell" rank="3" id="crab_the_path_of_the_shell">
        <Description>
The security and protection of Crab samurai is a somber
duty all Kaiu take very seriously indeed. When crafting
any set of armor, you may double the crafting time and
cost in order to add your School Rank
to the armor's Reduction value.
You may also add half your
School Rank (rounding
up) to the armor's Armor
TN bonus.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Path Of War" rank="4" id="crab_the_path_of_war">
        <Description>
Every Kaiu is a student of battle, as are all Crab. When you
roll on the Mass Battle Chart, you may modify your result
(up or down) by an additional amount equal to half your
School Rank. Additionally, when fi ghting with a katana,
dai tsuchi, or war fan, you may make melee attacks as a
Simple Action rather than a Complex Action.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Path Of Steel" rank="5" id="crab_the_path_of_steel">
        <Description>
The greatest and most sacred duty of the Kaiu is crafting
the sacred weapons of the Crab Clan. When crafting any
weapon, you may choose to confer either a +1k0 bonus
to all attack rolls made with that weapon, or a +0k1 bonus
to all damage rolls made with that weapon. If the
weapon is a katana, you may expend all your Void Points
(a minimum of one point must be spent) to make the
blade unbreakable (as per the Sacred Weapon: Kaiu Blade
Advantage). Doing so renders you unable to recover Void
Points for one week.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
  <School clanid="crab" name="Kuni Witch Hunter School" id="crab_ob_kuni_witch_hunter_school">
    <Trait>willpower</Trait>
    <Honor>5.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>monk</Tag>
      <Tag>crab_monk</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="investigation" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="jiujutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="kenjutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="lore_maho" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="lore_shadowlands" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="meditation" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>any</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="To See The Darkness" rank="1" id="crab_to_see_the_darkness">
        <Description>
Witch-Hunters are taught both to sense the power of
Jigoku and to crush those who carry its dreadful mark.
You may attempt to detect the Taint in another person by
holding your jade pendant (or another piece of jade) and
staring intently at them. This is a Complex Action and requires
you to make a Contested Roll of your Investigation
(Interrogation) / Awareness against the target's Sincerity
(Deceit) / Willpower. You gain a +1k0 bonus to this roll
for every full Rank of Taint the target possesses. If you
succeed in the roll and the target is Tainted (has at least 1
Rank of Taint), you are able to sense the presence of the
Taint and its approximate strength. If you fail the roll or
the target is not Tainted, you gain no information.
In addition, you gain +1k1 to your rolls to
resist the Shadowlands Taint and to your
attack rolls when attacking a foe who is a
Shadowlands creature or who you know
to be Tainted.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="To Ride The Darkness" rank="2" id="crab_to_ride_the_darkness">
        <Description>
Witch-Hunters do not confi ne themselves
to rooting out Tainted men and
women—they also learn how to fi ght the
creatures of the Shadowlands, and spend considerable
time studying their strengths and weaknesses.
Any time you are confronted by a Shadowlands creature,
you may take a Free Action to roll Lore: Shadowlands
/ Intelligence at TN 20 to recall either one specifi c strength
(such as Invulnerability) or one specifi c weakness (such
as jade) for that creature. You choose whether you recall
a strength or a weakness, but the GM chooses the exact
information. You may Raise on this roll to learn additional
pieces of information—one strength or weakness per Raise.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="To Strike The Darkness" rank="3" id="crab_to_strike_the_darkness">
        <Description>
At this rank the Witch-Hunter learns to call on the power
of purity to guide and strengthen his blows. You may
make melee attacks as a Simple Action when your opponent
is a Shadowlands creature or when you know your
opponent to be Tainted.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="To Repel The Darkness" rank="4" id="crab_to_repel_the_darkness">
        <Description>
The Witch-Hunter's intense study and spiritual training
now gives him access to esoteric powers and makes it
almost impossible for the forces of darkness to deceive
him. You gain a +3k0 bonus to the roll for your Rank One
ability to detect the Taint and to the roll for your Rank
Two ability. In addition, you may learn one Kiho. (If the
optional rule allowing Kiho for non-Brotherhood monks is
in effect, this Kiho does not count against the maximum
number of Kiho you can learn, although it is subject to
their other mechanical limitations such as Mastery Level.)
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="To Shatter The Darkness" rank="5" id="crab_to_shatter_the_darkness">
        <Description>
The Witch-Hunter is now the true nemesis of Jigoku's
forces, able to strike down his enemies with unmatched
power. You gain a +4k1 bonus to your attack and damage
rolls against Shadowlands creatures and against foes you
know to be Tainted. This stacks with the attack bonus from
your Rank One technique.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
