<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="crane" name="Daidoji Scout School" id="crane_ob_daidoji_scout_school">
    <Trait>reflexes</Trait>
    <Honor>3.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>crane_bushi</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="athletics" rank="1"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="hunting" emphases="Traps"/>
      <Skill id="kenjutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="knives" rank="1"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="kyujutsu" emphases="Yumi"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="stealth" emphases="Sneaking"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>bugei</Wildcard>
        <Wildcard>low</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Surveying The Land" rank="1" id="crane_surveying_the_land">
        <Description>
The Daidoji scouts are masters of observation and pursuit,
tracking their opponents, harassing them, and delaying
them with traps and ambushes. You gain +1k0 with Stealth
and Hunting skill rolls. Any rural/improvised traps you create
are exceptionally deadly, infl icting +1k1 extra damage.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Scouring The Shadows" rank="2" id="crane_scouring_the_shadows">
        <Description>
Daidoji scouts strike from concealment, hitting their opponents
with swift and devastating attacks. When attacking
an unaware opponent you gain a bonus of +2k0 to your
attack roll.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Weaken The Resistance" rank="3" id="crane_weaken_the_resistance">
        <Description>
The Daidoji learn to strike with precision, hitting their opponents
in weak spots and evading their armor. You may
ignore any Reduction your opponent gains from wearing
armor or from school techniques. (You cannot ignore the
natural Reduction of creatures, or Reduction bestowed by
magical or supernatural effects.) If you attack an opponent
who has no Reduction from armor or techniques, you gain
+1k0 to your damage rolls.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Strike And Move" rank="4" id="crane_strike_and_move">
        <Description>
The Daidoji scout strikes with the swiftness of the wind
itself. You may make attacks as a Simple Action instead
of a Complex Action when wielding a katana, wakizashi,
knife, or bow. Your traps now infl ict +2k1 extra damage.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Cunning Of Daidoji" rank="5" id="crane_cunning_of_daidoji">
        <Description>
The true master of the Daidoji scout school needs only a
single strike, for his opponent never survives to see the
second one. During a skirmish, you may spend a Void
Point as a Free Action to attempt a deadly precision strike
on your next attack (this may be done with a melee or a
ranged attack, but cannot be done more than once in the
same Turn). Any Maneuvers called on this attack require 1
less Raise (to a minimum of 1 Raise), and if you successfully
hit you gain a bonus of +1k1 to your Damage roll.
Furthermore, if your opponent is unaware of you, your
Raises on this attack are not limited by your Void.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
  <School clanid="crane" name="Kakita Artisan School" id="crane_ob_kakita_artisan_school">
    <Trait>awareness</Trait>
    <Honor>5.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>artisan</Tag>
      <Tag>crane_artisan</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="courtier" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="etiquette" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="games_sadane" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="sincerity" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>artisan</Wildcard>
        <Wildcard>perform</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>artisan</Wildcard>
        <Wildcard>perform</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>artisan</Wildcard>
        <Wildcard>perform</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Soul Of The Artisan" rank="1" id="crane_soul_of_the_artisan">
        <Description>
The Kakita Artisan is taught from earliest youth to focus on
one specifi c form of art above all others, devoting himself
to it heart and soul and pursuing the goal of absolute perfection
within its forms. Of course, in keeping with Crane
tradition the Artisan is also taught to be a ruthless critic to
any artistic rivals. Select one of your three chosen School
Skills (Acting, an Artisan skill, or a Perform skill) as the
focus of your artistic training. This becomes your chosen
art. When making skill rolls with your chosen art, you gain
a +2k0 bonus and your Raises are not limited by your Void.
Any time you are using Games: Sadane to criticize
someone else's art or performance, you gain a Free Raise
on your skill roll.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Soul's Dream" rank="2" id="crane_the_souls_dream">
        <Description>
The Kakita Artisan is taught to use his art to affect those
around them, inspiring emotions and shifting the views
of the audience. When presenting a public performance
or display of you chosen art, you may make a Contested
Social Roll of [chosen art]/Awareness against the Etiquette
(Courtesy)/Willpower of the audience members. Those audience
members who fail their rolls are profoundly swayed
and their emotions shift in a direction you desire—becoming
friendlier, more hostile, calmer, or whatever other emotional
shift your art is designed to evoke. This emotional shift normally
lasts a number of hours equal to your Insight Rank.
Note that not all persons are equally susceptible to the
impact of art—the GM may rule that a particular individual
is affected for a shorter period of time, or award a bonus to
the resistance roll for persons whose emotions are diffi cult
to manipulate. The GM should normally have each individual
audience member roll separately to resist this technique
(this should always be done for PCs or important NPCs), but
with large groups of ordinary NPCs the GM can opt to save
time by making a single roll for most or all of them.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Free The Spirit" rank="3" id="crane_free_the_spirit">
        <Description>
You may select a second of your three chosen School Skills
as a chosen art, and all Technique bonuses and effects which
applied to your fi rst chosen art now apply to it as well. The
bonus to your chosen art skill rolls increases to +2k1.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Undying Name" rank="4" id="crane_undying_name">
        <Description>
Your art is now so magnifi cent that you can make and break
the reputations of others by depicting or referencing them in
your work. You may create a piece of art referring to another
person by rolling [chosen art]/Awareness at a TN equal to
20 plus 5x their Glory Rank. With a success, you may either
increase (if your art is complimentary) or decrease (if it is
critical) their Glory by up to 5 points, plus an additional 5
points for every Raise you make on the roll. You may call
two additional Raises to infl ict a gain of Infamy on the
target instead of a Glory change.
You may not target the same person with this technique
more than once every six months. Furthermore, persons
of high station cannot have their reputations damaged by
artists lacking in prestige—the target's Status Rank cannot
exceed your Glory or Status Rank (whichever is higher).
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Gift Beyond Price" rank="5" id="crane_gift_beyond_price">
        <Description>
You art is now so perfect that a gift of it can profoundly
change another person's attitude toward you and your
clan. Once per month, you may give a gift of your chosen
art to someone from another clan or faction. Make a Contested
Social Roll of your [chosen art]/Awareness against
their Etiquette (Courtesy)/Willpower. (The GM may award
Free Raises to you or the target of this technique based on
the type and subject of the art and the attitudes and beliefs
of the target—some people are easier to sway than others.)
With a success, you permanently alter their attitude
toward your clan/faction in a favorable direction. With a
failure, the target becomes aware of your attempt to manipulate
his emotions, and his attitude toward your clan/
faction permanently shifts in a hostile direction.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
