<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="lion" name="Matsu Beastmaster School" id="lion_ob_matsu_beastmaster_school">
    <Trait>agility</Trait>
    <Honor>5.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>lion_bushi</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="animal_handling" rank="2"/>
      <Skill id="battle" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="defense" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="iaijutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="kenjutsu" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>bugei</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="One With The Pride" rank="1" id="lion_one_with_the_pride">
        <Description>
You have trained in the highly secretive dojo of the Matsu
Beastmasters and have forged a bond with one of the
legendary Lion warcats. The lion will accompany you
wherever you go and follows basic commands
without question. No lion
will ever attack you without being
compelled to do so in some
way. You may direct one of
your warcats to Attack as
a Complex Action. Any
one warcat who is not
attacking will use the
Guard Action to protect
you.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Heart Of The Beast" rank="2" id="lion_heart_of_the_beast">
        <Description>
Your training with the warcats has
increased your physical abilities as
well as your mental bond with your lions.
An additional lion joins your pride.
You and your companion lions gain the creature
trait of Swift 2 (as described in the L5R 4th
Edition core rules, page 320), and all of your lions
gain an additional Wound Rank that changes the end
of their progression from a normal lion's to: 36: +15, 60:
Dead.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Ferocity Within" rank="3" id="lion_the_ferocity_within">
        <Description>
You strike as fi ercely as the lions with whom you have
trained. When wielding a katana, wakizashi, magari-yari,
nage-yari, or any knife, or when fi ghting unarmed, you
may make melee attacks as a Simple Action. Additionally,
you may direct one of your warcats to Attack as a Simple
Action.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="All As One" rank="4" id="lion_all_as_one">
        <Description>
The fury of the beastmaster and his pride is a whispered legend
among your clan's enemies, and for good reason. Members
of your pride may make two claw attacks per Round
instead of the normal one. You and all members of your pride
gain a bonus of +2k1 on all damage rolls made when fi ghting
alongside one another. Finally, when you direct a warcat
to Attack (a Complex Action for lions), the warcat may also
make a Simple Move Action during the same Round.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="With The Soul Of A Lion" rank="5" id="lion_with_the_soul_of_a_lion">
        <Description>
United by your leadership and companionship, your pride
has become fearsome indeed. An additional lion joins your
pride. All of your warcats gain +10 Armor TN, +2 Reduction,
and +2 Fear.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
