<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="mantis" name="Yoritomo Shugenja School" id="mantis_ob_yoritomo_shugenja_school">
    <Trait>perception</Trait>
    <Affinity>water</Affinity>
    <Deficiency>earth</Deficiency>
    <Honor>4.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>shugenja</Tag>
      <Tag>mantis_shugenja</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="athletics" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="calligraphy" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="knives" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="lore_theology" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="meditation" rank="1"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="sailing" emphases="Navigation"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>any</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells>
      <Spell id="commune"/>
      <Spell id="sense"/>
      <Spell id="summon"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="1" element="air"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="2" element="fire"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="3" element="water"/>
    </Spells>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Child Of The Sea" rank="1" id="mantis_child_of_the_sea">
        <Description>
The family line of the Yoritomo who possess the talent for
magic have a strong bond with the sea and with weather
as a whole. You may expend one spell slot to alter the wind
conditions in your current location by one degree. If you
also spend a Void Point, you may instead shift the entire
weather status one degree. You may expend a maximum
combined total of spell slots and/or Void Points equal to
your School Rank each Round to enact these shifts. These
shifts affect an area a number of miles equal to your
School Rank in all directions from your current location.
You gain a Free Raise on all Thunder spells.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
  <School clanid="mantis" name="Mantis Brawler School" id="mantis_ob_mantis_brawler_school">
    <Trait>agility</Trait>
    <Honor>3.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>mantis_bushi</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="athletics" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="commerce" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="intimidation" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="jiujutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="knives" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="sailing" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>weapon</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Way Of The Drunken Fist" rank="1" id="mantis_way_of_the_drunken_fist">
        <Description>
The basic techniques of the Mantis Brawlers are based on
the need to prevail in chaotic fi ghts on tilting ship decks…
or when reeling drunk through a sake house. Brawlers are
tough and slippery fi ghters who evade the grip of their enemies
while striking them at every opportunity. If you are
Prone, you do not suffer any penalties to your Armor TN
or to your attacks with Small weapons (or when unarmed).
You still gain the Prone Armor TN bonus against ranged
attacks. Also, you gain a bonus of +1k0 to rolls made to
take control of Grapples and to your damage rolls with
unarmed strikes, improvised weapons, and Small weapons.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Drunk Loses His Sandal" rank="2" id="mantis_drunk_loses_his_sandal">
        <Description>
Mantis Brawlers learn to be swift and fl exible fi ghters who
attack their foes from unexpected directions, often deliberately
offering the appearance of weakness in order to
create openings. If you successfully perform the Feint maneuver,
you may choose to reduce the extra damage from
the Feint by 5 in order to add +5 to your Armor TN until
the start of your next Turn; if you were Prone when you
performed the Feint, you add +10 instead.
Also, immediately after an enemy attack resolves against
you (whether or not the attack hit or infl icted damage on
you), you may take a Free Action to become Prone.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Drunk Never Falls" rank="3" id="mantis_drunk_never_falls">
        <Description>
The third lesson of the Mantis Brawler is to win even when
exhausted, dead drunk, or clubbed on the head. During a
skirmish, you do not suffer any penalties for being Fatigued
or Dazed, nor do you suffer any penalties for intoxication.
If you become Stunned, you may still take one
Simple Action per Round.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Two Drunks Dance" rank="4" id="mantis_two_drunks_dance">
        <Description>
The erratic bobbing, squirming, and weaving of the Mantis
Brawler creates additional opportunities for him to attack
his foe. You may attack as a Simple Action when fi ghting
unarmed, with an improvised weapon, or with a Small
weapon.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Drunk Pounds A Door" rank="5" id="mantis_drunk_pounds_a_door">
        <Description>
The final lesson of the Mantis Brawler is to strike so hard
his foe never gets the chance to strike back. When making
a melee attack you may spend a Void Point to deliver a
fi erce shattering blow; this attack gains a bonus of +4k1 to
both the attack roll and the damage roll. If you are Prone,
the bonus is +4k2 instead.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
  <School clanid="mantis" name="Tsuruchi Bounty Hunter School" id="mantis_ob_tsuruchi_bounty_hunter_school">
    <Trait>agility</Trait>
    <Honor>4.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>mantis_bushi</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="athletics" rank="1"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="hunting" emphases="Tracking"/>
      <Skill id="intimidation" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="investigation" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="kenjutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="kyujutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="lore_underworld" rank="1"/>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="A Hunter's Sense" rank="1" id="mantis_a_hunters_sense">
        <Description>
A Tsuruchi bounty hunter is well known as a fi erce and
terrible opponent of all who seek to evade justice, and
even those who are without guilt fi nd them intimidating.
You gain a bonus of +1k1 to any Intimidation Skill Roll
used against someone of lower caste who you believe can
help you fi nd your prey. When interacting with samurai,
this bonus is reduced to +1k0 but applies to all Social Skill
Rolls, not just Intimidation. Also, when you are hunting
a particular target, you may roll additional unkept dice
equal to your School Rank on any Hunting or Investigation
Skill Rolls used to track the quarry down.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="No Prey Escapes" rank="2" id="mantis_no_prey_escapes">
        <Description>
A true master of the Tsuruchi method has an encyclopedic
knowledge of criminals throughout the Empire and can
use them as tools to capture his prey. You may spend a
Void Point to automatically
succeed at a
Lore: Underworld Skill Roll to identify any criminals in
an area who you might be able to press for information
regarding your prey. You lose Honor as normal for associating
with such individuals, however.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Justice Of The Wasp" rank="3" id="mantis_justice_of_the_wasp">
        <Description>
The Tsuruchi hunters are merciless, but have a reputation
for bringing their prey back alive to suffer a proper sentence
for their criminal acts. When facing an opponent
who has been declared guilty of a crime by an Imperial or
a higher Mantis authority, you may make the Disarm or
Knockdown Maneuvers for one Raise less than normal. If
you successfully execute one of these Maneuvers against
an opponent, that opponent is automatically Dazed.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Twin Sting Strikes" rank="4" id="mantis_twin_sting_strikes">
        <Description>
The justice of a Tsuruchi is swift and without mercy. You
may make ranged attacks as a Simple Action when wielding
a yumi. Additionally, if facing any target decreed
guilty of a crime by an Imperial or a higher Mantis authority,
you may also make melee attacks as a Simple Action
when wielding a katana or any knife.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Eyes Of The Wasp" rank="5" id="mantis_eyes_of_the_wasp">
        <Description>
The worst truth a bounty hunter learns is that anyone can
be a fugitive; thus a bounty hunter makes careful assessments
of everyone he meets. When you identify a samurai
using a Lore: Heraldry Skill Roll, you not only learn his
Glory but also his Honor Rank and all Social and Mental
Disadvantages. Also, any opponent who may be targeted
by your Rank 3 Technique is now automatically Dazed
if you successfully hit them with an attack, regardless of
whether or not you use a Disarm or Knockdown Maneuver
on them.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
