<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="phoenix" name="Asako Henshin School" id="phoenix_ob_asako_henshin_school">
    <Trait>willpower</Trait>
    <Honor>5.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>monk</Tag>
      <Tag>phoenix_monk</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="calligraphy" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="jiujutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="lore_elements" emphases="*any"/>
      <Skill id="lore_theology" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="meditation" rank="2"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>any</Wildcard>
        <Wildcard modifier="not">low</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="The Four Mysteries" rank="1" id="phoenix_the_four_mysteries">
        <Description>
The first lesson of the mysterious Henshin is the relationship
between the individual and the Elements that comprise
all things. You may, as a Simple Action, increase or decrease
both Traits associated with one of your Rings by an amount
equal to your School Rank. This lasts for a number of minutes
equal to your Insight Rank and may be done a total
number of times per day equal to fi ve times your Insight
Rank. You may instead increase or decrease the Traits of
another in a similar manner, but only by an amount equal
to half your School Rank, rounding down (to a minimum
of 1). Altering the Traits of an unknowing or unwilling target
requires a Contested Willpower Roll. Traits reduced in
this manner do not affect a target's Rings (and thus do not
change Wound Ranks when the Earth Ring is targeted, etc.).
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Riddle Of Earth" rank="2" id="phoenix_the_riddle_of_earth">
        <Description>
The stoic and straightforward kami of Earth are the simplest
to entertain with one's riddles, and their blessings are
potent indeed. As a Simple Action, you may invoke this
Technique and gain Earth's blessing; you are immune to
all Conditional Effects (excluding Grappled and Mounted)
for a number of hours equal to your Earth Ring.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Riddle Of Air" rank="3" id="phoenix_the_riddle_of_air">
        <Description>
The capricious spirits of Air can be delighted into conferring
their blessings upon you. As a Simple Action, you
may invoke the blessing of Air. The blessing lasts a number
of hours equal to your School Rank. For the duration
of this effect, you cannot be deceived by any illusion or
other false images, and can perceive them as transparent
falsehoods. If an illusion is created by a spell of higher
Mastery Level than your Insight Rank, you and the spell's
caster must engage in a Contested Air Roll. If you are defeated,
you do not perceive the falsehood of the illusion.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Riddle Of Fire" rank="4" id="phoenix_the_riddle_of_fire">
        <Description>
The wrathful spirits of Fire can be entertained by your
riddles, if only briefl y. As a Complex Action you may invoke
Fire's blessings to increase the number of kept dice
on an unarmed damage roll (which is normally 0k1) to
your Fire Ring. This effect lasts a number of Rounds equal
to your School Rank.
Alternatively, when an opponent strikes you with a melee
attack, you may spend a Void Point to force a Contested Fire
Ring Roll. If you are successful, the number of damage dice
your opponent rolls is reduced by your Fire Ring.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Riddle Of Water" rank="5" id="phoenix_the_riddle_of_water">
        <Description>
The mercurial spirits of Water can confer their speed and
fl uidity in exchange for your riddles. You must succeed at
a Lore: Elements (Water) / Water Skill Roll against TN 20.
If successful, you may take one Complex and one Simple
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
