<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="unicorn" name="Meishodo/Horiuchi Shugenja School" id="unicorn_meishodo_horiuchi_shugenja_school">
    <Trait>stamina</Trait>
    <Affinity>earth</Affinity>
    <Deficiency>air</Deficiency>
    <Honor>4.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>shugenja</Tag>
      <Tag>unicorn_shugenja</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="calligraphy" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="craft_meishodo" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="lore_theology" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="defense" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="meditation" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="spellcraft" emphases="Spell Research" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>high</Wildcard>
        <Wildcard>bugei</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells>
      <Spell id="commune"/>
      <Spell id="sense"/>
      <Spell id="summon"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="3" element="earth"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="2" element="water"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="1" element="fire"/>
    </Spells>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Mysteries of Meishodo" rank="1" id="unicorn_mysteries_of_meishodo">
        <Description>
Meishodo is a mixture of gaijin and Rokugani magic, resulting
in a fast and powerful method of calling the kami.
Shugenja studying these methods learn to create meishodo
amulets, keyed to invoke the elements in specifi c ways.
You may create a magical amulet by making a successful
roll of Craft: Meishodo/Ring, using the Ring for the desired
spell. The TN of this roll is equal to 15 plus 5x the spell's
Mastery Level. Creating a meishodo requires a number of
hours equal to the spell's Mastery Level. If the roll is successful,
you create a small charm imbued with the prayer
to the kami that will cast the chosen spell. Each meishodo
stores only one spell, and is used in place of the scroll
normally required to cast the spell.
Casting a spell through a meishodo requires only one
Complex Action, regardless of the Mastery Level of the
spell. You do not have to make a Spell Casting Roll to
cast the spell, but the spell cannot gain any benefi ts from
Raises (not even Free Raises). You expend a spell slot as
normal.
You may only create meishodo from spells of a Mastery
Level equal or less than your Shugenja School Rank, and
can never create meishodo from spells of Mastery Level 4,
5 or 6. Other shugenja may use your meishodo if they are
proficient in meishodo magic (e.g. trained in this school).
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
  <School clanid="unicorn" name="Moto Vindicator School" id="unicorn_moto_vindicator_school">
    <Trait>willpower</Trait>
    <Honor>3.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>unicorn_bushi</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="horsemanship" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="hunting" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="investigation" emphases="Notice" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="kenjutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="kyujutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="lore_shadowlands" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>bugei</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Purity of the Breath" rank="1" id="unicorn_purity_of_the_breath">
        <Description>
The Vindicator knows the only way to combat
the Shadowlands is to maintain integrity in the
face of the foulest corruption. At the beginning
of each Round, you may choose one of two effects
to apply until the end of the Round. You may
reduce your TN penalties from Wound Ranks by
an amount equal to your School Rank plus your
Willpower. Or, you may instead choose to add a
bonus to your Armor TN equal to your School Rank plus
your Willpower.
If you are in a skirmish against creatures of the
Shadowlands, the chosen bonus is doubled.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Facing the Dark Within" rank="2" id="unicorn_facing_the_dark_within">
        <Description>
The Vindicator learns to hone his senses so that he is never
surprised by those who serve the darkness. You gain a
+2k0 bonus to all Investigation rolls. This bonus is increased
to +2k1 if you are specifi cally attempting to notice
effects of the Shadowlands Taint.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Justice of our Ancestors" rank="3" id="unicorn_justice_of_our_ancestors">
        <Description>
The Vindicator's rage at his foes knows no bounds. You
may make melee attacks as a Simple Action instead of a
Complex Action.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Avenging our Own" rank="4" id="unicorn_avenging_our_own">
        <Description>
The Vindicator's fury is provoked the most when it is directed
at those creatures he once called his brothers. You
gain a bonus of +2k0 to your attack and damage rolls
against any enemy who has attacked you in this skirmish
and against any creature with the Shadowlands Taint
whether it has attacked you or not.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Bloodied but Unbowed" rank="5" id="unicorn_bloodied_but_unbowed">
        <Description>
The Vindicator can push on past physical limits once his
goal is in sight. Once per skirmish, you may choose to keep
fi ghting despite your injuries. Activating this Technique is
a Free Action. Once it is active, while making melee attacks
you gain a bonus to the total of your damage rolls equal
to the TN penalties you are suffering from Wound Ranks.
(This uses the default Wound penalties, ignoring modifi cations
from Advantages, spells, or other such effects.) The
effects of this Technique last for two full Rounds. You may
choose to extend the effects of this Technique for an additional
Round by taking ten Wounds.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
