<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="spider" name="Goju Ninja" id="spider_goju_ninja_school">
    <Trait>agility</Trait>
    <Honor>0.0</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>ninja</Tag>
      <Tag>scorpion_ninja</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="athletics" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="kenjutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="ninjutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="stealth" rank="2"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="sincerity" emphases="Deceit"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>any</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="The Cloak Of Night" rank="1" id="spider_the_cloak_of_night">
        <Description>
The first lesson a Goju masters is the art of wrapping oneself
in shadow, gaining concealment from enemies in exchange
for making direct action more diffi cult. You may
increase your Armor TN up to a maximum amount equal
to your School Rank x 5. The TN of all your rolls other
than Athletics, Defense, and Stealth Skill Rolls is increased
by the same amount. Activating this Technique is a Simple
Action and it lasts for the duration of the skirmish.
            </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Melting Into Shadow" rank="2" id="spider_melting_into_shadow">
        <Description>
A Goju is not merely protected by the darkness but part of
it, and can blend easily within it. You gain bonus rolled
dice equal to your School Rank on any Stealth Skill Roll.
Any uncontested roll made by an opponent trying to detect
you automatically has its TN increased by an amount
equal to your School Rank x 5. You gain one Free Raise on
all attack rolls made against opponents who are unaware
of your presence.
            </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="The Shadowed Blade" rank="3" id="spider_the_shadowed_blade">
        <Description>
The Goju is a swift and merciless foe. You may make an
attack as a Simple Action rather than a Complex Action
when attacking with knives or any weapon that uses the
Ninjutsu Skill. Alternatively, when wielding shuriken, you
may take a Complex Action to make a number of ranged
attacks equal to your School Rank.
            </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Step Within Shadow" rank="4" id="spider_step_within_shadow">
        <Description>
As all darkness is one with the Goju, so too can the Goju
use the darkness to move between shadows without crossing
the space in between. You may enter any shadow large
enough to conceal an individual of your size and emerge
from any other similarly-sized shadow nearby. This is considered
a Simple Move Action. The range of this movement
is equal to your School Rank x 100 feet.
            </Description>
      </Tech>
      <Tech name="Shadow Upon The Moon" rank="5" id="spider_shadow_upon_the_moon">
        <Description>
A true Goju no longer even vaguely resembles anything human.
Your facial features are permanently erased, leaving
only a tell-tale eggshell mask in their place. In darkness or
shadows, you may dissolve your physical body into a vague
cloud of inky vapor. This is a Simple Action; changing back
into corporeal form is a Free Action. You may move at your
full speed while in incorporeal form but may not physically
interact with any object or individual and cannot be harmed
by anything except crystal. You may pass through solid matter
in a thickness of up to your School Rank x 5 in inches.
You gain +5 to your Initiative Score during the fi rst Round
(only) each time you change back to your corporeal form.
            </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
  <School clanid="spider" name="Ninube Shugenja" id="spider_ninube_shugenja_school">
    <Trait>awareness</Trait>
    <Affinity>air</Affinity>
    <Deficiency>earth</Deficiency>
    <Honor>0.0</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>shugenja</Tag>
      <Tag>spider_shugenja</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="calligraphy" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="knives" rank="1"/>
      <Skill rank="1" id="sincerity" emphases="Lying"/>
      <Skill id="stealth" rank="2"/>
      <Skill id="spellcraft" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>low</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells>
      <Spell id="commune"/>
      <Spell id="sense"/>
      <Spell id="summon"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="3" element="air"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="2" element="fire"/>
      <PlayerChoose count="1" element="water"/>
    </Spells>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Mask of the Nothing" rank="1" id="spider_mask_of_the_nothing">
        <Description>
As a Complex Action you may expend a spell slot to dissolve
your physical self and become a shadow. As a shadow
you are invisible in darkness and gain a bonus of +5k0
to your Stealth Skill Rolls under all other circumstances.
You are immune to most mundane attacks, but crystal
and magic can affect you. Magical attacks that involve
crystal or generate light double their rolled damage dice
against you. When in shadow form, if you suffer damage
that would kill you, you instead return to physical form at
once with either half of your Wounds or with the Wounds
you possessed when you entered shadow form, whichever
is lower; you are Stunned when this happens.
You may not infl ict damage on others in any way while
in shadow form, but you may cast non-damaging spells
and can speak in the form of a disembodied whisper.
You gain a Free Raise on all Nothing spells. You may
not cast maho spells.
      </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
