<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
<School clanid="crab" name="Crab Berserker" id="crab_berserker">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>crab_bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>alternate</Tag>
      <Tag>crab_alternate</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Berserker’s Rage" rank="2" id="crab_berserkers_rage">
        <Description>
            The Crab berserkers manifest their unique and dangerous gifts after spending some time – often months, sometimes even years – on the Kaiu Wall. Some berserkers call on ma- niacal fury to power their rages, while others enter the notorious “dead eye” trance, but the result is the same: superhuman strength and a near-immunity to pain. Once per skirmish, you may enter your rage dur- ing the Reactions Stage. Once begun, the rage lasts for a number of Combat Rounds equal to double your Earth Ring. (You may end it during an earlier round by spending a Void point during the Reactions Stage.) While in your rage, you cannot take the Center, De- fense, or Full Defense stances, and cannot use any non-Bugei skills. While in the raging state, you ig- nore all penalties and effects of Wound Ranks. You also gain a +2k1 bonus to all attack and damage rolls. If you are killed while raging, you remain alive and can continue to attack until the rage ends, but you cannot be healed (unless you are first targeted with the Force of Will spell) – you are dead, your body simply does not know it yet. The rage ends if you sustain Wounds equal to twice the amount that would normally kill you
                </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Skills/>
    <Spells/>
    <Requirements>
      <Requirement field="earth" type="ring" min="4">Earth Ring: 4</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="crab" type="tag">Member of Crab Clan</Requirement>
      <RequirementOption text="Replaces Hida Bushi 2 or Hiruma Bushi 2">
        <Requirement field="crab_the_way_of_the_crab" type="rule"/>
        <Requirement field="crab_torchs_flame_flickers" type="rule"/>
      </RequirementOption>
    </Requirements>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
