<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="mantis" name="Moshi Guardian of the Sun (Path)" id="mantis_moshi_guardian_of_the_sun">
    <Trait>stamina</Trait>
    <Honor>3.5</Honor>
    <Tags>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>mantis_bushi</Tag>
      <!-- <Tag>alternate</Tag> -->
      <Tag>mantis_alternate</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Defender as the Sun" rank="1" id="mantis_defender_as_the_sun">
        <Description>
The Guardians of the Sun take an oath to repel all attacks
against their sacred charges. When defending a Moshi personage
or holding in a skirmish, you may choose to either
gain a bonus of +1k0 to your attack roll or to add an additional
+1k1 to the Armor TN of a person or object you are defending
with the Guard Action. You make this determination
at the start of your Turn during each Round of the skirmish.
            </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Skills>
      <Skill id="athletics" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="defense" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="jiujutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="kenjutsu" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="lore_theology" rank="1"/>
      <Skill id="spears" rank="1"/>
      <PlayerChoose rank="1">
        <Wildcard>high</Wildcard>
        <Wildcard>bugei</Wildcard>
      </PlayerChoose>
    </Skills>
    <Spells/>
    <Requirements/>
  </School>
  <School clanid="crab" name="Kitsune Ranger" id="mantis_kitsune_ranger">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>mantis_bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>alternate</Tag>
      <Tag>mantis_alternate</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="One With the Wild" rank="2" id="mantis_one_with_the_wild">
        <Description>
Although they do not possess an ability to speak to the
kami, the Kitsune rangers are at home in the wilderness
like few others in the Empire. You gain a Free Raise on all
Hunting Skill Rolls and on any Stealth Skill Rolls made
while in a rural environment. Additionally, you gain a bonus
of +2k0 on any Contested Roll involving detection,
whether you are avoiding detection or attempting to detect
a hidden opponent.
            </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Skills/>
    <Spells/>
    <Requirements>
      <Requirement field="hunting" type="skill" min="3">Hunting: 3</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="*mantis_bushi" type="school" max="1" min="1">Replaces any Mantis Bushi 2</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="rpg" type="more">
Prior to the Kitsune joining the Mantis
Clan, this Technique may be taken as a Rank 2
Path by any bushi-trained Kitsune, regardless of
school—including those who do not have a school.
This Technique can also be taken as a Rank 2 Ronin
Technique for any ronin characters who possess a
Ally Advantage associated with the Kitsune family.
            </Requirement>
    </Requirements>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
