<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <School clanid="unicorn" name="Ide Trader" id="unicorn_ide_trader">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>courtier</Tag>
      <Tag>unicorn_courtier</Tag>
      <Tag>alternate</Tag>
      <Tag>unicorn_alternate</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Brisk Economy" rank="2" id="unicorn_brisk_economy">
        <Description>
The Ide Trader is a master of the merchant class, extending
his control across the land. You cannot lose Honor or
Glory for using the Commerce skill in public. You may
attempt to persuade someone to become a new mercantile
partner for your clan by rolling Courtier (Manipulation) /
Awareness with a bonus to the roll equal to double your
Commerce Skill Rank. For persuading a commoner the
suggested TN is 25, increased by the GM as appropriate if
the target is hostile. Persuading a samurai requires a Contested
Roll against the target’s Etiquette (Courtesy) / Willpower,
with the target gaining a bonus equal to double
his Commerce Skill Rank. (Some samurai targets may gain
additional bonuses or even be immune to this Technique
due to unshakable loyalties—the GM has fi nal say in such
matters.)
If you succeed in the roll, the target agrees to become a
part of your network of connections and commercial assets.
You may immediately gain the target as a free Ally
with 1 point of Devotion.
If you are using the optional Way of the Daimyo rules
found in the L5R RPG 4th Edition supplement Emerald
Empire, taking this Path earns you a Duty Point.
            </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Skills/>
    <Spells/>
    <Requirements>
      <Requirement field="commerce" type="skill" min="3">Commerce: 3</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="rpg" type="more">must pursue a career as a merchant patron</Requirement>
      <Requirement field="unicorn_the_heart_speaks" type="rule">Replaces Ide Emissary 2</Requirement>
    </Requirements>
  </School>
  <School clanid="unicorn" name="Moto Fanatic" id="unicorn_moto_fanatic">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>unicorn_bushi</Tag>
      <Tag>alternate</Tag>
      <Tag>unicorn_alternate</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Reckless Abandon" rank="4" id="unicorn_recless_abandon">
        <Description>
The Moto Fanatic charges into the thick of battle with no
thought to his own safety. If you are in the Full Attack
Stance, you may spend a Void Point as a Simple Action
to activate this Technique. You gain Reduction equal to
your School Rank so long as you remain in the Full Attack
Stance.
            </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Skills/>
    <Spells/>
    <Requirements>
      <Requirement field="unicorn_desert_wind_strike" type="rule">Moto Bushi School 4</Requirement>
    </Requirements>
  </School>
  <School clanid="unicorn" name="Utaku Horse Master" id="unicorn_utaku_horse_master">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>alternate</Tag>
      <Tag>unicorn_alternate</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Techs>
      <Tech name="Master of the Open Plains" rank="2" id="unicorn_master_of_the_open_plains">
        <Description>
The Utaku men devote themselves to raising and training
horses, and are without question the greatest in Rokugan
at this task. Indeed, the Unicorn claim that in all their
travels across the world they have never encountered better.
You gain a +2k0 bonus to all Animal Handling, Horsemanship,
and Hunting rolls.
            </Description>
      </Tech>
    </Techs>
    <Skills/>
    <Spells/>
    <Requirements>
      <Requirement field="unicorn_utaku" type="tag">Must be a male of the Utaku family</Requirement>
      <RequirementOption text="Replaces any Unicorn school 2">
        <Requirement field="*unicorn_bushi" type="school" min="1" max="1"/>
        <Requirement field="*unicorn_shugenja" type="school" min="1" max="1"/>
        <Requirement field="*unicorn_monk" type="school" min="1" max="1"/>
        <Requirement field="*unicorn_courtier" type="school" min="1" max="1"/>
        <Requirement field="*unicorn_ninja" type="school" min="1" max="1"/>
      </RequirementOption>
    </Requirements>
  </School>
</L5RCM>
