<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
	<SpellDef name="Blessed Wind" area="10' radius around the caster" mastery="1" element="air" range="Personal" duration="Concentration" id="blessed_wind">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Special (you may target another with this spell with 3 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You summon a swirling aura of winds to protect you from ranged attacks. The buffeting winds deflect arrows and other projectiles. While you maintain your concentration, this spell adds + 15 to your Armor TN versus all non-magical ranged attacks.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="By the Light of the Moon" area="20' radius around the caster" mastery="1" element="air" range="Personal" duration="1 minute" id="by_the_light_of_the_moon">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+5' radius)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You call upon the kami to reveal that which has been hidden. All concealed objects within the area of effect appear as slightly luminous outlines to you. Any non-magical concealment is revealed, including secret compartments, trap doors, concealed weapons, etc. Only you can see the presence of these objects.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Cloak of Night" area="One object" mastery="1" element="air" range="Touch" duration="1 hour" id="cloak_of_night">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 hour)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You can call upon the kami trap an object in their embrace, hiding it from the sight of mortal beings. You may target anyone non-living object smaller than you. This object becomes invisible the naked eye. Attempts perceive it magically will automatically succeed if the Mastery level of the spell used is higher than that of this spell. Spells of equal Mastery Level require a Contested Air Roll to detect the hidden object. The object is still physically present and can be touched, smelled, or sensed with any normal sense other than vision.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Legacy of Kaze-no-Kami" area="One known individual within range" mastery="1" element="air" range="School Rank x 10 miles" duration="Special" id="legacy_of_kazenokami">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+1 individual)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10 miles)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You are able call upon the spirits of the wind to take form as a bird and carry a message for you. The bird that is created by this spell appears perfectly normal in all regards, but if it takes any damage it dissipates into wind immediately, ending the spell. Upon creating the bird, you may speak tit, giving it a spoken message of up tone minute in length. The bird will then flyaway to deliver the message the person (or persons) specified when the spell is cast. The bird will fly to their location, deliver the message via a whisper (it can be overheard by others, but not easily), and then disappear. If the bird is unable to reach the individual, but they are within range (if they are within a building with no windows, for instance will remain outside waiting for up tone week before disappearing. If the person specified by the spell is not within range, the bird will fly away in a random direction and disappear when it is out of your line of sight.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Nature's Touch" area="One Creature" mastery="1" element="air" range="10'" duration="Special" id="natures_touch">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You are able to use the spirits of the wind to speak to an animal and ensure that it understands what you are saying. This spell works only on natural animals, and will not work with Shadowlands creatures or creatures from other realms. It does not guarantee that the animal will regard you positively or that it will fulfill requests made of it, but the creature will understand anything you tell it (within its ability (naturally - political relationships will have no meaning ta horse. no matter how many times you explain them). This spell lasts as long as you maintain your full and undivided attention on the animal and continue speaking to it.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Tempest of Air" area="A cone 75' long and 15' wide at its end" mastery="1" element="air" range="Personal" duration="Instantaneous" id="tempest_of_air">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>thunder</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+5' to the width of the cone)</Raise>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5' to the length of the cone)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+5 to Air TN against Knockdown per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You summon a powerful gust of air emanating from your position that crashes into all in its path, knocking them the ground. All targets within the area of effect suffer 1k1 Wounds and must make a Contested Roll using their Earth against your Air. Every target that fails suffers Knock down.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="To Seek the Truth" area="One individual touched (may be the caster)" mastery="1" element="air" range="Personal / Touch" duration="5 minutes" id="to_seek_the_truth">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You call upon the wind to purge the mind of your target, granting him clarity. This spell may negate temporary mental or social penalties suffered as a result of a mechanical effect, including Techniques, Wound Ranks, or other spells. The TN of the Spell Casting Roll made to cast this spell is increased by an amount equal the Technique Rank, Wound Rank, or spell Mastery Level used create the penalty in the first place. Disadvantages permanently possessed by an individual may not be countered using this spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Token of Memory" area="One small (1 cubic foot or smaller) illusory object" mastery="1" element="air" range="10'" duration="1 hour" id="token_of_memory">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+1 cubic foot in size of illusory object)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 hour)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You can create a flawless illusion of one object. The item appears real in every way up until the spell expires, at which point it disappears. If you are attempting create a specific, familiar object. Such as another samurai's katana, you must declare one Raise, and (hat individual may make a Contested Roll using his Perception against the total of your Spell Casting Roll to detect the forgery. Images created by this spell are completely stationary, and if placed in a situation where they must move (such as floating in water), disappear instantly. An image of a katana could be created sitting on a rack, for example, but not in a samurai's obi because it would not be able to move with the samurai. Objects created with this spell have no true physical substance and cannot bear weight or inflict damage.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Way of Deception" area="One illusory duplicate of the caster" mastery="1" element="air" range="20'" duration="Concentration plus 5 minutes" id="way_of_deception">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+1 duplicate per 2 Raises)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5 feet)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (see spell description)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You can entreat the capricious spirits of the wind create a perfect duplicate image of you a short distance away. The illusion exactly reflects your appearance at the time the spell is cast, including your clothing and any equipment. The illusion may appear anywhere within the spells range, and will perform whatever actions you perform while it is in effect. (If you sit down, for instance, your duplicate will sit down as well, even if there is nothing so sit on.) Once you leave the normal range of the spell, the duplicate disappears. If you make two Raises on the Spell Casting Roll, you may leave the area of effect and the illusion will remain in whatever position it was in when you left for as long as you continue concentrating on maintaining the spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Yari of Air" area="One created weapon" mastery="1" element="air" range="Personal or 20'" duration="5 minutes" id="yari_of_air">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
			<Tag>thunder</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+5 minutes)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5 feet)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You summon a swirling weapon of pure air, only visible as a foggy outline. The weapon's default form is a yari, but one Raise can change its form to any other spear of your choosing. The weapon has DR 1k1. If you do not possess the Spears Skill, you may instead use your School Rank in its place. If you do possess the Spears Skill, using this weapon grants you one Free Raise that can only be used on the Feint or Increased Damage Maneuvers. This weapon disappears if is lost from your hand. Instead of summoning the yari for yourself, you may cause it to appear in the hands of an ally within 20 feet. He is treated as the caster for all purposes of the spell, but he does not gain the Free Raise bonus.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Commune" area="Self" mastery="1" element="all" range="20'" duration="Concentration" id="commune">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>See Spell Description</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell can be cast in any element save Void. It allows the caller to speak with one of the local elemental kami, asking it a few questions, which it will answer honestly to the best of its ability. Typically this spell will invoke the most active and energetic spirit of the chosen element in the area of effect; if all of the local spirits are quiescent. The GM may require the caster call 1 or 2 Raises to wake up a local spirit enough answer questions. A spirit reached with Commune will answer questions. The caster may Raise to get more questions (one per Raise). The caster may also Raise for clarity, get a more accurate and informative answer the questions. (Kami are notorious for their inability Tully comprehend human behavior, and asking questions without Raises for clarity can often result in confusing, enigmatic, or incomplete answers.) Spirits snot forget anything. So theoretically a shugenja can ask a spirit about something that happened decades ago; however, they do not experience time in the same way as mortals. Straying task about something from long agile usually require Raises in order make the caster's wishes clear the spirit. The nature of the information which spirits can impart varies by element: Air spirits tend to be playful and easily distracted, conveying information as emotions or as riddles and jokes. Since they are more interested in feelings than in facts, and enjoy playing games with those speak with them, communing with an Air spirit can sometimes be very frustrating. Earth spirits are straightforward and matter-of-fact, often blunt, but are rather uninterested in the behavior of mortals, have a poor understanding of human emotion, and tend to be overly focused on obscure details such as the color of a piece of clothing or the weight of a horse. Fire spirits are irritable and temperamental, and are often angry at being summoned unless they are propitiated with an offering of something burn. On the other hand, if a shugenja can please them they tend to offer the clearest and most accurate information. Water spirits communicate their knowledge through soundless visual images. This can be very helpful ta shugenja trying investigate a past incident, but since the spirits cannot convey scent, sound, or emotion, the information they provide can often be incomplete or misleading.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Sense" area="50' radius from the caster" mastery="1" element="all" range="Personal" duration="Instantaneous" id="sense">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell can be cast in any of the four standard elements. It allows the caster sense the presence, quantity, and rough location of elemental spirits (not the evil spirits known as kansen) of that element within the range of the spell. This is most frequently applied when looking for spirits with which commune (see below), but can also be useful as a crude, basic location device. For example, a caster lost in the wilderness could cast Sense (Water) in hopes of locating a source of drinking water.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Summon" area="1 cubic foot of summoned material" mastery="1" element="all" range="30'" duration="Permanent" id="summon">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
			<Raise>Quantity (+1 cubic foot)</Raise>
			<Raise>Composition of material (1-4 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell can be cast in any of the four standard elements. It allows the caster to summon a modest quantity (one cubic foot) of the chosen element. The summoned matter appears (usually in a rough hall shape) in any open space within the spells range. This cannot place the summoned material inside another physical object or living creature. The summoned element will behave in a normal and mundane matter - Earth falls the ground, water soaks anything it lands on, air blows away, and fire winks out unless there is something present for it burn. In general it is impossible to use this spell effectively in combat, although clever shugenja may find a few modest combat uses, such as using Summon Fire to ignite a foe soaked in cooking oil. More commonly, the spells value is in simpler functions, such as summoning Water while in a desert, or summoning Fire to light a campfire without flint and tinder. Raises may be used with this spell summon a more specific type of the appropriate element, such as wood or iron with Earth, or tea with Water. The GM should choose how many Raises (generally anywhere from 1 to 4) this requires. However, these Raises cannot be used create rare/precious materials (such as gold) or spiritually powerful substances (such as jade or crystal).</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Armor Of Earth" area="Self" mastery="1" element="earth" range="Personal" duration="10 rounds" id="armor_of_earth">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 rounds)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell infuses the caster's body with the strength of Earth, weakening the force of any physical or magical attack which strikes him. For the duration of the spell, you gain Reduction in an amount equal to your Earth Ring + School Rank. However, this infusion of Earth slows your movements. Your Water is considered 1 Rank lower for purposes of movement while you are under the effects of this spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Courage Of The Seven Thunders" area="Targets up to caster's Shugenja School Rank" mastery="1" element="earth" range="30'" duration="10 minutes" id="courage_of_the_seven_thunders">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1)</Raise>
		</Raises>
    <Description>This spell infuses the targets (who may include the caster) with firm and unyielding courage, bolstered by the eternal power of the Earth. For the duration of the spell, all the targets gain +5k to resist any kind of Fear effect, whether magical or natural. However, this spell is associated with the memory of the legendary Seven Thunders, and those whose connection the Thunders is tenuous do not receive the same degree of blessing from the Earth kami. Samurai who are not of the original Seven Great Clans receive only + 3k to their rolls to resist Fear. Anyone who has at least a full Rank of Shadowlands Taint cannot benefit from this spell, although this will not actually reveal that they are tainted. This spell may be cast as a combined ritual by two or more shugenja who know the spell, in which case they may add their highest single Earth Rank to their combined total School Ranks to determine how many targets the spell can affect.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Earth's Stagnation" area="One target" mastery="1" element="earth" range="50'" duration="6 rounds" id="earths_stagnation">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 rounds)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1, to a maximum of 4 total targets)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell calls on the Earth in the target's body to weigh him down, impeding his movements. The target suffers a -2k penalty to all rolls using the Agility trait, and his Water Ring is considered 1 Rank lower for the purpose of how far he can move.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Earth's Touch" area="One target" mastery="1" element="earth" range="Touch" duration="1 hour" id="earths_touch">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1/2 hour)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 per 2 raises, maximum of 3 total targets)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>With this spell, the shugenja calls forth the Earth of the target (which may be himself), invoking the kami to strengthen his health and mental fortitude. For the duration of the spell, one of the target's Earth Traits (chosen by the caster) is increased by 1. This does not increase the Ring itself, but it can enhance the target's ability to withstand temptation, resist poisons, or dominate others.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Elemental Ward" area="One target" mastery="1" element="earth" range="Touch" duration="1 hour" id="elemental_ward">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>wards</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1/2 hour)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell uses the power of Earth to enhance resistance to hostile magic. The spirits of Earth armor the target's body and soul, rejecting other kami when they try to affect the target. When the shugenja casts this spell, he chooses one Element (which cannot be Void or Maho). Spells of that element suffer a TN penalty equal the caster's School Rank x 5 when they are cast on anyone under the protection of this spell. (Unfortunately, this includes "friendly" magic, such as healing.)</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Jade Strike" area="One target" mastery="1" element="earth" range="100'" duration="Instantaneous" id="jade_strike">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>jade</Tag>
			<Tag>thunder</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target, maximum of 5 total targets)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell summons forth the purest of Earth kami, those of jade, in the form of a blast of iridescent green energy. The jade power flies out and unerringly strikes the chosen target. It cannot be intercepted or deflected, although Magic Resistance or other forms of magical Defense can thwart it. If the target has at least one Rank of Taint, the Jade Strike will inflict damage with a DR of 3k3, burning and blackening the Tainted flesh. However, a target who does not have at least a full Rank of Taint will not suffer any damage from the spell. Casting Jade Strike on a non-Tainted target is generally regarded as a grave insult - except perhaps among the more paranoid ranks of the Kuni family, where it is seen as merely a sensible precaution.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Jurojin's Balm" area="One target" mastery="1" element="earth" range="Touch" duration="1 hour" id="jurojins_balm">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1/2 hour)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 per 2 Raises, maximum of 5 total targets)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell fills the target's body with the purity and vigor of Earth, driving out poisons and impurities. If the target suffers the effects of any poison or toxin within the duration of the spell, or is already under the effects of a poison when the spell targets him, he may re-roll any failed Stamina roll to resist the poison, with a bonus of +2k the second roll. (However, if the second roll is also failed, the poison has full effect.) An interesting side-effect of this spell is that it also cures drunkenness and other such effects, and it is impossible for the target to become intoxicated during the spells duration.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Minor Binding" area="One target" mastery="1" element="earth" range="60'" duration="2 hours" id="minor_binding">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 hour)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+20')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell was pioneered by the Kuni family but has come into use among other shugenja who Battle the forces of the Shadowlands, such as the Scorpion and the Phoenix. It is used to safely imprison minor Shadowlands creatures, typically for purposes of interrogation. Any Shadowlands creature with an Earth of 3 or less can be targeted with this spell. It cannot affect the Lost, Oni Lords or their spawn, or creatures with an Earth of 4 or higher, nor can it affect creatures who are not tainted. If the spell is cast successfully, it calls forth manacles of iron, formed from pure Earth spirits, which trap and bind the target creature, rendering it physically helpless for the duration of the spell. When the spell expires, the manacles instantly crumble away into dust.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Soul Of Stone" area="One target" mastery="1" element="earth" range="Touch" duration="1 hour" id="soul_of_stone">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1/2 hour)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell fills the targets soul with the firm and unyielding strength of stone. For the duration of the spell, the target's feelings are immovable, and any attempt to divert or distract him will be resisted with supernatural determination. He gains a +3k bonus to any rolls made to resist emotional manipulation or the distractions of desire, including Courtier (Manipulation) rolls, Temptation rolls, Compulsions, and any similar effects which the GM judges to be appropriate. However, this stony self-control also makes it difficult for the target to read and affect the emotions of others, and for the duration of the spell he suffers a -1k penalty to all Awareness Trait rolls and Awareness-related Skill Rolls made for the purpose of influencing others.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Tetsubo Of Earth" area="One created weapon" mastery="1" element="earth" range="Personal or 20'" duration="5 minutes" id="tetsubo_of_earth">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
			<Tag>jade</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+5 minutes)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5 feet)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You summon a tetsubo of pure earth, studded with all manner of stones. The weapon's default form is a tetsubo, but one Raise can change its form to any other heavy weapon of your choosing. The tetsubo has a DR of 2k2. When wielding this weapon, you may use your School Rank in place of your Heavy Weapons Skill if you wish. If you do have the Heavy Weapon skill, the tetsubo grants you a Free Raise for the Knockdown maneuver (this bonus does not apply if you grant the tetsubo to another person instead of wielding it yourself). The tetsubo disappears if it is lost from your hand. Instead of summoning the tetsubo for yourself, you may cause it to appear in the hands of an ally within 20 feet. He is treated as the caster for all purposes of the spell, but does not gain the Free Raise bonus.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Biting Steel" area="1 bladed weapon" mastery="1" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="1 minute" id="biting_steel">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Fire spirits can infuse metal with their own fury, turning a sharp edge into a supremely perfect one. This spell enhances the damage of steel bladed weapons, such as swords, knives, naginata, etc. Biting Steel cannot affect weapons which are not metal blades, which are Nemuranai, or which have already been enhanced by magical effects. The weapon's DR is increased by 1k1 for the duration of the spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Burning Kiss Of Steel" area="One melee weapon in caster's hand" mastery="1" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="5 minutes" id="burning_kiss_of_steel">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 minutes)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell embraces a weapon with fire, causing it to be larger and more effective. When the spell is cast, a tendril of fire extends from your hands to engulf your weapon. (If you drop or lose the weapon, the spell effect ends.) This weapon gains a + 1k1 bonus to melee attack rolls. The bonus is +2k2 when making attacks against mounted opponents or opponents of larger than human size.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Envious Flames" area="One target" mastery="1" element="fire" range="30'" duration="Instantaneous" id="envious_flames">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Fire's most basic power is destruction, and summoned Fire spirits can easily be unleashed on one's enemies. This spell invokes a single Fire kami, which lances toward the target, hitting unerringly so long as the target is within range. The spell deals 2k2 Wounds. The burns this spell inflicts are quite painful, and if the spell targets a shugenja who is casting a spell, his Willpower roll has a TN of 20 plus the damage dealt, instead of the normal 10 plus damage dealt.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Extinguish" area="100' radius" mastery="1" element="fire" range="Personal" duration="Instantaneous" id="extinguish">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+20 feet)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Fire spirits can be driven away by the proper invocation, a very useful ability in Rokugani towns and cities where the construction is all wood and paper. This spell dismisses the active Fire kami in the area. All non-magical fire in the area of effect is immediately snuffed out, and any damage dealt by fire (magical or not) reduces its DR by 1k1 until the start of the next Round.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Fires Of Purity" area="One target" mastery="1" element="fire" range="25'" duration="1 minute" id="fires_of_purity">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0 per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell, one of to the few directly protective prayers involving the Fire kami, asks the kami to protect one person, enveloping the target in a shroud of bright flames. Neither the caster nor anything he carries takes damage from the spell, but anyone who comes into contact with him or strikes him with a melee attack takes 2k2 Wounds. Anyone the target strikes in melee with an unarmed attack or a weapon he carried when the spell was cast also rakes an extra 2k2 Wounds. Anything the target puts down, however, cannot be picked back up without subjecting it to the damage from the spell. Ranged weapons such as arrows bypass this barrier of fire, dealing Wounds as normal.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Fury Of Osano-wo" area="One target" mastery="1" element="fire" range="300'" duration="Instantaneous" id="fury_of_osanowo">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>thunder</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0 per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell is actually a prayer to the Fortune of Fire and Thunder, inviting his wrath upon your enemy. It can only be cast outdoors, and summons a bolt of lightning from the sky, striking the target for 5k2 Wounds. Everyone within 10' of the target must make a Stamina roll versus a TN of 15 to avoid being deafened for 2 Rounds. If this spell is cast during a thunderstorm, the damage is increased to 6k2 for a moderate storm and 6k3 for a disastrous storm or hurricane.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Katana Of Fire" area="One created weapon" mastery="1" element="fire" range="Personal or 20' (see script description)" duration="5 minutes" id="katana_of_fire">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+5 minutes)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5 feet)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You summon a blade of pure fire, blazing like the soul of an honorable warrior. The weapon's default form is a katana, but one Raise can change its form to any other sword of your choosing. The katana has a DR of 2k2. When wielding this weapon, you may use your School Rank in place of your Kenjutsu Skill if you wish. If you do possess the Kenjutsu Skill, you add your Honor Rank to all damage rolls made with this weapon. The katana of fire disappears if it is lost from your hand. Instead of summoning the katana for yourself, you may cause it to appear in the hands of an ally within 20 feet. He is treated as the caster for all purposes of the spell, but does not gain the Honor boost to damage.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Never Alone" area="One target" mastery="1" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="5 Rounds (see script description)" id="never_alone">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Targets (+1)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell invokes Fire's element of knowledge and understanding, strengthening the spirit of one of your allies by opening his eyes to the courage of his ancestors. The target of the spell receives a bonus to all attack rolls, Skill rolls, and Trait Rolls equal to your Fire Ring. This effect lasts until either the spell expires, or until the target fails an attack roll or Skill Roll, or until the target suffers Wounds from any source, whichever comes first.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Fires That Cleanse" area="c Area: 30' radius" mastery="1" element="fire" range="Self" duration="Instantaneous" id="the_fires_that_cleanse">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area of Effect (+5 feet per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Destruction is one of the basic impulses of Fire, and this spell calls on that urge to spread destruction in the caster's surroundings. The spell whips the kami into a frenetic chaos, destroying everything around you. Everyone in the area of effect, including you, suffers damage with DR equal to your Fire Ring. This result is rolled once and applied to everyone within the area. However, you take only half damage (rounded up), since the kami makes some effort to avoid you.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Raging Forge" area="One weapon or armor" mastery="1" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="Instantaneous" id="the_raging_forge">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Fire is the element of creation as well as destruction, and a skilled shugenja can use this to great effect. This spell invokes the powers of the forge, mighty and merciless, to remake a material item, such as a weapon or suit of armor, into its perfect form. The target item loses all blemishes, including cracks or nicks. This spell cannot repair an item which has actually been broken or destroyed, however, and it can only affect items that are of ordinary quality.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Boundless Sight" area="Self" mastery="1" element="void" range="50 miles" duration="4 rounds" id="boundless_sight">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5 miles)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The most essential lesson of the ishiken is that all is linked through the Void, and through the Void all can be perceived. By focusing your energy, you can look through the veil and see another location as if you were standing there. This location must be familiar to you, and you must have been there at least once before. For the duration of the spell, you can see and hear all that transpires in the other location, but you may not be detected and you may not interact with things or individuals there in any way. During this spell, your body is in a trance-like state that leaves you highly vulnerable to attack (your Armor TN is reduced to 5).</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Drawing The Void" area="Self" mastery="1" element="void" range="Personal" duration="Instantaneous" id="drawing_the_void">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Special (+1 Void Point gained per three Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The ability to reach into the Void itself and gain strength from it is a vital lesson in the training of all ishiken. Upon completion of this spell, you gain a number of additional Void Points equal to your School Rank plus one. If these Void Points take you above the number you may normally possess, then you lose one of the extra Void Points every Round that you do not spend one.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Flow Through The Void" area="Up to one cubic foot of pure elemental matter" mastery="1" element="void" range="Touch" duration="Permanent" id="flow_through_the_void">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+1 cubic foot)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>In the Void, all things are equal, all one and none. By tapping into this connection, you may transform a small amount of pure elemental matter(water, fire, air, or Earth in the form of dirt or soil) into anyone other element.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="See Through Lies" area="Target individual" mastery="1" element="void" range="25'" duration="Instantaneous" id="see_through_lies">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (one additional Advantage/Disadvantage per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The patterns that comprise all things in the Void exist in individuals as well, and with training, ishiken can recognize them. You learn the highest point Advantage or highest point Disadvantage (your choice) possessed by the target of this spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Sense Void" area="25' radius around the caster" mastery="1" element="void" range="Personal" duration="Concentration" id="sense_void">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+5' radius)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Life is evident in the Void like the stars in the night sky. This spell causes you to enter a trance during which you become aware of the existence and location of all living creatures within the radius of the spell. Although you are aware of their location, you cannot see them or any details. You would know if there were the three humans waiting outside the castle wall, for instance, but you would not recognize them other than to know that they were present. This also gives you information regarding non-sentient, natural living creatures. Spirits and Shadowlands creatures are recognizable as a gap in your awareness, although this spell cannot recognize Tainted humans as anything other than humans.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Void's Caress" area="One target individual" mastery="1" element="void" range="Touch" duration="1 minute" id="the_voids_caress">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Although beginning students of ishiken-do cannot affect the pattern of the Void, they can make very short-term alterations to it. You may negate any one Mental or Spiritual Disadvantage of the target of this spell posseses, up to a maximum of 5 points in value. The Shadowlands Taint may not be removed via this spell, although the mental disorders that can be caused by it can be temporarily alleviated.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Touch The Emptiness" area="One target individual" mastery="1" element="void" range="30'" duration="Instantaneous" id="touch_the_emptiness">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The sensation of experiencing the Void firsthand can be extremely disturbing for those unaccustomed to it. The target of this spell suffers 1k1 damage and is dazed.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Witness The Untold" area="One target individual" mastery="1" element="void" range="15'" duration="3 rounds" id="witness_the_untold">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>divination</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>It is possible to gain fleeting glimpses of things that have not yet happened by peering through the Void. If you are delaying your action, you may interrupt the target of the spell after he has declared his action but before he has taken his action when his turn comes up. This may be done during each Round for the duration of the spell. (Normally someone delaying their Action cannot interrupt the Action of another participant.)</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Bo Of Water" area="One created weapon" mastery="1" element="water" range="Personal or 20' (see spell description)" duration="5 minutes" id="bo_of_water">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+5 minutes)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5 feet)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You summon a staff of pure water, as rigid as the real thing despite its fluid nature. The weapon's default form is a Bo, but one Raise can change its form to any other staff of your choosing. The weapon has DR 1k2. If you do not possess the Staves Skill, you may instead use your School Rank in its place. If you do possess the Staves Skill, using this weapon grants you one Free Raise that can only he used on the Knockdown Maneuver. This weapon disappears if it is lost from your hand. Instead of summoning the Bo for yourself, you may cause it to appear in the hands of an ally within 20 feet. He is treated as the caster for all purposes of the spell, but he does not gain the Free Raise bonus.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Clarity Of Purpose" area="10' radius around caster" mastery="1" element="water" range="Personal" duration="2 rounds" id="clarity_of_purpose">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>One of the many strengths of Water is in its speed. All allies within the area of effect of this spell gain a bonus of +5 to their Initiative Scores for the duration of the spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Ebbing Strength" area="One target creature" mastery="1" element="water" range="20'" duration="3 rounds" id="ebbing_strength">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Energy flows through the universe just as water flows through the mortal shell. You may send your energy to another, weakening yourself and strengthening them in the process. You may reduce anyone of your Physical Traits by an amount up to your School Rank. The target of this spell increases the same Physical Trait by the same amount. If your Trait is reduced to 0 as a result of this spell, you immediately fall unconscious and the spells duration is reduced to 1 round. No trait may be enhanced above double its normal rank by this spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Path To Inner Peace" area="One target individual" mastery="1" element="water" range="Touch" duration="Instantaneous" id="path_to_inner_peace">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The water kami can influence the flow of water through the body, dramatically hastening the natural healing process. You can use this spell to heal Wounds that another individual has suffered. This spell restores a number of Wounds to the target equal to the amount by which the Spell Casting Roll exceeded the spells TN to cast.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Reflections Of Pan Ku" area="One object" mastery="1" element="water" range="Touch" duration="Instantaneous" id="reflections_of_pan_ku">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>divination</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Divining the abilities of an object is among the simplest lessons a student of water learns in the temple. If this spell is successfully cast on an object, you automatically learn all powers and abilities that object possesses. This is most frequently used to identify any supernatural qualities an item possesses, such as a Nemuranai or a cursed weapon, but it can also identify the spell contained within a shugenja's prayer scroll. This spell will not allow a shugenja to read a scroll if it is written in a cipher he does not understand, but he can at least identify the spell in question. This spell will also grant the caster knowledge of the item's origin in very broad strokes, such as where it was forged, the Clan of the individual who has carried it the longest, or something similar at the GM's discretion.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Reversal Of Fortunes" area="One target individual" mastery="1" element="water" range="10'" duration="3 rounds" id="reversal_of_fortunes">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Versatility is the domain of water, and those who carry its blessing reap the rewards. For the duration of this spell, the target may immediately re-roll anyone roll per round. This must be done immediately after the first roll is completed, and the target may keep either result.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Speed Of The Waterfall" area="One target individual or creature" mastery="1" element="water" range="Touch" duration="1 hour" id="speed_of_the_waterfall">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>travel</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+10 minutes)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (may increase to 10' for two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Those filled with the essence of water find their movement far faster than ever before. The target of this spell may move a total distance per round equal to their Water x 20' plus an amount equal to twice your Water Ring, This spell does not grant the target additional movement, it simply increases the maximum possible amount they can move during a Round for the duration of the spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Spirit Of The Water" area="One target individual" mastery="1" element="water" range="20'" duration="Instantaneous" id="spirit_of_the_water">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (Increase additional action to Complex for 5 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The spirit of Water is both fluid and rapid. The target gains one additional Simple Action during the Reactions Stage of the Round in which this spell is completed. This Action cannot be used to make an attack.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Sympathetic Energies" area="One target individual" mastery="1" element="water" range="25'" duration="Instantaneous" id="sympathetic_energies">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (see spell description)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Energy flows between all living things as water flows through the Earth, You may transfer any one existing spell effect from you to the willing target of this spell. With three Raises, you may transfer one spell effect from one willing target to another willing target. You cannot transfer spells between unwilling targets.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Rushing Wave" area="One target individual" mastery="1" element="water" range="10'" duration="1 round" id="the_rushing_wave">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>travel</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You can temporarily increase the speed of your target. This spell allows the target to make a Free Move Action of up to his Water Ring x 10' (instead of the normal x 5'). Without Raises for Duration, this benefit must be used on the target's next Turn or it is lost.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Benten's Touch" area="Target individual (may be the caster)" mastery="2" element="air" range="Personal / Touch" duration="1 hour" id="bentens_touch">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (may increase range to 5' with a single Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>By calling upon the air kami to whisper suggestions to others, you may cause them perceive the target of this spell more positively than they otherwise might. The target of this spell gains a bonus of + 1k1, plus your Air Ring, the total of all Social Skill rolls made for the duration of the spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Call Upon the Wind" area="Target individual (may be the caster)" mastery="2" element="air" range="Personal or 20'" duration="1 minute" id="call_upon_the_wind">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>travel</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The winds can lift and buoy, carrying even the heaviest burden into the skies for short periods. The target of this spell gains a limited form of flight, allowing him to move through the air unimpeded. The target of the spell may make Free Move Actions, but not Simple Move Actions, and may never move more than 10' per round. Heavy winds can interfere with this movement or prevent it altogether. At the end of the spells duration, the target drifts harmlessly the ground, no matter how high he might be.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Hidden Visage" area="Self" mastery="2" element="air" range="Personal" duration="5 minutes" id="hidden_visage">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area of Effect (another person in line of sight can be targeted by this spell by making three Raises)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+5 minutes)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Air kami are mischievous and capricious, and enjoy anything they perceive as a joke. You may call upon them create a subtle illusion, altering your facial features just enough that you appear to be a different person. This spell does not allow you to impersonate specific individuals, or even people radically different from you, you appear as a person of the same age, build, race, and gender. The differences are subtle, enough so that you could be mistaken for your own brother or cousin.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Mist of Illusion" area="10' radius" mastery="2" element="air" range="20'" duration="1 minute" id="mist_of_illusion">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>With greater fluency with the kami comes the ability to craft increasingly convincing images from the stuff of the wind itself. You may create illusions of any object, individual, or image that you can imagine. These images are stationary, and they must fit within the spells area of effect, but they can be as simple or complex as desired. These illusions are visual only, with no auditory component, odors, etc.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Secrets on the Wind" area="20' radius" mastery="2" element="air" range="10 miles" duration="Concentration" id="secrets_on_the_wind">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+5' radius)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5 miles)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The kami can carry whispers across an Empire, if properly entreated to do so. This spell requires you to perform a preparation ritual in order to cast it effectively. The ritual requires ten minutes of uninterrupted meditation in the area designated as the spells area of effect. Any time within the 48 hours immediately following this ritual, you may cast this spell, and overhear anything being said in the prepared area. If your concentration is disrupted, the effect ends and may not be renewed without an additional preparation ritual. Only one area may be prepared via this ritual at one time.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Kami's Whisper" area="10' radius" mastery="2" element="air" range="50'" duration="1 round" id="the_kamis_whisper">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+5' radius)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The kami of the wind can carry whispers for great distances, and can even create them if properly entreated. You can petition the kami create a false sound, either a voice or a natural sound such as an animal's growl or running water, for example. The sound can be no louder than a normal speaking voice, and cannot impersonate a specific person's voice. If used create the sound of a voice, the spell is limited to twenty words.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Whispering Wind" area="Target individual" mastery="2" element="air" range="20'" duration="Instantaneous" id="whispering_wind">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>divination</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The air kami see very little difference between speech and thought, and can perceive both with relative ease. By comparing the two, the kami can determine if what has been spoken is true, or a lie. Unfortunately, they have notoriously short attention spans, and thus can only assess extremely recent conversations. By invoking this spell, you may determine if the last thing said by the target was true or false. The kami have no concept of personal opinion, however, and if the target truly believes what he said was true, the kami will believe it as well.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Wolf's Proposal" area="Self" mastery="2" element="air" range="Personal" duration="10 minutes" id="wolfs_proposal">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (may target another with 2 Raises)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+5 minutes)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+1 Honor Rank per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell, crafted to initiate relations between groups, is easily twisted to nefarious purposes. It calls the kami create a subtle aura of suggestion around the caster, one that does not disguise the caster but rather causes others perceive him as slightly more benevolent than perhaps he truly is. For the duration of this spell, your Honor Rank is considered three ranks higher for the purposes of any Lore:Bushido rolls made to determine your Honor Rank.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Be The Mountain" area="One target creature" mastery="2" element="earth" range="30'" duration="4 rounds" id="be_the_mountain">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 Round)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A variant of the spell Armor of Earth, designed to protect allies, this prayer causes the Earth kami to envelop the target with their embrace, covering his skin with a stony barrier that repels physical blows. The target gains Reduction of a value equal to 5x the caster's School Rank to a maximum of 20, but cannot take Simple Move Actions for the duration of the spell (Free Move Actions are still allowed). Only a willing ally can be targeted with this spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Earth Becomes Sky" area="One target creature" mastery="2" element="earth" range="100'" duration="Instantaneous" id="earth_becomes_sky">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>jade</Tag>
			<Tag>thunder</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (make boulders Jade with 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell summons up several huge boulders from the earth, and hurls them through the air to unerringly strike one (or more) target creatures. The target struck by these boulders suffers damage with a DR equal the caster's Earth rank. If the caster strikes multiple targets, the DR is reduced by 1k1 for each additional target, to a minimum of 1k1 damage per target. These boulders are made of normal, mundane stone, and thus cannot normally bypass Reduction or Invulnerability, but a powerful caster can infuse the boulders with the power of Jade.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Embrace Of Kenro-ji-jin" area="One target creature" mastery="2" element="earth" range="Personal or Touch" duration="1 hour" id="embrace_of_kenrojijin">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>travel</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1/2 hour)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell allows the target (who can be the caster or one other person) to literally dive into the ground, which becomes as clear and easy to traverse as water for him. He can see for a distance of 100 yards through the Earth, and can move through it in any direction as easily as though he were in normal air. The target can see through the edge of the Earth into the normal world, but he cannot attack, cast spells, speak, hear, or otherwise interact with those outside the Earth unless he emerges from the ground (at which point the spell immediately ends). If the spell ends while the target is still underground, the Earth spirits are offended by the Target's continued presence, and immediately expel him into the nearest open air, wherever that might be.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Force Of Will" area="One target" mastery="2" element="earth" range="50'" duration="2 rounds" id="force_of_will">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round, maximum 4 Rounds duration)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell infuses the target with an intense resistance to pain and death, as the Earth kami bolster his will to live to superhuman levels. He is able to shrug off the pain and shock of his wounds, even continuing in the face of lethal injuries for a short time. For the duration of this spell, the target is immune to all Wound Rank penalties and effects - including the effect of being dead if the Out rank is completely filled. When the spell expires, however, the full effects of any Wounds apply immediately - thus, this spell typically affords either a brief chance to be healed before it is too late, or the chance to wage a final battle in the face of certain death.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Grasp Of Earth" area="One target" mastery="2" element="earth" range="50'" duration="5 rounds" id="grasp_of_earth">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 Round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 Target per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell causes the Earth kami to reach up and seize hold of the target, often taking the form of a massive hand or claw which grips the unfortunate creature in stony digits. The target is rendered near-immobile, able to move only 3' per round as a Simple Move Action, and unable to move at all with a Free Move Action. The target may break free by spending a Complex Action and rolling Raw Strength at a TN equal to 5x the caster's Earth.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Hands Of Clay" area="Self" mastery="2" element="earth" range="Personal" duration="10 minutes" id="hands_of_clay">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>travel</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+5 minutes)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell infuses Earth spirits into the hands and feet of the caster, allowing them to merge with the Earth found in wood, earth, and stone. This allows the caster to walk and climb along sheer surfaces, including walls and cliffs, at half his normal movement speed (rounded up). He can even hang from ceilings and move along them, although in that case he can only move 3' with a Simple Action. When the spell ends, the effect concludes without warning, possibly leading to a painful fall.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Mountain's Feet" area="One target" mastery="2" element="earth" range="Personal or 20'" duration="1 hour" id="the_mountains_feet">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1/2 hour)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell fortifies the target by rooting his feet the stone and soil beneath, allowing him to shrug off anything that might separate him from the much of Earth. The target gains +3k0 to resist all Knockdown maneuvers, and any spell which seeks to knock down the target, lift him into the air, or otherwise break his connection the Earth must win a Contested roll of the spells Element against the caster's Earth.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Wholeness Of The World" area="One target creature" mastery="2" element="earth" range="Personal or 20'" duration="10 minutes" id="wholeness_of_the_world">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell infuses the target with the strength of Earth to such a degree that his Rings and Traits become wholly resistant to any effort to change them. Any physical or magical effect which would raise or lower his Traits or Rings is completely ineffective for the duration of those spell, as the Earth kami normally rebuff any such efforts to alter the target's Elemental balance.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Disrupt The Aura" area="Target person or creature" mastery="2" element="fire" range="50'" duration="24 hours" id="disrupt_the_aura">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+12 hours per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Anyone whose elements are out of balance will feel the effects, and this spell creates this condition deliberately by aggravating the Fire present in the target's body. While the spell is in effect, the target cannot be healed by magical means. Magical spells, items, or Techniques that attempt to restore Wounds to the target automatically fail. (Mundane wound treatment with the Medicine skill will still be effective.) The target may realize something is physically wrong with him but cannot find out what is happening without the help of a shugenja - casting Sense (Fire will show the presence of many excited Fire spirits within the target.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Enticing Dance Of The Flame" area="20' radius" mastery="2" element="fire" range="50'" duration="2 rounds" id="enticing_dance_of_the_flame">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A more potent version of The Fires That Cleanse, this spell keeps the Fire kami under tighter control and persuades them to remain present for longer. If the spell is cast successfully, Fire kami erupt into a violent, ferocious dance at a location of your choice, igniting that area into flames. Every target in the area takes 3k2 Wounds on the Round the spell takes effect. At the beginning of each subsequent Round, if the spell is still active, every target still in the affected area takes an additional 2k1 Wounds.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Hurried Steps" area="Self" mastery="2" element="fire" range="Personal" duration="2 rounds (see script description)" id="hurried_steps">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Fire is the element of thought, and thought is swift indeed. You draw upon the speed of the Fire kami to aid you in the next spell you cast. The casting time of the next Fire spell you cast is reduced by 4 Rounds. If the next spell is Mastery Level 3 or lower, it casts instantaneously as a Simple Action. If you do not begin casting the new spell within the next 2 Rounds, however, the benefit of Hurried Steps elapses.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Mental Quickness" area="One item" mastery="2" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="10 minutes" id="mental_quickness">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Fire kami can be imbued into physical objects, allowing them to remain present for longer periods of time. Shugenja have devised many ways to use this technique to aid themselves and others. This spell, one of the most basic of this kind, imbues a material item with the cleverness and wit of fire. Anyone who carries that item has their Intelligence Trait increased by 3 for the duration of the spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Relentless Heat" area="One armor" mastery="2" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="10 Rounds" id="relentless_heat">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 Rounds)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell is designed to protect bushi by infusing a Fire kami into their armor. The spell targets one suit of armor, which glows with the strength of the merciless desert sun. Any opponent who attempts to strike the person wearing the armor, whether or not the attack hits, is immediately considered to be Fatigued until the beginning of their next Tum. The penalties apply to the attack roll that triggered the spell, and any attackers in the Full Attack Posture immediately assume the Attack Posture instead. This spell has no effect on ranged attacks or spells that target the wearer of the armor.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Tail Of The Fire Dragon" area="Self" mastery="2" element="fire" range="Personal" duration="4 rounds" id="tail_of_the_fire_dragon">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell invokes several Fire kami to form a whip-like tendril that extends from the caster's hand. The tendril of flame will not burn you, since the kami are grateful for the opportunity to burn others at your command. You may use this tendril to strike enemies as far as 30' away, extending it out and back with blinding speed. Your attack roll with the tendril is equal to your Agility + (twice your School Rank), keeping your Agility. The tendril has a DR equal to your Fire Ring.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Fires From Within" area="One target" mastery="2" element="fire" range="100'" duration="Instantaneous" id="the_fires_from_within">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Target (+1 target per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Probably the most widely known and recognized offensive spell in the element of Fire. This prayer has been in use by Rokugani shugenja since the very earliest days of the Empire. You summon Fire kami to form an orb of flame that hovers in your palm for a moment before streaking toward the target. The sphere gains momentum and size until it hits its target, making it quite spectacular visually. The spell has a DR equal to your Fire Ring.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Ward Of Purity" area="15' radius from the object touched" mastery="2" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="1 day" id="ward_of_purity">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>ward</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Although Earth is the traditional method of opposing evil forces like the Shadowlands Taint, the spirits of Fire can also be invoked to purge and destroy such spiritual abominations. This spell binds a Fire kami into a specific location which it protects against the forces of evil. Casting the spell requires inscribing elaborate kanji on a flat surface in chalk or ink, and takes one minute of concentrated effort, after which the Spell Casting Roll must be made. Once the Ward of Purity is activated and the power of the kami is fully engaged, however, the kami within the inscription protects the area against the influence of the Shadowlands or the Lying Darkness. Persons or creatures with at least 1 Shadowlands Taint Rank, or who are under the control of the Lying Darkness, must make a successful Contested Willpower Roll against you in order to enter the Ward's area of effect; you gain a +5 bonus to this roll. In addition, those creatures who successfully enter the area suffer extreme pain, as the power of the ward burns their very essence. Their bodies ignite and they suffer Wounds equal to the total of your Fire Ring + insight Rank each Round they remain within the area of effect. Spells and missiles are unaffected by Ward of Purity. The object upon which the ward is inscribed must remain immobile and the inscription must remain dearly visible at all times, or else the Ward is dispelled. If overlapping Wards of Purity are present, their effects do not stack.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Altering The Course" area="Self" mastery="2" element="void" range="Personal" duration="1 minute" id="altering_the_course">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Ishiken have a much greater capacity to draw upon the Void than others, and may do it consciously rather than unconsciously. You may spend multiple Void Points on any roll made within the duration of this spell. It still must be a roll on which the expenditure of Void Points is allowable (no damage rolls may be augmented via this spell, for example.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Drink Of Your Essence" area="One target individual" mastery="2" element="void" range="30'" duration="Instantaneous" id="drink_of_your_essence">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>As an ishiken grows more powerful, he can gain more information from examining an individual's pattern within the Void. You learn a great deal of information about the target of this spell, including his individual Rings (but not Traits), his current Wound penalties, and a one word summation of his present mood ("hostile, "sorrowful," "confused," etc.).</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="False Whispers" area="One target individual" mastery="2" element="void" range="30'" duration="1 minute" id="false_whispers">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Mingling the Void of two beings, even for just a moment, can lead to one of the two being manipulated if he is not prepared for it. The target of this spell will repeat the next sentence you say, verbatim, without any foreknowledge of what he is doing. They speak the words in their own normal voice, regardless of how you speak it. This effect will not allow others to cast spells, even if you have them recite a portion of a spell. This spell only allows the effect once, the first time you speak a single sentence during the duration of the spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Reach Through The Void" area="Target object, up to five pounds in weight" mastery="2" element="void" range="50'" duration="Instantaneous" id="reach_through_the_void">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+1 pound per two Raises)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>All things, both living and un-living, exist within the Void, and can be touched through it. You can manipulate items through the Void, moving them without touching them. These items are small, usually only up to only five pounds, although a powerful shugenja can raise enough to move somewhat heavier items.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Severed From The Stream" area="One target individual" mastery="2" element="void" range="25'" duration="5 rounds" id="severed_from_the_stream">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Talented ishiken can rob others of their ability to tap into the Void, if only temporarily. If this spell is successful, the target must succeed at a Contested Void Roll against you before they are able to spend any Void Points. This roll does not count as an action for the target, and they must succeed at only one Contested Roll per turn, even if they are spending multiple Void Points per turn as a result of a Technique or other ability.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Empty Voice" area="Self" mastery="2" element="void" range="Personal" duration="5 minutes" id="the_empty_voice">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Drawing on the essence of everything allows an ishiken to invoke the kami with far greater ease than normal. For the duration of this spell, you may cast spells of other elements without speaking your prayers aloud. This applies only to spells of equal or lower Mastery Level (any spell of Mastery Level l or 2).</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Cloak Of The Miya" area="Self" mastery="2" element="water" range="Personal" duration="5 rounds" id="cloak_of_the_miya">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You wrap yourself in the protective embrace of the wave. Your Armor TN is increased by an amount equal to your Water Ring plus your School Rank for the duration of this spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Inari's Blessing" area="Created sustenance" mastery="2" element="water" range="Personal" duration="Instantaneous" id="inaris_blessing">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Special (Enough food for one additional person per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Inari is the Fortune of Rice, and one of the most beloved of all divine entities throughout the Empire. This spell invokes Inari's blessing, and creates nourishing food and drink at your command. This spell generates enough food and drink to sustain a number of individuals equal to your School Rank + 1 for one day. Without Raises, this food is bland but sustaining, such as unflavored rice and water, but with Raises, you can increase the quality of the food to seafood or tea at the GM's discretion. The TN to cast this spell is doubled when in the Shadow lands.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Reflective Pool" area="Body of water / target location" mastery="2" element="water" range="10 miles" duration="5 minutes" id="reflective_pool">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>divination</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10 miles)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The inscrutable knowledge of Water is a great boon to those who know the means by which it can be invoked. You may stare into a body of water, which may be as small as a puddle, and through it view a familiar location as if you were present, although you can only see what is taking place, not hear it. In order for a location to be familiar to you, you must either have spent a great deal of time there (your home, the dojo, a preferred temple, etc.), or have spent a minimum of ten minutes in meditation at the location. Any body of water can be used for this spell, but since the visions imparted are visual images depicted will be clearer with larger bodies.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Rejuvenating Vapors" area="One target individual" mastery="2" element="water" range="Touch" duration="Instantaneous" id="rejuvenating_vapors">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Targets (one additional person per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Water washes away all that is impure, refreshing and reinvigorating all it touches. The target of this spell is instantly refreshed as if he had just arisen from a full night's sleep. This does not restore spent Void Points, but can eliminate fatigue and exhaustion. When used on a shugenja, this spell does restore the spell slots associated with the Void Ring (which can be used for any elements), but not the spell slots associated with other Rings. Abilities that characters may use a limited number of times per day are not refreshed by this spell. No Individual can benefit from Rejuvenating Vapors more than once within a 24-hour period.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Stand Against The Waves" area="One target individual" mastery="2" element="water" range="10'" duration="Instantaneous" id="stand_against_the_waves">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (10' per 3 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A samurai who possesses the speed and strength of the mighty river is a dangerous foe indeed. The target of this spell gains a Simple Action during the Reaction Stage of the current Combat Round. This action may only be used to make an attack. If the target is incapable of making an attack as a Simple Action, this spell grants him a Complex Action instead. This spell cannot award a shugenja the ability to cast a second spell in the same Round.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Ties That Bind" area="Self" mastery="2" element="water" range="10 miles" duration="Instantaneous" id="the_ties_that_bind">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>divination</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+2 miles)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Even the lightest touch forges a connection, and through the spirits of water that connection may be explored. This spell allows you to seek out the spirits of Water within a single, specific object. You must be familiar with the object in question, either having spent a great deal of time around it or handled it personally. If the object is within the range of this spell, you will know the direction and relative distance it is from your current position.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Wave-borne Speed" area="Self" mastery="2" element="water" range="Personal" duration="2 Rounds" id="waveborne_speed">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>travel</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The speed of the river can be imparted by knowledgeable shugenja. Your Water Ring is increased by 2 for the purposes of determining how far you may move as part of any Move Actions made during the present Round or the following Round.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Essence Of Air" area="Self" mastery="3" element="air" range="Personal" duration="5 rounds" id="essence_of_air">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Air can be merged with the essence of a mortal, and doing so can impart tremendous abilities, albeit at great risk the caster. You mix with the wind itself and become insubstantial. You may not interact with any physical objects while insubstantial, although you remain on the ground, and you may pass through solid objects at a rate of one foot per round. Your Water Ring is considered halved (rounded down) while you remain insubstantial, and you may not cast any other spells until you return to solidity.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Mask Of Wind" area="Self" mastery="3" element="air" range="Personal" duration="1 hour" id="mask_of_wind">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (may target another with two Raises)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+10 minutes)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A skilled shugenja can petition the kami to create incredibly elaborate illusions to obscure ones identity and appearance. You may use this spell to adopt the appearance of any humanoid creature of approximately the same size, up to one foot taller or shorter than you. You could use this spell to assume the guise of a kenku, for example, because they are roughly the same size as humans. A goblin or an ogre would be impossible, however, because they are to short and to large, respectively.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Striking The Storm" area="Self" mastery="3" element="air" range="Personal" duration="3 rounds" id="striking_the_storm">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The most powerful winds can turn aside not only arrows, but steel as well. You may summon a buffet of winds that surrounds you in an unrelenting cocoon of swirling air. Your Armor TN is increased by +20 against both melee and ranged attacks. The force of the winds surrounding you prevents you from hearing others if they speak to you, however.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Summon Fog" area="50' radius" mastery="3" element="air" range="100'" duration="1 minute" id="summon_fog">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+5' radius)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The kami can be petitioned to coalesce in an area as they do in the coast, creating a thick, obscuring fog. Within the area affected by your spell, the visibility is decreased to a meager five feet. Fabrics and other absorbent materials within the spells area of effect will become damp or even wet if they remain within it long enough. Small sources of open flame such as candles, might be extinguished as well, at the GM's discretion. The moistness of fog is extremely damaging to rice paper.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Summoning The Gale" area="Target individual (may be the caster)" mastery="3" element="air" range="50'" duration="Concentration" id="summoning_the_gale">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Swirling winds can be commanded to circle a designated target, preventing ranged attacks being made in either direction. This spell affects an area thirty feet around the target in all directions. Everyone within the affected area gains a + 15 bonus to their Armor TN against ranged attacks. However, everyone within the area also suffers a penalty of -3k3 to all ranged attack rolls.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Eye Shall Not See" area="Self or target individual" mastery="3" element="air" range="Personal or Touch" duration="Concentration" id="the_eye_shall_not_see">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You call upon the kami to create an area of distraction surrounding you, drawing all attention away from you and your actions. The kami whisper in the ears of those within 20' of you (or of the target if you cast the spell on someone else), causing them to be conveniently distracted from your presence. You are not invisible, but those within 20' of you will not see you as long as you do not make any loud noises or otherwise draw attention to yourself. Those outside that distance are not distracted, however, and will see you perfectly well regardless of your action or inaction.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Your Heart's Enemy" area="One target individual" mastery="3" element="air" range="25'" duration="5 rounds" id="your_hearts_enemy">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The kami can see into the hearts of mortals, and can use that information at a shugenja's request. You manifest the Kami as an illusion of the thing your target fears most in the world. It may be an individual (the man who killed his father), or an item (a cursed blade that brought ruin this family), or even a vista of some sort (an image of an enemy slaying his family). This effectively generates Fear 4 that the target must overcome (see the Book of Earth for rules regarding Fear). Only the target can see the specifics of the illusion, others see only a hazy outline that appears to be a small fog cloud.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Bonds Of Ningen-do" area="One target spirit creature" mastery="3" element="earth" range="500'" duration="30 days" id="bonds_of_ningendo">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>wards</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 day)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell is a more powerful and specialized form of Minor Binding. It is a ritual designed to bind or dispel troublesome creatures from the various spirit realms. Any creature from the realms of Sakkaku, Chikushudo, Gaki-Do, Toshigoku, or Yume-Dan be affected by this spell. Casting it requires 10 minutes, although if additional shugenja who know the spell assist in the ritual, the time is reduced by 1 minute per additional shugenja, to a minimum of 1 minute. If the targeted creature is within range of the caster(s) when the spell is successfully completed, the creature can be either bound or dispelled. If it is bound, it must obey the caster's commands for the duration of the spell, although suicidal commands will break the spell - this is how the Kuni have forced mujina spirits to labor for them in their iron mines. (It should be noted that this use of the spell is considered controversial and even blasphemous by many in Rokugan.) If the creature is dispelled, it immediately leaves Ningen-Do its native spirit realm, and cannot return until the spells duration ends. Either way, the spirit creature will regard the caster as an enemy thereafter, and is likely to seek vengeance if it can.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Earth Kami's Blessing" area="Caster or one target creature" mastery="3" element="earth" range="Personal or 20'" duration="10 minutes" id="earth_kamis_blessing">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell infuses the target (which may be the caster or one of his allies) with the strength and resilience of the Earth, making him rougher and more firm-minded. For the duration of the spell, the target gains +2 Wounds per Wound Rank, and gains + 1k1 on all rolls involving the Earth Ring and its associated Traits. When the spell expires, any Wounds the target has suffered still remain, and this may drive him into a lower Wound Rank or even kill him.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Earth's Protection" area="10' radius from caster" mastery="3" element="earth" range="Personal" duration="Concentration" id="earths_protection">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
			<Tag>wards</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+5' radius per 2 Raises, to maximum of 30' radius)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (damage reduced by an additional +1k1 for 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell calls on the spirits of Earth to protect the area around the caster from the effects of the other three Elements (Air, Fire, and Water) for a short time. While the caster concentrates on maintaining the favour of the Earth spirits, the effects of spells which call on those other three elements are mitigated. Any hostile Air, Fire, or Water spell cast within the area of Earth's Protection, or extending its effects into that area, will suffer a + 10 TN penalty to the Spell Casting roll. In addition, any damage which those spells inflict on creatures within Earth's Protection will be reduced by 1k1 (to a minimum of 1k1).</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Purge The Taint" area="50' radius around caster" mastery="3" element="earth" range="Personal" duration="Permanent" id="purge_the_taint">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>jade</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+10' radius)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell was originally created by the Kuni family and is still primarily practised by them, although knowledge of its prayers has spread to other Clans. It is an elaborate ritual spell, requiring an hour to cast, that calls on the powers of Earth to purge the land of the Shadowlands Taint, driving out all the evil kansen in the area. The spell will remove all the Taint from the land, plant life, and inanimate objects within the area of effect. It will not remove Taint from living creatures, nor will it affect powerful Tainted artifacts or objects made of obsidian. The removal of the Taint, however, is not without price. The elemental kami in the area of effect are also weakened and purged by the spell, especially the Earth spirits whose efforts are called upon to power it. In the aftermath of casting this spell, the local spirits will be scattered and weakened, inflicting a + 15 TN penalty on all Spell Casting rolls within the area. This negative effect will sometimes fade with time, especially if it was cast in a single location surrounded by normal lands. But if the spell is cast over a wide area, such as the Kuni Wastes, the elemental kami will usually permanently leave the area, reducing it to a gray, lifeless wasteland.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Sharing The Strength Of Many" area="One to six target persons within range" mastery="3" element="earth" range="30'" duration="5 rounds" id="sharing_the_strength_of_many">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell infuses its targets, up to six people (who can include the caster), with the power of Earth, allowing them each call upon the Earth of their comrades to bolster their efforts. For the duration of the spell, the lowest Earth Ring Rank among all the targets is added the total of all Ring, Trait, and Skill rolls (but not Spell Casting rolls) they make.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Strength Of The Crow" area="One target" mastery="3" element="earth" range="Touch" duration="Hours equal to caster's Shugenja School Rank" id="strength_of_the_crow">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>jade</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 hour)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell infuses the target (who can be the caster) with a powerful resistance the Shadowlands Taint, repelling the dark kansen of the Taint with the pure power of Earth. For the duration of the spell, the target(s) gain a +5K5 bonus to all rolls made to resist gaining the Shadow lands Taint, and any Maho spells suffer a + 10 TN penalty to affect them. This bonus does not apply to any rolls made to resist an increase in Taint the target already possesses - it only applies to new Taint gained from outside sources. Likewise it cannot protect the target from gaining Taint by casting Maho.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Wolf's Mercy" area="One target creature" mastery="3" element="earth" range="50'" duration="10 rounds" id="the_wolfs_mercy">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell has existed in Rokugan for centuries, but is best known for its extensive use by Toturi Sezaru, "the Wolf," who employed it during his hunts for Bloodspeakers. It calls on the power of the Earth to afflict the target, weighing down his body and impeding his muscles, leaving him weak and vulnerable. The target's Earth Ring is lowered by 1 Rank, and his Wound Ranks are reduced correspondingly for the duration of the spell. (This can potentially kill him immediately if he has already suffered Wounds.) In addition, his Strength Rank is also lowered by 1 for the same duration. If the target has at least one full Rank of Shadow lands Taint, the Earth spirits will be filled with wrath, and punish him more severely, lowering his Earth Ring by 2 Ranks (to a minimum of 1).</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Breath Of The Fire Dragon" area="15' long, 5' wide blast" mastery="3" element="fire" range="Personal" duration="4 rounds" id="breath_of_the_fire_dragon">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell is a prayer to the Dragon of Fire, one of the mightiest of celestial beings, entreating him for a bit of his power. If the spell is successful, you gain the ability to breathe a bolt of flames from your open mouth once per Round as a Simple Action. The bolt has a DR equal to your Fire Ring and strikes every target in front of you within the area of effect. You may choose to take actions other than breathing fire while under the effects of this spell, but you cannot speak or cast spells. The spell expires after four Rounds, but you may choose to end this spell during the Reactions Stage of any earlier Round.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Fiery Wrath" area="One free-standing structure, or 50' x 50' area" mastery="3" element="fire" range="100'" duration="Instantaneous" id="fiery_wrath">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Fiery Wrath was originally created to clear brush for farming and to demolish wooden structures with a minimum of work and no hazard. It is also used to start bonfires for rituals and celebrations. The spell allows you to destroy a building or other structure by appealing to the excitable Fire kami with in the target's materials. All flammable materials within the area of effect immediately catch fire and burn until nothing but ash is left. The fire cannot be extinguished except by magical means; mundane water, sand, and other retardants would have no effect. Only one structure may be targeted by the spell, and the fire will not spread out to adjoining structures, as your prayers keep the Fire kami under tight control. Living beings and materials that are not flammable are not affected. In fact, while clothes worn by people caught within the area of effect will burn, their flesh will not so much as singe.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Haze Of Battle" area="One target" mastery="3" element="fire" range="10'" duration="5 Rounds, or 1 hour out of combat" id="haze_of_battle">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 Round)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Fire spirits are known for their erratic and temperamental nature, and shugenja can badly disrupt their foes in battle by imbuing them with this aspect of the element. The target of this spell is filled with the unfocused fury of Fire, enraging him and forcing him to lose perspective. The target immediately assumes the Full Attack Stance and cannot switch from that Stance for the duration of the spell. If the spell is cast out of Battle, the target gains the Brash and Contrary Disadvantages for the duration of the spell. This spells effects can be overcome by those of strong will. The target can attempt to resist with an opposed Willpower roll, but you add youre Fire to the total of your roll. If the spell is cast in battle, this roll occurs during the Reactions Stage of Battle. The roll occurs once every 10 minutes.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Hungry Blade" area="One weapon" mastery="3" element="fire" range="50'" duration="5 Rounds" id="hungry_blade">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 Round)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell is a more potent version of Biting Steel, designed to enhance any weapon rather than merely a sword. The spell strengthens the Fire spirits in a single target weapon, causing them to come forth and form a faint sheath of fire around it. The weapon's wielder adds +1k to all attack rolls, and all of his damage dice explode on a result of 8 or better. Each die can explode on an 8 or 9 only once per roll, however, even if the wielder has other effects that allow the die to explode on 9s.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Ravenous Swarms" area="One target person" mastery="3" element="fire" range="30'" duration="5 Rounds" id="ravenous_swarms">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 Round)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A more powerful and sophisticated form of the prayer which invokes the Fires From Within. This spell not only damages the target but also disrupts his own attempts to invoke the Fire kami, making it a very effective weapon against a rival Fire shugenja. You summon forth a bolt of flames that streaks toward the target with wild abandon. The flames deal 4k3 Wounds on impact and then encircle the opponent for the duration of the spell, waiting for him to make a mistake. If the target casts any Fire spell during that time, the Fire kami instantly strike, dealing 3k3 extra Wounds and causing the Spell Casting Roll to automatically fail. (The target loses the appropriate spell slot as usual.)</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Shining Light" area="One target armor" mastery="3" element="fire" range="30'" duration="10 rounds" id="shining_light">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0 per two Raises)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 Rounds)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Another example of spells which can imbue Fire kami into items, this spell temporarily binds a Fire kami into a piece of armor (such as a helmet or chest plate). The armor emits a bright light that becomes blinding whenever the wearer is attacked. Any time the armor's wearer is attacked in melee, immediately afterward the opponent takes 2k2 Wounds and is Blinded until the Reactions Stage of the same Round. The spell has no effect on ranged attacks.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Fist Of Osano-wo" area="20' radius" mastery="3" element="fire" range="50'" duration="1 round" id="the_fist_of_osanowo">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>thunder</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area of Effect (+10' radius)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A more powerful prayer to the Fortune of Thunder, this spell invokes his anger to devastate a targeted area. Massive lightning strikes and vaguely fist-shaped bolts of flame streak from the skies, smiting the area of effect. Weak structures and those easily set on fire (such as most Rokugani homes) are destroyed by the spells fury, or catch fire and are consumed. The spell has a DR equal to your Fire Ring, inflicting this damage on anyone caught within the area of effect Using this spell in populated areas is generally considered a criminal act, unless the shugenja can cite extreme circumstances, since fires are terribly dangerous to Rokugani cities.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Echoes In The Void" area="One target individual" mastery="3" element="void" range="25'" duration="Concentration" id="echoes_in_the_void">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Thoughts are as whispers in the Void, if one knows how to listen. As long as this spell is in effect and you maintain concentration on one target within the area of effect, you can hear what that person is thinking. How this manifests may vary depending upon the individual. Stalwart warriors may have short, curt statements summarizing their thoughts, while artisans may think in terms of poetry.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Kharmic Intent" area="One target individual" mastery="3" element="void" range="20'" duration="10 minutes" id="kharmic_intent">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Links forged of the Void allow the passage of enormous energy, the substance of the universe itself, between those who share it. You may target anyone willing individual with this spell. All remaining Void Points either of you possess are placed in a Single pool, which either of you may draw upon as normal. Essentially, this spell allows two individuals to share Void Points back and forth as they see fit. This also allows ishiken to share the additional Void Points they gain from other Void spells, At the end of the spells Duration, all remaining Void Points are divided between the participants, up to their normal maximum number.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Moment Of Clarity" area="Self" mastery="3" element="void" range="Personal" duration="2 rounds" id="moment_of_clarity">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The entirety of human achievement is reflected in the Void. You may select any one Skill. You gain temporary ranks in this Skill equal to your Void Ring. If you already possess ranks in this Skill, the new level of Skill replaces your old one; the two are not cumulative.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Read The Essence" area="One target object" mastery="3" element="void" range="Personal" duration="Instantaneous (but see spell description)" id="read_the_essence">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>divination</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Even objects have resonance, and retain some memory of those who hold them, and events that take place involving them. By meditating upon an object, you can gain a vision of the individual who held it last, or of a major event that might have involved it in some manner. Using this spell on a calligraphy brush, for example, might show the last person who used it to write a letter. Using it on a weapon might instead show the last death it was used to inflict. The GM has ultimate authority over what vision the spell imparts. Extremely important objects, such as ancestral weapons or standards, may have powerful visions that grip the caster for longer periods of time, rather than imparting simple instantaneous visions.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Void Release" area="One target individual" mastery="3" element="void" range="25'" duration="Instantaneous" id="void_release">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Most are ignorant of the Void coursing within them, and do not realize that it can be stolen away. You must make a Contested Void Roll against the target of this spell. If successful, the target loses one Void Point, and you gain one Void Point. An additional point is exchanged for every increment of 5 by which you exceed the target's roll. These temporary Void Points may take you above the maximum number of Void Points you may have, but they expire within one hour if not used. This spell cannot be used on a creature who does not have Void Points, or which has some other mechanical effect that substitutes for Void (such as Naga Akasha or Ratling Name).</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Near To Ice" area="One target individual" mastery="3" element="water" range="Touch" duration="5 rounds" id="near_to_ice">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (increased to 10' with 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>As water grows durable and resistant with the coming winter, so too can the water within the human form become sterner and more durable. The target of this spell has all current Wound Penalties negated for the duration of the spell. Any additional penalties incurred take full effect, using the difference between the negated penalty and the new penalty as the effective penalty incurred. Wounds are not healed by this effect, they simply cease to inhibit those suffering from them.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Regrow The Wound" area="One target individual" mastery="3" element="water" range="Touch" duration="Concentration" id="regrow_the_wound">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Special (your Water is increased by 1 for the purposes of healing, per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Water flows into all things, and flows out. In flowing out, it can carry away that which is undesirable. The pain and suffering inflicted by injuries can be channeled away from an individual, and cast into the infinite ocean where they are lost forever. The target of this spell recovers a number of Wounds equal to your Water Ring plus your School Rank each round the spell is in effect. You must touch the target when the spell is cast, but after that it may be maintained without physical contact.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Silent Waters" area="Self" mastery="3" element="water" range="Personal" duration="Variable" id="silent_waters">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The memory of the ocean is infinite, and its vast power call lay in wait for a very long time indeed. Upon completion of a successful casting of this spell, you may immediately cast a second spell of any element. This second spell must be a spell you can normally cast, and it must be of Mastery Level 3 or lower. If the second Spell Casting Roll is successful, the second spell is stored within you, and will not activate until a specific physical effect takes place, which you specify at the time of the casting. The spells trigger could be that you speak a certain word, draw a blade, or fall in Battle, for example. Whatever the trigger, when it occurs, the second spell immediately takes effect as if you had just finished casting the spell. A character may never benefit from multiple uses of Silent Waters at one time. If a second use of the spell is cast on the same individual, the currently stored spell is immediately dispelled and replaced with the new one.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Strike Of The Tsunami" area="A cone originating from the caster, ten feet wide at the end" mastery="3" element="water" range="25'" duration="Instantaneous" id="strike_of_the_tsunami">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+5 to the Earth Roll TN per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Water is everywhere, and obeys the commands of its favored shugenja. You summon a crushing wave of water that overruns everything in its path. The wave inflicts 3k3 Wounds on everything within the affected area, and all opponents within the area of effect must make an Earth Roll (TN 15) or suffer Knockdown. Obviously, everything within the area of effect is saturated with water.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Visions Of The Future" area="Self" mastery="3" element="water" range="Personal" duration="1 minute" id="visions_of_the_future">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>divination</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Although not as reliable as the natural,if extremely rare gift of foresight or the equally rare Void spells that enable divination, this spell still allows powerful visions of the future. It was first developed by the Tonbo Family of the Dragonfly Clan, and is found infrequently outside their ranks. The spell requires use of a large pool of still Water into which you must gaze. Upon completion of the spell, you enter a brief trance, and see images of things that have not yet come to pass. These Images are rarely direct, and tend to be symbolic (violence is depicted as a scene of battle, for instance) but the events foreseen are completely accurate, and will come to pass unless prevented by your direct intervention. Only the shugenja casting this spell may see the events depicted in the vision. Many shugenja believe that use of this spell is a means of thwarting the natural order, and regard both it and those who make use of it negatively.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Walking Upon The Waves" area="One target individual (may be the caster)" mastery="3" element="water" range="Touch" duration="10 minutes" id="walking_upon_the_waves">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>travel</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 individual per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The Water kami buoy those who carry their favor and grant them passage. The target of this spell may move across the surface of water as if it were slid ground (Basic Terrain). If the surface of the Water is disturbed, as by a storm, rolling waves, or any other similar event, it counts as Difficult Terrain.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Water Kami's Blessing" area="One target individual (may be the caster)" mastery="3" element="water" range="Touch" duration="5 rounds" id="water_kamis_blessing">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Special (your Water Ring is considered one rank higher per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>By calling upon the clarity of water, you can receive tremendous insight into the world around you. The target of this spell receives a bonus to all his Perception based rolls, whether Trait Rolls, Skill Rolls, or anything else, consisting of additional rolled dice equal to your Water Ring.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Call The Spirit" area="Target spirit" mastery="4" element="air" range="Special" duration="5 minutes" id="call_the_spirit">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Essentially an extremely powerful specific form of the basic spell Summon. Call the Spirit allows a shugenja summon any particular spirit, regardless of its realm, to have a discussion. You may use this spell to summon any spirit from any of the spirit realms, although realm denizens that are not spirits (such as Fortunes) are immune. If you know something specific about the spirit, either having seen it before or having intimate knowledge of its actions (for example, "the spirit that killed my father"), you may summon that spirit in particular. The nature of the spell prevents the spirit from attacking you unless you attack first, but it will not necessarily be friendly. The spirit disappears as soon as the spells duration expires. This spell can potentially summon extremely dangerous creatures, such as oni, and should be used with caution.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="False Realm" area="100' radius" mastery="4" element="air" range="250'" duration="1 hour" id="false_realm">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+10' radius)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+10 minutes)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The greatest masters of the wind can create illusions of such beauty and clarity that those affected by them might truly believe they were somewhere else. You can completely alter the appearance of the terrain within the area of effect of this spell. You can make a miserable swamp look, sound, and smell like a beautiful garden, or vice versa. Although these illusions can be extraordinarily intricate and completely convincing to all other senses, they still have no substance and cannot be touched.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Gift Of Wind" area="Self" mastery="4" element="air" range="Personal" duration="5 minutes" id="gift_of_wind">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The ultimate gift of the wind spirits is to become like the wind itself, unseen. The wind kami surround you and render you completely invisible. Non-magical vision can detect your presence. You can still be touched, heard, and smelled, hut unless you attack someone else, you remain invisible for the duration of the spell. The kami consider attacking someone to be ruining the joke, and immediately end the spells effect if you do so.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Know The Mind" area="Target individual" mastery="4" element="air" range="10'" duration="3 rounds" id="know_the_mind">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Although the ultimate secrets of the human mind and hidden even the winds, air kami can pluck the most intimate thoughts from the minds of others and whisper them to those who carry their favor. For the duration of this spell, you essentially hear the surface thoughts of the spells target. You only learn things they are actively thinking about. For example, if you asked the name of the Target's daughter, that name would appear in their mind instantly even if they had no intention of speaking it aloud. A Contested Roll using your Perception against the target's Awareness will also allow you to assess their true emotional state, regardless of how they appear physically.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Netsuke Of Wind" area="One hand-held object" mastery="4" element="air" range="Touch" duration="1 hour" id="netsuke_of_wind">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+10 minutes)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Although it requires great favor, the air kami are willing to coalesce into a solid form for a short period of time if they are fond enough of the priest asking them. You may create a small object out of the Air itself, something that can be held in one or both hands and that does not weigh more than twenty pounds at the most. This creation is an illusion, but it can be used functionally, including inflicting damage if it is a weapon. The object disappears completely at the end of the spells duration.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Symbol Of Air" area="Special" mastery="4" element="air" range="Touch" duration="Permanent" id="symbol_of_air">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>ward</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Priests of the kami are capable of inscribing powerful wards that invoke the power of the elements against all who attempts to pass them. A Symbol of Air must be inscribed on a solid object, most often a door, window, gate, or other passageway. Anyone attempting to pass through this passageway or otherwise pass by the area protected by the Symbol is affected by the protective ward. Such persons must succeed at a Contested Roll using their Earth against the caster's Air. Those who fail are affected by a powerful drowsiness, and must succeed at a Willpower Roll against the total of the Spell Casting Roll used create the ward or fall into a deep sleep for one hour. Those affected by the spell cannot be woken by normal means, but will awaken instantly if subjected to any attack or form of harm, as the kami will not be party to such humorless tricks. You may only have one Symbol of Air in existence at any time, and Symbol spells of different elements may never affect the same area. This spell may be dispelled by another casting of Symbol of Air from any shugenja, or by destroying the surface where the Symbol was etched.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Armor Of The Emperor" area="Self" mastery="4" element="earth" range="Personal" duration="5 Rounds" id="armor_of_the_emperor">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 Rounds)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell covers the caster in a thick layer of tough, resilient Earth spirits who repel all damage, whether physical blows or magical effects. Any time the caster suffers damage from an enemy physical or magical attack, each individual damage die has its total Reduced by the caster's Shugenja School Rank. This cannot reduce a die's total below O.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Essence Of Earth" area="One target creature (self or another)" mastery="4" element="earth" range="Personal or 20'" duration="10 rounds" id="essence_of_earth">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 per 2 Raises)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+1 Rank of Earth per 2 Raises, maximum increase 3 Ranks of Earth)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell infuses the target with the true strength of Earth, allowing him to shrug off blows which might otherwise take his life. For the duration of the spell, the target's Earth Ring is considered to be 1 Rank higher, and his Wounds are increased correspondingly. However, when the spell ends, the Earth spirits immediately depart and the target's Wounds return to normal - possibly resulting in death, if he has suffered sufficient injury.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Symbol Of Earth" area="Special" mastery="4" element="earth" range="Touch" duration="Permanent" id="symbol_of_earth">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>wards</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Priests of the kami are capable of inscribing powerful wards that invoke the power of the elements against all who attempt to pass them. A symbol of Earth can be inscribed on a solid object, most often a door, window, gate, or any other passageway. Anyone attempting to pass through this passageway or otherwise pass by the ward is affected by its power, and must succeed at a Contested Roll using their Air against the caster's Earth. Those who fail are struck with a powerful shockwave, and must succeed at a Strength roll against the Total of The Spell Casting Roll used to create the ward or be knocked Prone and Stunned. If they have at least one Rank of Taint, they also suffer 2k2 Wounds. You may only have one Symbol of Earth in existence at any time, and Symbol spells of different elements may never affect the same area. This spell may be dispelled by another casting of Symbol of Earth from any shugenja, or by destroying the surface where the Symbol was etched.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Tomb Of Jade" area="One target creature" mastery="4" element="earth" range="50'" duration="Concentration" id="tomb_of_jade">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>jade</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (Contested Roll, +1k1 to caster for each Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Considered by many shugenja to be the ultimate spell for opposing the creatures of the Shadowlands, this spell calls on the purest of Earth spirits, those of jade, to consume the very Taint within the target. The spell can only affect a target who has at least one full Rank of Shadowlands Taint, but if the spell fails, the caster will not automatically know that the target is Taint-free - there is always the possibility that the target was able to resist the spell l. When Tomb of Jade is cast, the target is momentarily immobilized as the Earth spirits enter his body. Each round, starting with the first round, the caster must make a Contested Earth roll against the target. If Rhea target wins, the spell ends. If the caster wins, the target takes 2k2 Wounds as the spirits begin transform his body into jade. This continues each round until the target successfully resists, the caster stops concentrating, or the target dies. Those killed by this spell are transformed into statues of pure jade, which crumbles away into mundane dust in 24 hours.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Wall Of Earth" area="Wall measuring a maximum of 10' high and 100' wide" mastery="4" element="earth" range="100'" duration="10 minutes" id="wall_of_earth">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (increase height by 1' or width by 10' per Raise), Duration (+1 minute), Range (+10')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell coaxes the spirits of Earth into rising up and forming a thick, powerful barrier to protect the caster. The wall of rock-hard earth which this spell creates can be shaped as the caster desires, and can be curved, placed on the side of a hill, or even formed in a circle. It is extremely tough, requiring a Strength roll against a TN of the caster's (Earth + School Rank) x 5 in order to break through. It is strong enough to hold back a raging flood, a lava flow, or hurricane winds, at least as long as the spell lasts. When the spell expires, however, the earthen barrier crumbles away in moments.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Death Of Flame" area="One target" mastery="4" element="fire" range="100'" duration="5 Rounds" id="death_of_flame">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell brings the anger of Fire on the target, suppressing his elemental Fire and lowering both his Agility and his Intelligence Ranks by an amount equal to your Fire Ring, to a minimum of one. If you maintain Concentration for the duration of the spells effect, the target cannot escape its effects. If you don't maintain Concentration, each Round at the start of his Turn the target may make a contested Fire roll against you (using his original, unmodified Fire Ring) to end the spells effect.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Defense Of The Firestorm" area="One target armor" mastery="4" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="5 Rounds" id="defense_of_the_firestorm">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 Round)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A more potent form of spells like Shining Light, this prayer summons forth an aura of magical flames from a suit of armor, surrounding and protecting: the armor's wearer. These flames do not harm the armor's bearer and do not harm living things, However, all wooden weapons (including arrows and many pole arms) burn instantly before they reach the target, doing no damage. The flames also impede sight to the target, increasing his Armor TN by 20.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Symbol Of Fire" area="10' radius" mastery="4" element="fire" range="100'" duration="Permanent" id="symbol_of_fire">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>ward</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Priests of the kami are capable of inscribing powerful wards that invoke the power of the elements against all who attempt to pass them. A symbol of Fire can be inscribed on a solid object, most often a door, window, gate, or any other passageway, anyone attempting to pass through this passageway or otherwise pass by the ward is affected by its power, and must succeed at a Contested Roll using their Water against the castor's Fire. Those who fail are Dazed, Blinded for one Round, and take 3k3 Wounds. This spell may be dispelled by another casting of Symbol of Fire from any shugenja, or by destroying the surface where the Symbol was etched. You may only have one Symbol of Fire in existence at any time, and Symbol spells of different elements may never affect the same area.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Mending Forge" area="One target item" mastery="4" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="Instantaneous" id="the_mending_forge">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This simple and powerful spell has only one function: to call on the creative power of Fire to bring back what has been destroyed. Any damaged or destroyed material item can be restored with this spell, provided all of its pieces are gathered in front of the caster, (if some pieces are missing, the spell will automatically fail.) The spell takes 1 minute to cast, and you must concentrate during that minute. If successful, the spell restores the item to a whole and undamaged state. It should be noted that the Fire kami must work harder to repair items of unusual quality - if you use this spell to repair a Nemuranai or an item of Fine quality or better, you must offer the Fire kami a gift of another item for them to burn and destroy - appropriate to the worth of the item.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Wall Of Fire" area="Special" mastery="4" element="fire" range="100'" duration="1 hour" id="wall_of_fire">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area of Effect (+1 increment, see spell description)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>You invoke the Fire kami to spring up and form a wall of flames, barring passage to all. The wall 1s a 10' tall, l' wide, and 25' long, and causes 6k6 Wounds to anyone who touches it. This wall may be made shorter or thinner as desired, within the total specifications, but all of the mass of flames must be used somehow. The wall may be created in an area where people or creatures are standing, forcing them to make a Reflexes Trait Roll against a TN of 20 to avoid taking Wounds from the fire. You may Raise to increase one of the specifications (height, width, or length) by its base increment 10', 1', or 25' respectively).</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Ward Of Thunder" area="15' radius from the armor" mastery="4" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="1 hour" id="ward_of_thunder">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
			<Tag>thunder</Tag>
			<Tag>ward</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Osano-Wo's protection can be temporarily invoked for a suit of armor by casting this spell and inscribing the kanji for thunder on the armor. Those within 15' of the armor are under Osano-Wo's care, and are completely protected from non-magical fire and thunder for the duration of the spell. Additionally, any Fire spell cast by a shugenja other than yourself which targets something within the area of effect has its Spell Casting TN increased by 20.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Balance Of Elements" area="One target individual (may be the caster)" mastery="4" element="void" range="Touch" duration="5 rounds / 5 minutes (see spell description)" id="balance_of_elements">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round / +1 minute, see spell description)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+1k1 Wounds per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Flaws in the great pattern of the Void can be overcome, no matter how severe. You may negate all Disadvantages of the target for the duration of the spell. Negative effects inflicted from spells (such as TN penalties, Armor TN reduction, or Trait/Ring reduction) are negated as well, as long as the Mastery Level of the spell causing the penalty is 3 or less. If used during the taxing environment of combat, the duration of this spell is extremely limited (5 rounds). In non-combat situations, however, the effects of the spell can last significantly longer (5 minutes). This temporary replenishing of the target's pattern also heals 3k3 Wounds.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Draw Closed The Veil" area="One target spirit" mastery="4" element="void" range="50'" duration="Instantaneous" id="draw_closed_the_veil">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 spirit per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The emptiness that is the Void is part and parcel of what separates the various spirit realms from one another, and it is possible to strengthen it in certain areas. You may target any one spirit not native to the mortal realm of Ningen-do. That spirit is banished to its home realm for a minimum amount of time equal to your Void Ring in months. Spirits that possess a physical body in the mortal realm, such as oni or certain shape shifter spirits, require a Contested Willpower Roll for this spell to affect them. Spirits that are significantly more powerful than you are (GM's discretion) may prove immune to the effects of this spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Fill With Emptiness" area="One target individual" mastery="4" element="void" range="Touch" duration="Instantaneous" id="fill_with_emptiness">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (may be increased to 10' with three Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Strengthening an individual's connection to the Void can replenish their reserves of inner energy. The target of this spell regains all lost Void Points, up to their normal maximum number.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Void Strike" area="One target individual" mastery="4" element="void" range="50'" duration="Instantaneous" id="void_strike">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+1k0 damage per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The mortal shell can endure only so much direct contact with the Void, too much, and the flesh can be destroyed by the exposure. This spell inflicts damage with a DR equal to your Void Ring.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Dominion Of Suitengu" area="Two bodies of water" mastery="4" element="water" range="100 miles" duration="Concentration" id="dominion_of_suitengu">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>divination</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+10 miles)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The Fortune of the Sea is a wrathful entity, but one who nevertheless blesses those who entreat him properly. This spell, created by the Mantis clan, allows you to peer into a body of water, which must be at least one foot across and one inch deep, and see out of any other body of water anywhere in the Empire, so long as it is within range of the spell. This can be at any point along the seacoast, a lake, river, stream, or even a puddle, but you must know the location of the body of water you are targeting. You can see everything around that body of water as if you were submerged within it. You cannot hear what is taking place, only see it.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Heart Of The Water Dragon" area="Target individuals equal to caster's School Rank (may include the caster)" mastery="4" element="water" range="25'" duration="1 round per School Rank" id="heart_of_the_water_dragon">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+1k0 healed per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The Water Dragon is a benevolent entity, and his blessings are powerful. Any time that a target of this spell suffers damage during the duration, he instantly regains 1k1 Wounds.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Strike Of The Flowing Waters" area="One target individual (may be the caster)" mastery="4" element="water" range="10'" duration="1 round" id="strike_of_the_flowing_waters">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Water flows over and through obstacles, and so too can those infused with its energy. The target of this spell may ignore bonuses this opponents' Armor TN conferred by worn armor, spell effects of Mastery Level 3 and below, and other non-Technique mechanical effects. Against non-human creatures who do not wear armor, this allows the target to treat their armor as Slower. This spell does not negate the Reduction awarded by armor, nor does it ignore the increase to armor TN conferred as a result of an individual adopting the Defense or Full Defense Stances.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Symbol Of Water" area="Special" mastery="4" element="water" range="Touch" duration="Permanent" id="symbol_of_water">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>ward</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Priests of the kami are capable of inscribing powerful Wards that invoke the power of the elements against all who attempt to pass them. A symbol of water can be inscribed on a solid object most often a door, window, gate, or any other passageway. Anyone attempting to pass through this passageway or otherwise pass through the area is affected by the protective Ward, and must succeed at a Contested Roll using their Fire against the caster's Water. Those who fail arc affected by a crippling terror, and must immediately roll against a Fear 7 effect. You may only have one Symbol of Water in existence at any time, and Symbol spells of different elements may never affect the same area. This spell may be dispelled by another casting of Symbol of Water from any shugenja, or by destroying the surface where the Symbol was etched.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Path Not Taken" area="Self" mastery="4" element="water" range="Personal" duration="1 day" id="the_path_not_taken">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Special (gain one bonus spell slot per five Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>No element can match the sheer versatility and adaptability of Water. Prior to casting this spell, you must select one Ring in which you will be temporarily weakened, and one in which you will be temporarily strengthened. Upon the successful conclusion of this spell, you may transfer a number of unused daily spell slots from the weakened Ring to the strengthened Ring. This spell lasts exactly one day, and then the effects are lost.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Cloud The Mind" area="One target individual" mastery="5" element="air" range="Touch" duration="Permanent" id="cloud_the_mind">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Special (+1 day of effect)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This extremely invasive spell is considered blasphemous by most honorable shugenja, and many respectable shugenja orders would deem its use reason for excommunication if not outright execution. This spell calls upon the air kami befuddle and dismay a target, invading their mind and influencing their ability to recall exactly what happened to them over a certain length of time. When this spell is successfully cast against a target, you must succeed at a Contested Roll using your Air versus the targets Earth. If successful, the target's memories are disrupted, and they forget what has happened to them over the course of the past week (five days). This information is completely lost the target. What's more, the spell renders them extremely susceptible to suggestion, and you can tell them what happened to them over the course of the missing time. This allows unscrupulous shugenja to exploit others and essentially give them false memories, although certain individuals are highly resistant to this manner of manipulation. It is possible to determine that an individual was the target of this spell through use of the Commune spell, but it requires that the kami be specifically asked if they can detect any such manipulation.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Draw Back The Shadow" area="30' radius" mastery="5" element="air" range="100'" duration="Instantaneous" id="draw_back_the_shadow">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+5' radius)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Just as the kami craft illusions, they can cast them aside. Within the area affected by this spell, any illusions created by spells of Mastery Level 4 or lower are automatically dispelled. Spells of Mastery Level 5 or 6 require a Contested Air Roll between you and the shugenja who created those spells; if you are successful, those illusions are dispelled as well. Ongoing magical effects that are not illusions may also be dispelled by this spell, but require a Contested Ring Roll between you and their creator, using your Air versus his appropriate Ring.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Echoes On The Breeze" area="One target individual" mastery="5" element="air" range="Personal" duration="Concentration" id="echoes_on_the_breeze">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>No destination is beyond the reach of the wind. With a simple prayer the kami, you can send your words across the span of the Empire, whispering into the ear of anyone you need to send a message. The person must be someone you know, and the spell will establish a link between the two of you only as long as you concentrate. You may communicate with one another, although you only hear each others voices as whispers. Both participants are instantly aware when the connection is forged, and either can end it at any point.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Legion Of The Moon" area="10' radius from the caster" mastery="5" element="air" range="Personal" duration="5 minutes" id="legion_of_the_moon">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The Moon can reveal what is hidden, but also conceal those who receive its blessings. You may summon the greater blessing of the Moon and envelop a large group of people within it, completely obscuring them from sight. Every individual you choose within the area of effect of this spell is rendered invisible to all normal senses for the duration of the spell. Those within the area that you choose to exclude are not affected. Anyone affected by the spell who performs any action that physically interacts with an unaffected individual is immediately excluded from the spell effect.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Slayer's Knives" area="Corridor of air 10' wide" mastery="5" element="air" range="30'" duration="Instantaneous" id="slayers_knives">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>thunder</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+3' wide)</Raise>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0 per three Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The wind can be deadly to those unprepared for its fury. You summon a powerful wind that tears through anything in its path. At your behest, the kami create a corridor of air filled with a cutting wind that inflicts damage with a DR equal tour Air Ring +2k to everything in its path. (For example, a shugenja with Air 4 would inflict 6k4 damage with this spell). Paper and light cloth are destroyed instantly, although heavier cloth may only be damaged. Anyone damaged by these winds must succeed at an Earth Ring Roll (TN 20) or be Knocked Down.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Earthquake" area="1 mile radius" mastery="5" element="earth" range="Personal" duration="1 minute" id="earthquake">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+500 yards)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell unleashes a terrible, ground-wracking earthquake, centered on the caster, who alone is unaffected. The earthquake utterly destroys all wooden buildings within the radius of effect, and inflicts severe damage on stone structures. All persons with in the area of the earthquake are thrown the ground, and remain Prone and Stunned for the duration of the spell, as well as suffering 2k1 Wounds. Individuals who are inside buildings (including the caster) will suffer 6k6 damage from falling debris, collapsing roofs, etc. Casting this spell within range of a major inhabited area is generally considered an act of war.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Major Binding" area="One target Shadowlands creature" mastery="5" element="earth" range="100'" duration="12 hours" id="major_binding">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>jade</Tag>
			<Tag>wards</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 hour)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+50')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The more powerful counterpart the Kuni family's Minor Binding spell, this spell has also been employed by other clan shugenja, especially those of the Phoenix Clan. It is used to imprison more powerful Shadowlands creatures and members of the Lost, typically for purposes of interrogation. Any Lost and any Shadow lands creature can be targeted with this spell. It can also target other spirit creatures who are tainted. It cannot affect any other creatures. The spell is a ritual, and requires ten minutes to cast (making it quite hazardous when dealing with a rampaging oni), but if additional shugenja join in casting the spell the casting time is reduced by 1 minute per shugenja, to a minimum of 1 minute. If it is cast successfully, the casters make a Contested Roll of their combined Earth Rings against to be Earth of the target. If the casters win, the spell calls forth manacles of pure elemental jade, which imprison the creature and render it helpless with the pain of its searing bonds for the duration of the spell. When the spell expires, however, the manacles instantly crumble into dust, and the creature is liable to seek immediate and bloody vengeance on its captors.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Strike At The Roots" area="One target creature" mastery="5" element="earth" range="50'" duration="3 rounds" id="strike_at_the_roots">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 Round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target per 2 Raises)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (Contested Roll, +1k1 to the caster for each Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A more powerful and devastating form of The Wolfs Mercy, this spell brings the true wrath of the Earth onto the target, draining all favor of the Earth from his body and leaving him a weak, trembling, helpless victim. After casting this spell, the caster must succeed in a Contested Earth roll against the targets of the spell (rolling separately if he is targeting multiple people). If the target loses the roll, his Earth Ring is immediately reduced to 1 for the duration of the spell. This also reduce his Wound Ranks and may result in his immediate death if he has already suffered injuries.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Kami's Strength" area="One target creature" mastery="5" element="earth" range="30'" duration="5 rounds" id="the_kamis_strength">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell allows the caster to fortify one person with the power of Earth, greatly enhancing their physical capabilities and their resistance to damage. The target of this spell gains Reduction of 20 and increases his Strength and one other physical Trait by an amount equal the casters Earth Ring. In return, however, the target is weighed down by the burden of Earth and cannot take Simple Move Actions (he can still take a Free Move Action).</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Kami's Will" area="One target creature" mastery="5" element="earth" range="30'" duration="10 rounds" id="the_kamis_will">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The counterpoint to the Kami's Strength, this spell infuses one person with the stubbornness and determination of Earth, greatly enhancing their willpower and making them all but immune the effects of elemental magic. The target of this spell increases his Willpower by an amount equal the caster's Earth Ring, and any spells (friendly or hostile, but not including Maho spells) which target him suffer a penalty of -XkX to their Spell Casting roll, where X is the caster's Earth Ring. In return, however, the target is made so stubborn and willful that he cannot function properly in a social environment, and suffers a penalty to all Social Skill rolls of Xk0, where X is the Earth Ring of the caster.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Destructive Wave" area="25' radius" mastery="5" element="fire" range="Personal" duration="Instantaneous" id="destructive_wave">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k1 per two Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A highly potent offensive spell, originally devised by the Isa-wa Elemental Masters. This prayer summons up a great mass of Fire kami, which roll outward from the caster in a wave of searing flames. Every target within the area of effect, whether friendly or hostile, takes 7k7 Wounds, for the raging flames make no distinction between ally and enemy. You alone do not take damage from the spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Everburning Rage" area="One target" mastery="5" element="fire" range="25'" duration="1 Round" id="everburning_rage">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 Round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A highly potent offensive spell, originally devised by the Isa-wa Elemental Masters. This prayer summons up a great mass of Fire kami, which roll outward from the caster in a wave of searing flames. Every target within the area of effect, whether friendly or hostile, takes 7k7 Wounds, for the raging flames make no distinction between ally and enemy. You alone do not take damage from the spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Follow The Flame" area="See below" mastery="5" element="fire" range="Personal" duration="5 Rounds" id="follow_the_flame">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1k0 per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell grants you exceptional control of the nearby Fire kami, allowing you to coax them into a very unusual and terrifying attack. On the Round this spell is cast and every Round thereafter, you may declare a line of sight target within 300' and send a stream of fire toward it that snakes along the ground. (On later Rounds, designating a target in this manner is a Simple Action.) The stream of fire moves at a rate of 75' each Round and moves around impassable (or inflammable barriers) in order to reach its target. Once the fire reaches its destination, the target bursts into flames, suffering 6k5 Wounds. The subject catches fire and takes half that many Wounds (rounded down) every subsequent Round until the Fire is doused normally or the spells duration expires.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Light Of The Sun" area="30' radius" mastery="5" element="fire" range="100'" duration="10 rounds" id="light_of_the_sun">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>jade</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This prayer invokes the power of the Sun, worshipped and venerated throughout Rokugan, and is a special favorite among the Moshi family, although shugenja all across the Empire have learned it. The spell calls down a concentrated beam of pure sunlight to punish the unworthy. Everyone caught in the area of effect hikes 2k2 Wounds per Round from the intense heat. Human targets (only) take an additional 2kl Wounds for every Honor Rank they are below 4, and an additional 2k2 Wounds if they possess at least 1 Rank of the Shadowlands Taint or are controlled by the Lying Darkness. Human targets who have an Honor Rank of 0 are Blinded for a number of Rounds equal to your Fire Ring.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Wings Of The Phoenix" area="Self" mastery="5" element="fire" range="Personal" duration="10 Rounds" id="wings_of_the_phoenix">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>travel</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The Phoenix is one of the most powerful symbols of Fire known to the Rokugani, and this spell calls on the essence of that being to grant its caster the power of flight. When this spell is cast, you summon clouds of Fire kami who take the form of giant wings sprouting from your back. You gain the ability to fly for the duration of the spell, moving at a speed of Water x 10 for a Free Action or Water x 20 for a Simple Action. If you are airborne when the spell expires, the Fire kami will bear you down to earth before departing.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Divide The Soul" area="Self" mastery="5" element="void" range="Personal" duration="1 minute" id="divide_the_soul">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The true mysteries of the Void are beyond the comprehension of non-ishiken. Using this spell, you may divide your soul across the Void, and exist in who places in the mortal realm simultaneously. The second "you" appears anywhere you might wish within your sight when you cast the spell. You have full knowledge of all that happens in both locations, and may take any normal actions in either place (both manifestations may take actions simultaneously as if they were two separate individuals). Only one manifestation may make a Spell Casting Roll per round. Any Wounds suffered by either manifestation are combined when the spell ends, and if either of your selves dies, both die.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Reforge" area="One object" mastery="5" element="void" range="Touch" duration="Permanent" id="reforge">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>All is one and one is all. You may take any single object and transform it into any other object of comparable size. This will only work on an object that is uniform in its construction, rather than assembled from multiple pieces. This spell will not affect living material. Although the effect of this spell is permanent, it can be reversed by a second casting on the same object, even by a different ishiken.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Unbound Essence" area="One target individual" mastery="5" element="void" range="25'" duration="1 hour" id="unbound_essence">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 hour)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Tampering with the pattern of another being's Void can result in catastrophic changes to their abilities. The target's Rings are reordered at random, along with their Traits. For instance, a target might exchange his Air Ring for his Fire Ring, and his Water Ring for his Earth Ring for the duration of this spell. Mental and Physical Traits exchange their values if those values are greater than the Ring. In the above example, if your target has Air 3 and Reflexes 4, he would instead have Fire 3 and Agility 4, with his values for those Traits reassigned this Air and Reflexes.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Ever-changing Waves" area="Self" mastery="5" element="water" range="Personal" duration="1 hour" id="everchanging_waves">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 hour)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Ultimate command over Water can allow flesh to flow like liquid. This spell allows you to physically alter your mortal body, changing your shape to match that of another natural creature (see the Book of tile Void for a list of the more common natural creatures found in Rokugan). While in this form, you keep your Mental Traits. For Physical Traits, you keep whichever is higher, yours or those of the animal into which you have transformed. Other natural abilities are gained as well, including natural weapons or sensory abilities. Some traditionalist shugenja sects look down upon this spell as unclean.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Hands Of The Tides" area="Targets up to caster's Water Ring" mastery="5" element="water" range="100' radius centered on the caster" duration="Instantaneous" id="hands_of_the_tides">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
			<Tag>travel</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+10')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The exchange of energy via Water is a simple matter that can ultimately lead to the exchange of flesh as well. Within the area of effect of this spell, you may choose a number of willing targets up to your Water Ring. You may switch the positions among those targets as you see fit, exchanging one for another. At the end of the spell, there must be a person in every position that was occupied when the spell began, but who is located where can vary depending upon the number of people affected.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Power Of The Ocean" area="One target individual" mastery="5" element="water" range="Touch" duration="A number of days equal to your School Rank" id="power_of_the_ocean">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 day per three Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Perhaps the greatest gift Water can bestow requires a powerful shugenja to impart it to others. This spell is a complex ritual that requires an hour to cast, and can only be cast upon a willing target. For the duration of the spell, the target requires no food, drink, or sleep. A number of times during the duration equal to your School Rank, the target may replenish his Void Points as a Simple Action; this is the equivalent of recovering Void Points via a full night of rest. The target also recovers a number of Wounds per hour equal to twice your Water Ring. If the target of this spell is a shugenja, he regains all expended spell slots at sunrise, regardless of whether he has had any rest. After the spell expires, the target lapses into a state of complete exhaustion. This lasts for exactly half the duration of the spell effect. During this time, the target cannot take any significant physical action, and can only move about sluggishly. Travel is completely impossible.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Suitengu's Embrace" area="One target individual" mastery="5" element="water" range="25'" duration="Instantaneous" id="suitengus_embrace">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>thunder</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The Fortune of the Sea is wrathful, and requires little prompting by his loyal adherents to smite another. By invoking the Water kami, you can fill a target's lungs with seawater, crippling and potentially killing them. If the spell is cast successfully, the target can take no actions other than to attempt to resist the spell. For All intents and purposes, the target is reduced to the Down Wound Level in terms of his ability to take actions. Each round he must make a Stamina Roll (TN 15) to resist. If the target makes three total successes, he spends one additional round vomiting up seawater, and then is fully recovered. However, if the target suffers two consecutive failures, he has fallen unconscious and will die within 1 minute unless some form of magical or medical intervention is made. Although means of combating drowning are not well known in Rokugan, it is possible to save an individual incapacitated by this spell by making a successful Medicine / Intelligence roll at TN 5O.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Final Bond" area="One target object or individual" mastery="5" element="water" range="Special" duration="Instantaneous" id="the_final_bond">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>divination</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The greatest bonds can never be broken. This spell allows you to detect the location of one object or individual well known to you, regardless of their location. The object must be one you have spent a tremendous amount of time around, or have handled frequently in the past. If the target of the spell is an individual, it must be someone well known to you, such as a member of your immediate family or a close friend. You instantly know their approximate location anywhere in the Empire. This is not a exact location, but sufficient to tremendously narrow any search (for example. "The City of Ryo Owari Toshi," or 'the northern reaches of the Shinomen Mori"). If the target is outside the Empire of Rokugan, the spell automatically fails.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Rise, Air" area="One summoned spirit" mastery="6" element="air" range="30'" duration="Concentration" id="rise_air">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The wind itself will take form to defend you. The ultimate actualization of the Summon spell, this spell summons a massive kami of pure air to serve you. It takes the form of a vaguely humanoid shape, roughly ten feet in height, with an indistinct outline visible only because of small debris caught up in its body. The kami may move up to 10' x your Air per round, and generates powerful winds in a twenty foot radius around it that hinder movement, preventing anyone from making Simple Move Actions within its area of effect. The manifest kami is treated as if it has all Physical Traits equal to your Air Ring, and attacks with a Jujitsu Skill Rank equal to half your Air Ring. Damage from these attacks has a DR equal to your Air Ring (for example, a spirit summoned by a shugenja with Air 6 would inflict 6k6 damage with its attacks). For purposes of taking damage, the spirit is considered to have Wounds as though it were a human with Earth equal tour Air Ring, but suffers no Wound penalties. It is Invulnerable (see the creature rules in the Book of Void for details of this ability). If it is successfully reduced to zero Wounds, it is dispelled.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The False Legion" area="Within 100' of the caster" mastery="6" element="air" range="Personal" duration="Concentration" id="the_false_legion">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>battle</Tag>
			<Tag>illusion</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (+10')</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+5 illusory figures per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The greatest illusory gift of the wind is legion. Within the area of effect of this spell, you can create a number of illusory figures up to your Air Ring x 10. These figures may be as detailed or as vague as you prefer (such as "Crane bushi" versus "heavy infantry of the fourth Daidoji legion"), although you must be familiar with their appearance in order for this spell to take effect (you could not, for example, replicate a family man you have never seen). The figures are fully mobile and will take whatever actions you desire as long as they do not leave the spells area of effect. They can be seen, heard, or even smelled, but as with most illusions, they cannot physically interact with objects or individuals in any way.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Wrath Of Kaze-no-kami (hurricane)" area="1 mile radius, centered on the caster" mastery="6" element="air" range="Personal" duration="Concentration (special)" id="wrath_of_kazenokami_hurricane">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>thunder</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The wrath of the air kami, and of the Fortune of the Wind, is truly dreadful to behold. In casting this spell, you unleash the full force of a hurricane upon your enemies. When the spell takes effect, you are standing in the eye of the storm, a zone radiating twenty feet in every direction from you, and in which no ill effects of the spell are suffered. Outside the eye, however, the brutal effects of the storm tear at everything in its path. Objects weighing less than five hundred pounds are lifted by the wind and tossed into the storm. Individuals in this area must hold on to something immobile or be cast into the winds to their certain death. Everyone within the affected region who does not have sturdy shelter suffers 1k1 Wounds per minute from the winds and minor debris. There is a one in ten chance each minute that an exposed individual will instead suffer 5k5 Wounds due to being struck by a wind-borne object. This spell lasts for a maximum of one hour, although it can last far shorter times if you are disrupted while maintaining the spell. This spell may not be cast in a given area more than once per month, as it completely exhausts the favors of the air Kami to perform it.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Essence Of Jade" area="One target creature" mastery="6" element="earth" range="30'" duration="10 rounds" id="essence_of_jade">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
			<Tag>jade</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target for 2 Raises, maximum of 3 total targets)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell calls on the purity of jade to protect its targets against the power of Jigoku, whether manifested as Taint or as the dreaded magic known as Maho. The target radiates the sacred green light of jade, and while the spell lasts, he cannot gain the Shadowlands Taint and is completely immune to the effects of all Maho spells. This spell cannot be cast on anyone who possesses at least one full Rank of Taint, for the pure jade spirits will recoil from such a corrupt individual, immediately alerting the caster to this individuals Tainted nature.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Power Of The Earth Dragon" area="One target creature" mastery="6" element="earth" range="50'" duration="10 minutes" id="power_of_the_earth_dragon">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 minute)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (Damage absorption +10 Wounds per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell is the most powerful of the physically protective Earth spells, calling on the favor of the Dragon of Earth to enshroud the targets with protection against all forms of harm. The Earth spirits absorb all damage which the targets suffer while the spell lasts. However, there are limits to even Earth's endurance. Nemuranai can bypass the protection. Further, if the Earth spirits protecting a specific target absorb a total of 100 Wounds of damage, they will be exhausted and the spells effects on that target come to an end.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Prison Of Earth" area="One target creature" mastery="6" element="earth" range="30'" duration="Permanent" id="prison_of_earth">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>wards</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+5')</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (Contested Roll, +1k1 to the caster for each Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The most powerful of the binding spells which Earth shugenja use to deal with dangerous creatures, this spell can literally imprison the essence of such a creature for as long as the caster desires. Casting this spell requires that the caster possess a gem or pearl in which to imprison the creature (the GM may, discretionally, allow other rare or precious items to be used, such as a beautifully inlaid puzzle-box or a crystal pendant). The spell can target any creature native the realms of Jigoku, Gaki-Do, or Toshigoku, and any other non-human creature with at least 1 full Rank of Taint. After casting the spell, the caster must make a Contested Willpower roll against the target. If the caster wins, the creature's physical body vanishes and its essence is imprisoned within the item. It will remain there indefinitely unless the item is physically destroyed. If that happens, the released creature immediately resumes its physical form, and will most likely seek vengeance against the caster or his descendants.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Rise, Earth" area="One summoned spirit" mastery="6" element="earth" range="30'" duration="Concentration" id="rise_earth">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The Earth itself arises and takes form to defend you. The ultimate realization of the Summon spell, this prayer summons a massive kami of pure Earth to serve you. It takes the form of a vaguely humanoid shape, roughly ten feet in height, with a broad body and thick limbs all formed from earth and stone. This mighty Earth kami may move up to 5x your Earth per round, and its footsteps shake the Earth 1n a twenty foot radius around it, preventing anyone from making Simple Move Actions within its area of effect. This Earth spirit is treated as if it has all Physical Traits equal to your Earth Ring, and attacks with a Jujitsu Skill Rank equal that of your Earth Rank. The DR from these attacks is equal to your Earth Ring. The kami can carry up to 1,000 pounds of weight if so commanded, and its blows are strong enough to destroy any wooden structure and to shatter stone walls of one-foot thickness. For purposes of taking damage, the spirit is considered to have Wounds as though it were a human with Earth equal to your Earth Ring, but suffers no Wound penalties. It is Invulnerable (see the creature rules in the Book of Void for details of this ability). If it is successfully reduced to zero Wounds, it is dispelled.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Beam Of The Inferno" area="One Target" mastery="6" element="fire" range="200'" duration="Instantaneous" id="beam_of_the_inferno">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This is perhaps the deadliest single spell available ta shugenja, and one of the most fearsome spells ever developed in the Empire. The prayer invokes a tremendous blast of fire against the chosen target, who takes l0k10 Wounds. The spell puts all the Fire kami in the area into a state of agitation, and normal fires within range will burn hotter and more violently for many minutes after the spell is cast.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Globe Of The Everlasting Sun" area="1 mile" mastery="6" element="fire" range="500'" duration="1 day" id="globe_of_the_everlasting_sun">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>defense</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This mighty prayer calls on all the Fire kami in the area to remain quiet and calm, soothing the agitation which often afflicts them. It is often invoked during major festivals, such as the crowning of a new Emperor. For the duration of the spell, all buildings within the area of effect are immune to the effects of magical fire, and all Fire spells cast within that area have the TN of their Spell Casting Rolls increased by 15. Normal fires will still ignite and burn, but they do so sluggishly, and do not spread easily.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="The Soul's Blade" area="One target weapon" mastery="6" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="5 Rounds" id="the_souls_blade">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>craft</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 Round per 3 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell imbues incredibly powerful Fire kami into a weapon, granting it the full fury of a raging firestorm. A bushi armed with this weapon is a terrible opponent, for the Fire spirits shock and daze his enemies with every blow. For the duration of the spell, the weapon will overcome invulnerability and every target hit with it is automatically Stunned.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Ring Of The Void" area="Self" mastery="6" element="void" range="Personal" duration="Concentration (requires one hour to cast)" id="ring_of_the_void">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (-5 minutes to casting time)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Rare and extraordinarily powerful, even by shugenja standards, this prayer calls on the unique favor of the dragon whose domain the ishiken tread: the Void Dragon. Unlike most spells, this is not something that is taught by others, but rather is simply learned through insight by those capable of casting it (and as such it has no scroll associated with it). This spell, more of a meditation ritual, actually allows you to commune with the Void Dragon itself, a feat few mortals have ever managed to perform successfully. During your brief moments of contact with this divine entity, you may ask it questions as you see fit. The Void Dragon knows all that can be known, although it is under no particular compulsion to answer you directly, or even at all. Respect must be maintained at all times, for those who have attempted this feat in the past and failed to pay homage to their patron have ceased to exist altogether.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Rise From The Ashes" area="One target individual" mastery="6" element="void" range="Touch" duration="Instantaneous (requires one hour to cast)" id="rise_from_the_ashes">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Special (+1 hour of regression per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Everything that exists has a pattern in the Void, a thread woven in the tapestry that is existence. By recalling the memory of that pattern, you can reverse recent effects that have happened to a living creature. When you cast this spell on an individual, you are essentially restoring their existence within the Void in accordance with their previous self. Upon completion of the spell, the person is immediately restored to the state they were in eight hours prior to when the spell was begun. Any injuries suffered during this time, the effects of diseases or poisons, even the acquisition of supernatural conditions such as the Shadowlands Taint or corruption by the Lying Darkness, can be undone in this manner. Upon the completion of this spell, you lose all Void Points, and you may not regain Void Points for a period of three days, after which they will begin to recover at one Void Point per day until you have your maximum normal amount again. This spell cannot be used to restore someone who has died.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Unmake The World" area="One target creature, individual, or object" mastery="6" element="void" range="50'" duration="Instantaneous" id="unmake_the_world">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+10')</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The most powerful and terrifying ability of those who command the Void is the ability to destroy the bonds that exist between the five elements. By eradicating the bonds between existing elements, you can effectively cause one object or creature to cease to exist. When you cast this spell on a living creature, you must succeed at a Contested Roll using your Void against the target's Earth. If you are successful, they are instantly killed, and their remains disappear into the Void. Success is automatic against a non-magical object, but attempting to destroy an awakened object, such as a Nemuranai, may have dire ramifications at the GM's discretion. The kami contained within an awakened object frequently respond very poorly to this manner of attack, for instance.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Peace Of The Kami" area="One target individual" mastery="6" element="water" range="Touch" duration="Instantaneous" id="peace_of_the_kami">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The ultimate benevolence of the Water Dragon is without measure. The target is instantly cured of all diseases, his system purged of any and all poisons, and all Wounds are completely healed.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Rise, Water" area="One summoned spirit" mastery="6" element="water" range="30'" duration="Concentration" id="rise_water">
		<Tags/>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The sea itself will take form to defend you. The ultimate actualization of the Summon spell, this spell summons a massive kami of pure water to serve you. It takes the form of a vaguely humanoid shape, roughly ten feet in height, with an outline that constantly shifts and changes due tits fluid construction. The kami may move up to 15' x your Water per round, and saturates the ground in a 20' radius around it, ensuring that all terrain in that area is at least Moderate Terrain (unless it was already Difficult). The manifest kami is treated as if it has all Physical Traits equal to your Water Ring, and attacks with a jiujutsu Skill Rank equal to half your Water Rank. Damage from these attacks has a DR equal to your Water Ring. For purposes of taking damage, the spirit is considered to have Wounds as though it were a human with Earth equal to your Water Ring, but suffers no Wound penalties. It is Invulnerable (see the creature rules in the Book of Void for details of this ability). If it is successfully reduced to zero Wounds, it is dispelled.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="Water's Sweet Clarity" area="Target body of water" mastery="6" element="water" range="Personal" duration="3 rounds" id="waters_sweet_clarity">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>divination</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>None</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The greatest form of augury is one that speaks directly and allows others to witness it. By focusing your energy on a still body of water, you can invoke powerful visions of the future based upon your questions. You may ask one question, and the waters will reveal the answer. The answer takes the form of three separate images, which may be connected in any number of ways, including events occurring over time, or perhaps three facets of a single event. Unlike other forms of augury, others may witness these visions as well.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="Wisdom and Clarity" area="self" mastery="2" element="water" range="Personal" duration="1 hour" id="wisdom_and_clarity">
    <Tags/>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Duration (+30 minutes)</Raise>
      <Raise>Targets (may target another with 2 Raises)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>By entreating the insight of the Water kami, a shugenja may dramatically increase his ability to perceive the world around him. For the duration of this spell, your reading speed doubles, and you will have perfect recall of everything you read while under the influence of this spell. This spell does not enhance comprehension, however, so any language or cipher you are not familiar with is still completely indecipherable.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="Ebb and Flow of Battle" area="All selected allies within 50' radius of the caster" mastery="4" element="water" range="Personal" duration="5 rounds" id="ebb_and_flow_of_battle">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>Battle</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Duration (+ 1 round per two Raises)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>Mobility is one of the greatest strengths of Water. In a skirmish or a Battle, mobility is key to survival. This spell increases the movement speed of all allies within range. You may choose to exclude specific allies from its effects if you choose. All those affected by the spell may move a distance equal to their Water Ring x 10 in feet as a Free Action (this is normally a Simple Action).</Description>
  </SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Blood And Darkness" area="30 foot radius" mastery="1" element="air" range="Centered on caster" duration="10 rounds" id="maho_blood_and_darkness">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Area (5 foot additional radius per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 rounds per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell plunges the air around the caster into an unnatural visual obscurement, either pitch black or dark blood red as the caster desires, as the kansen literally block the vision of everyone in the area of effect. Everyone who enters or remains within the spell's area of effect, except for the caster, is considered to be Blind until they move out of the area of effect. The caster can see normally - the kansen recognize their master and do not block his vision. The zone of obscurement does not move once it is created. Magical effects or Shadowlands powers that overcome blindness can see through the obfuscation, but otherwise there is no way to overcome tbe effect until the spell expires.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Inspire Fear" area="One Target person" mastery="1" element="air" range="50 feet" duration="1 hour" id="maho_inspire_fear">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+10 minutes per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10 foot per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This maho spell causes the target person to gain a Phobia of the caster's choice. For the duration of the spell, the victim is considered to have a 3-Point Phobia (as per the Disadvantage in the Book of Fire) of a nature chosen by the caster. Mahotsukai frequently use this spell to make their victims afraid of their weapons or allies, to make shugenja afraid of their spell scrolls, and other cruel tricks.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Legacy Of The Dark One" area="One target person/creature" mastery="1" element="air" range="100 feet" duration="5 rounds" id="maho_legacy_of_the_dark_one">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (1 addtional Void point per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This subtle maho spell causes distracting kansen to cluster around the target, disrupting his connection to the true Void. Tbe target immediately loses one Void point, and cannot regain it for the duration of the spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Sinful Dreams" area="One target intelligent creature" mastery="1" element="air" range="300 feet" duration="1 hour" id="maho_sinful_dreams">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+50 feet per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (1 additional Free Raise awarded per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This subtle and sinister spell causes the target to experience dreams of committing dark, sinful, and dishonorable acts. It can only be cast on a person who is either sleeping or in a situation where they could easily fall asleep (resting, meditating, etc). The caster need not know exactly where the target is located. So long as the target is within the spell's range, the spell will succeed. Due to the impact of these disturbing and distracting dreams, the victim of this spell becomes vulnerable to future manipulation by the caster. For the next 24 hours after the spell concludes, the caster gains a Free Raise on all Temptation and Intimidation rolls against the victim. The caster may Raise on the spell to increase the number of Free Raises awarded.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Blood Rite" area="One Target person/creature" mastery="1" element="earth" range="Touch" duration="10 minutes" id="maho_blood_rite">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 minutes per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (heals an extra +1k0 per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A deceptive spell which allows many maho-tsukai to masquerade as noble priests, healing the injured. This spell convinces the kansen to flow into the target, stimulating his flesh to heal and knit itself closed, and stimulating his body to feats of physical prowess. The target immediately heals 1k1 Wounds, and for the duration of the spell one of his physical Traits (chosen by the caster) is treated as one Rank higher. (This can award a temporary increase in Wounds if it causes the target's Earth Ring to increase, but the Wounds will drop back to normal when the spell expires, and this may result in the death of the target if he has taken sufficient injury.) However, there is a cruel price for this assistance from the kansen: the target of spell immediately gains 1k1 points of Shadowlands Taint.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Summon Undead Champion" area="One humanoid corpse" mastery="1" element="earth" range="100 feet" duration="1 hour" id="maho_summon_undead_champion">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 hour per two Raises)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+20 feet per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 corpse per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell is used by maho-tsukai to quickly bring forth undead warriors to protect themselves or slaughter their enemies. It must be cast on a corpse which is within the spells range - it cannot target a living creature. The corpse will be animated by a kansen, rising up and serving the caster as best it can. Mechanically, the animated corpse is considered a zombie (as per the Book of Void, page 331). It obeys any simple commands (such as "kill them" or "wait here") from the maho-tsukai who summoned it. Complex or conditional orders cannot be understood, and the zombie will simply stand and wait until it is given an order simple enough to understand. Once created, it can move freely beyond the spell's initial range. If the zombie is beheaded or destroyed, it will not re-animate unless the spell is cast again. At the end of the spell's duration, the kansen will depart and the undead creature will collapse to the ground, becoming nothing more than a corpse.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Bleeding" area="One Target person/creature" mastery="1" element="fire" range="50 feet" duration="Indefinite" id="maho_bleeding">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Damage (+1 Wound of bleeding per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell inflicts a malignant kansen on a wounded person. The target of the spell must be already injured (suffering from at least 1 Wound) in order for this spell to be effective. The spell causes the injury to begin bleeding, inflicting 1 Wound per Round at the start of the victim's Turn. This effect continues every Round indefinitely, unless the injury is bandaged with a successful Medicine (Wound Treatment) / Intelligence roll at TN 20. Magically healing the target to full Wounds will also end the bleeding.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Written In Blood" area="One message (up to ten words)" mastery="1" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="1 week" id="maho_written_in_blood">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 day per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+3 words per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Maho-tsukai use this spell to leave hidden messages, either to communicate with each other or to intimidate others. The message is written in blood onto any flat surface, and may be up to ten words long (Raises can be taken ro lengthen the message). When the message is completed, the blood will sink into the surface and disappear, reappearing later when a condition set by the caster is fulfIlled. Conditions for the message's reappearance can be as simple or as complex as the caster might desire, so long as they are conditions the kansen can reasonably perceive (GM's judgment). Until the message reappears, it is physically undetectable, although spells such as Sense or By the Light of the Moon will detect something magically concealed in the surface. If the spell's duration expires without the trigger-event taking place, the hidden blood will reappear without forming the message.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Disrupt The Limb" area="One Target person's limb" mastery="1" element="water" range="50 feet" duration="10 rounds" id="maho_disrupt_the_limb">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 rounds per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10 feet per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This curse causes the muscles of a target limb - an arm or leg of the caster's choice - to be afflicted with pain, weakness, and tremors for the duration of the spell. All rolls for physical actions taken with that limb for the duration of the spell suffer a +15 TN penalty. In addition, if the target limb is a leg, the victim is considered to be under the effects of the Lame Disadvantage for the duration of the spell.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Curse Of The Unblinking Eye" area="One target creature" mastery="2" element="air" range="100 feet" duration="2 days" id="maho_curse_of_the_unblinking_eye">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 day per 2 Raises, maximum of 7 days duration)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell curses the target with the attentions of malignant Air kansen who prevent him from sleeping. For the duration of the spell, the victim cannot sleep, and thus cannot recover Void points or spell slots from rest. Further, for each day the victim goes without sleep, he must make a Raw Stamina roll at a TN equal to 5 + (5x number of nights without sleep) or suffer the effects of being Fatigued.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Caress Of Fu Leng" area="One target object" mastery="2" element="earth" range="50 feet" duration="Instantaneous" id="maho_caress_of_fu_leng">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+10 feet per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell summons dark kansen to consume and destroy the substance most inimical to them - jade. The caster may target any one jade item, weapon, or object within the spell's range (he must be able to see it). The jade is instantly corrupted, its blessed properties annihilated by an overwhelming saturation of Taint. Only a foul black slime is left behind. This spell cannot affect an awakened nemuranai (magical relic) that contains jade.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Drain The Soul" area="One target person/creature" mastery="2" element="earth" range="50 feet" duration="10 minutes" id="maho_drain_the_soul">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 minutes per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10 feet per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+1 stamina rank per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell causes malignant Earth kansen to afflict the target, draining away his natural Earth and leaving him weak and sickly. For the duration of the spell, the victim's Stamina rank is reduced by 1 (to a minimum of 1). This can cause the victim's Earth Ring to temporarily drop, reducing his Wound Ranks and making him more vulnerable to injury.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Pain" area="One target creature" mastery="2" element="earth" range="10 feet" duration="1 round" id="maho_pain">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 Round per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+5 feet per Raise), Targets (+1 target per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell wracks the target with intense physical pain shooting up and down the limbs and through the torso. The target falls Prone, helpless with pain, and cannot act on his next Turn. In addition, the target must make a Willpower Trait Roll at TN 20 to avoid crying aloud in pain, which could cause a loss of Honor and/or Glory.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Spreading The Darkness" area="Two target persons" mastery="2" element="earth" range="30 feet" duration="Permanent" id="maho_spreading_the_darkness">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+10 feet per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This sinister curse is employed by maho-tsukai both to control their own Taint and to spread the gift of Jigoku to others. The spell targets two people, at least one of which must have the Shadowlands Taint. The spell causes some of this Taint to leave that creature and transfer to the other, the kansen gleefully carrying the gift of Jigoku from one creature to the other. The maximum number of Taint points which can be moved in this manner is equal to The caster's Earth + Insight Rank - however, it can never remove the last point of Taint from the target. (Once the Taint has its grip on someone, it is supremely unwilling to let go.) If the person receiving the Taint is an unwilling target, the caster must succeed in a Contested Willpower roll against the target, or the spell fails.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Puppet Master" area="One target undead creature" mastery="2" element="fire" range="100 feet" duration="4 hours" id="maho_puppet_master">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 hours per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+20 feet per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 undead creature per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell allows a maho-tsukai to exert his will against any undead creatures in the area, taking control of them and forcing them to obey his will. If the spell targets a mindless uncontrolled creature such as a zombie, the caster takes control of it automatically. If the spell targets a free-willed undead creature such as a pennaggalon, the caster must succeed in a Contested Willpower roll against the creature. Likewise, if the spell targets an undead creature controlled by someone else (another maho-tsukai, oni lord, etc), the caster must succeed in a Contested Willpower roll against the controller. Once controlled, the undead will obey the caster's commands for the duration of the spell, subject to the limits of the creature's intelligence. Zombies will typically only be able to comprehend the most basic of orders ("kill him," etc). At the end of the spell's duration, the undead either revert to the control of their previous master (if they had one) or become free-willed once more.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Curse Of Weakness" area="One target person or creature" mastery="2" element="water" range="50 feet" duration="10 rounds" id="maho_curse_of_weakness">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 rounds per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10 feet per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A more powerful form of the spell Disrupt Limb, this spell inflicts an overwhelming barrage of angry Water kansen on the target. The kansen flow through his body, inflicting headache, weakness. fatigue, and muscle tremors. For the duration of the spell, he is at a +10 TN penalty to all physical and mental activities that require Skill or Trait rolls. (This includes Spell Casting rolls.) He also suffers a -10 penalty to his Armor TN, as the debilitation makes it difficult for him to dodge blows.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Hate's Heart" area="One target creature" mastery="3" element="air" range="50 feet" duration="3 rounds" id="maho_hates_heart">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 round per 2 Raises)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10 feet per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The target of this spell is infused with Air kansen which cause him to suffer a sudden, violent, murderous rage against whoever he is looking at or speaking with when the spell takes effect. (Cunning maho-tsukai usually cast this spell from concealment, to avoid the risk that the rage might he directed against them.) For the duration of the spell, the victim will be consumed with murderous, uncontrollable rage, unable to think of anything but killing this person. He will immediately attack the object of his hatred to the very best of his ability. At the start of each Turn, the victim may roll his Honor at TN 30 to control the rage for that Round. The victim will only be able to take Free and Simple Actions during that Round, since so much of his energy is dedicated to conrrolling the anger.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Death Beyond Life" area="One target person" mastery="3" element="earth" range="Touch" duration="24 hours" id="maho_death_beyond_life">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+24 hours per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell is among the most secret spells employed by the leaders of the Bloodspeaker cult, and is quite rare among maho-tsukai outside of that elite group. It allows the caster to literally cheat death, for himself or another person. The spell must be cast on its target while still alive, and its protective effect normally lasts 24 hours, although skilled spell casters can extend it. If the target dies within the duration of the spell, powerful kansen will cany his soul away, preventing it from passing on to Meido for judgment. Exactly eight hours after death, they will bring hack the soul and re-infuse it into the body, and the target rises from the dead at the Down Wound Rank. Returning from the dead in this way inflicts a full Rank of Taint on the target, due to his soul having been in the care of kansen for eight hours. This blasphemous resurrection will work as long as the target's corpse is still intact - even if limbs have been lost or the head severed, the body will reassemble itself when the kansen return. The only way to prevent the resurrection is to scatter the body parts or burn the corpse to ashes.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Essence Of Undeath" area="One humanoid corpse" mastery="3" element="earth" range="50 feet" duration="Indefinite" id="maho_essence_of_undeath">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+20 feet per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target per 3 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A more powerful form of undead summoning, this spell animates a dead corpse into an undead warrior. Unlike the minor, temporary zombies created by "Summon Undead Champion," this spell binds a kansen into a dead body, creating a powerful Tainted revenant which serves the caster to the best of its ability. The resulting creature is described as "Undead Revenant" in the Book of Void, page 330. The revenant will last indefinitely (until destroyed), and the Taint infusing its body prevents it from decaying further. It cannot speak, but can understand and obey any verbal command. It will serve the maho-tsukai who summoned it until it is physically destroyed.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Summon Oni" area="One summoned oni" mastery="3" element="earth" range="50 feet" duration="Indefinite" id="maho_summon_oni">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Special (+1k0 per Raise to the Willpower roll to control the oni)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (more powerful oni, GM's discretion)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>Among the most hazardous spells in the maho-tsukai's repertoire, this spell summons forth an oni from Jigoku. The oni appears anywhere the caster desires within the range of the spell, and must immediately be given a name - either the caster's own name or the name of another person closely connected to the caster (a close friend, immediate blood relative, or someone who owes the caster their life) - or it will simply depart back to Jigoku. A name, however, anchors the oni into Ningen-do and allows it to remain within the mortal realm. Once the caster has given the oni a name he must engage in a Contested Willpower roll against it. If the caster gave the oni his own name, he gains a +3k2 bonus to this roll. The caster may also Raise when casting Summon Oni to gain additional unkept dice on this roll. The GM should determine the Willpower of the oni - the more powerful the oni, the higher its Willpower. If the caster wins the roll, the oni will obey his commands (at least for now). If the oni wins the roll however, it is free of control and typically runs amok until it is destroyed. Naming an oni is a perilous business, for the oni will try to steal the name away and thereby gain full autonomy and the ability to remain in the mortal realm. Such creatures become Oni Lords, monstrously powerful, able to spawn lesser but still potent copies of themselves. Thus summoned oni will typically not immediately attack the persons who gave them names, seeking instead to leave them alive until they can steal the names completely. Any person who shares their name with an oni will acquire an Oni Mark, a small discoloration on the skin. Every day the bearer of an Oni Mark must make an Earth roll to resist gaining the Shadowlands taint as the connection to the oni corrupts them {see the Taint rules for more details}. Each week they must make another Contested Willpower Roll, similar to the first, against the oni in order to avoid surrendering their name to it. The oni gains +1k1 to this roll for each Rank of Shadowlands Taint the Mark has inflicted on its bearer. If the name-bearer is the same person who summoned the oni, he continues to gain the +3k2 bonus to the roll, plus any bonuses from Raises on the original spell. If the oni ever wins this roll it steals the victim's name and becomes an Oni Lord, freeing itself from any control by its summoner (even if that person is different from the one with the Oni Mark). The now-nameless victim of the Oni Mark becomes a slave of the oni and must obey its commands. If the oni is destroyed or otherwise banished back to Jigoku, it loses its connection to the person with its name and the Oni Mark disappears.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Armour Of Obsidian" area="One target person or creature (can be caster)" mastery="3" element="fire" range="Touch" duration="10 minutes or until used" id="maho_armour_of_obsidian">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+5 minutes per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (absorb one additional spell per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell wreaths the target in an invisible shield of kansen. If the target is struck or affected by a spell with the Jade keyword, the kansen intercede and negate the spell's effect. This is quite spectacular, as the target is briefly wreathed in a cloud of black, soundless fire which visibly absorbs and consumes the spell. The magical armor normally only works once, although a skilled maho-tsukai can make it strong enough to withstand multiple spells.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Truth Is A Scourge" area="One target person" mastery="4" element="air" range="50 feet" duration="10 minutes" id="maho_truth_is_a_scourge">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+2 minutes per Raise), Range (+10 feet per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>One of the more subtle and psychologically destructive spells in the maho-tsukai's arsenal, this spell causes a kansen to distort the target's thoughts, making it impossible for him to lie. Regardless of what he might intend to say, the target of this spell will find himself telling the truth, no matter how damaging that truth might be to himself, his family and lord, or his Clan. In fact, he will find himself blurting out any dangerous or damaging secrets he possesses. In order to conceal the truth while under the effects of this spell, the target must make a Willpower roll at TN 30.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Chains Of Jigoku" area="One creature or person" mastery="4" element="earth" range="50 feet" duration="10 minutes" id="maho_chains_of_jigoku">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+5 minutes per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+10 feet per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+1k0 per Raise to caster's roll to contain the prisoner)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>A dark counterpoint to the binding spells practiced by Earth shugenja, this spell summons the kansen to bind and trap living creatures (it cannot affect the undead). When the spell is cast, manacles of dark, rusty iron burst from the ground and ensnare the target, trapping him and holding him in place. The target is rendered immobile and helpless, unable to take any physical actions other than to try to break free (although he can still speak). The victim can only break free by making a Contested Roll of his Strength against the Earth of the maho-mahotsukai who cast the spell. (The caster may take Raises to gain additional unkept dice on this roll) When the spell expires, the manacles melt away into a disgusting black ooze.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Possession" area="One target person" mastery="5" element="air" range="100 feet" duration="1 day" id="maho_possession">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 day per 2 Raises)</Raise>
			<Raise>Range (+25 feet per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+1k0 on Contested Willpower Roll per Raise)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This fearsome spell allows the maho-tsukai to take direct possession of another person, forcing his soul into the victim's body and controlling it like a puppet. The caster must know the name of his chosen victim and must also have either a drop of blood or a piece of hair from the target. Once the spell is cast, the maho-tsukai must make a Contested Willpower Roll against the target. (The caster may take Raises to gain unkept dice on this roll.) If the target wins the roll, the possession fails, and the caster suffers 2k1 Wounds as the angry kansen lash back at the one who summoned them. If the caster wins the roil, he takes complete possession of the victim's body and may use it as he sees fit. He does not, however, gain any of the possessed body's memories, knowledge, or instincts. In mechanical terms, the possessed body has its own physical Traits and Advantages but has the mental Traits,mental/spiritual Advantages, School Techniques, and Skills of the possessing maho-tsuka. The spell's victim experiences what is happening to him in an eerie, dream-like manner. When the spell's duration ends, the caster's soul returns to his own body, and the victim regains control of himself - and must face the consequences of what he did while possessed. While the possession lasts, the caster's body is in a comatose state. He can end the possession early and return to his own body at will. If the possessed body is killed, he will immediately return to his own body. If his own body is killed while he possesses another, he will have no place to return when the spell expires and will thus die the moment the spell's duration ends.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Touch Of Death" area="One target creature" mastery="5" element="earth" range="50 feet" duration="Instantaneous" id="maho_touch_of_death">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Range (+10 feet per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Targets (+1 target per 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>The most dreaded of all maho spells, the Touch of Death ages, blackens, and blights the target. Skin and flesh shrivel and blacken, hair turns gray and falls out, and shattering pains wrack the body. The victim physically ages by 10 years, and suffers 7k7 Wounds. The wounds can be healed normally, but the aging cannot be reversed. A character unfortunate enough to be hit by this spell multiple times (and survive) will be left elderly and decrepit.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
	<SpellDef name="[MAHO] Strength Of Darkness" area="One target person" mastery="5" element="fire" range="Personal / Touch" duration="10 rounds" id="maho_strength_of_darkness">
		<Tags>
			<Tag>maho</Tag>
		</Tags>
		<Raises>
			<Raise>Duration (+1 Round per Raise)</Raise>
			<Raise>Special (+1 Rank to one physical Trait for every 2 Raises)</Raise>
		</Raises>
		<Description>This spell infuses me body of the target with the power of the Taint, unnaturally enhancing his physical prowess for a short time, allowing him to perform superhuman feats of speed, strength, and stamina. The recipient of the spell gains + 1 Rank to his Earth Ring and his other three physical Traits for the duration of the spell. (The caster may Raise to increase the Traits, but the Earth Ring cannot be increased further.) He also gains the ability to see through any sort of visual impairment - fog, smoke, or even complete darkness. The physical evidence of this magical enhancement is obvious and grotesque - the target's flesh swells and bulges unnaturally and his eyes turn blood-red. This spell increases the target's Wounds per Rank to match his enhanced Earth Rank. When the spell expires and the Earth Ring drops back to normal, the target's Wounds also return to normal levels. This can result in death if he has suffered serious damage while under the spell's effects.</Description>
	</SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Heart Of The Damned" area="Caster" mastery="1" element="earth" range="Touch" duration="Instantaneous" id="maho_heart_of_the_damned">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Description>A foul necromantic ritual, first practiced by Iuchiban himself, this spell calls on the strength of the dead to enhance the living. The caster must touch a recently-dead human corpse (dead within the last day) when casting the spell. The corpse shrivels and rots away as the caster draws on its essence, reddish-black energy flowing out of the dead body and into the caster. The caster heals 2k2 Wounds and regains 1 Rank in any Ring or Trait which has been reduced below its normal level.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Purge The Weak" area="Food and water for up to 5 people" mastery="1" element="earth" range="50 feet" duration="Permanent" id="maho_purge_the_weak">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Range (+20 feet per Raise)</Raise>
      <Raise>Area of Effect (supplies for 1 additional person per Raise)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>This unpleasant curse ruins food and drink, rendering it foul, diseased, and inedible. The effects of the spell are obvious  food becomes rotten, water turns foul and discolored, and so forth. The food and water lose all nutritional value and anyone who eats or drinks must roll Stamina at TN 20 or become severely ill, suffering a 3k0 penalty to all Skill, Trait, and Spell Casting rolls. The illness is incurable with medical treatment and will last for two weeks unless magically cured.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Suck The Marrow" area="One target creature" mastery="1" element="earth" range="Touch" duration="1 day" id="maho_suck_the_marrow">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Duration (+1 day per 2 Raises)</Raise>
      <Raise>Range (change to 50 feet for 2 Raises)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>This unpleasant curse impedes the victims ability to heal and recover from injury and sickness. The victim becomes pale and weak, exuding an unpleasant body odor, and is unable to heal Wounds normally or from applications of the Medicine skill. The victim also is unable to recover from illnesses or poisons, and suffers a 2k0 penalty to any roll made to resist the effects of a poison or disease. Magical healing can still affect the target normally.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Symbol Of Blood" area="30 foot radius" mastery="1" element="water" range="Touch" duration="12 hours" id="maho_symbol_of_blood">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Area of Effect (+5 feet per Raise)</Raise>
      <Raise>Duration (+2 hours per Raise)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>This spell inscribes a sinister ward onto a flat surface. The caster writes the ward in the blood he spill to cast the spell, and once inscribed the ward cannot be destroyed except by physically destroying the surface on which it is written. The ward causes its victims blood to become sluggish and cold. Anyone other than the caster who enters the area of effect suffers a 2k0 penalty to all physical Actions. The effect only applies while they are within the area of effect, and does not stack with other Symbols of Blood.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Curse Of The Clan" area="One target samurai" mastery="2" element="air" range="50 feet" duration="1 month" id="maho_curse_of_the_clan">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Duration (+10 days per Raise)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>This subtle curse causes a samurai to manifest his clans most stereotypical and notorious behavior. For example, a Crab might become more crude, intolerant, and ruthlessly pragmatic, while a Phoenix might become more arrogant and obsessed with magical power. The changes are significant but not overwhelming, and the victim of the spell will try to rationalize and justify his behavior. If a PC is targeted with this spell the GM should present the situation as a role-playing challenge rather than dictating how the character is played.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Curse Of The Kansen" area="One target creature" mastery="2" element="air" range="50 feet" duration="8 hours" id="maho_curse_of_the_kansen">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Range (+10 feet per Raise)</Raise>
      <Raise>Duration (+1 hour per Raise)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>This curse subtly attracts hostile kansen to harass the target. The spells victim begins hearing constant whispers inside his head, voices urging him to sinful and corrupt behavior. The continual distraction causes him to suffer a 1k0 penalty to all Courtier, Etiquette, and Sincerity rolls. If he is rolling to resist the Temptation Skill, the penalty is 2k0 instead. (This effect stacks with the maho spell Sinful Dreams.) If the optional Honor Roll rule is in effect, the victim of this spell also suffers a penalty of -1k0 to Honor Rolls.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Gift Of The Maker" area="One target creature (can be the caster)" mastery="2" element="fire" range="Self;Touch" duration="1 hour" id="maho_gift_of_the_maker">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Duration (+30 minutes per Raise)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>The caster summons the power of Jigoku, temporarily granting the blessings of the Taint. Most Bloodspeakers rationalize this spells effects by claiming it is evoking power from within themselves. The caster (or another person touched by the caster) gains a Greater Shadowlands Power of his choice for the duration of the spell.</Description>
  </SpellDef>  
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Dark Wings" area="Caster" mastery="2" element="water" range="Self" duration="10 minutes" id="maho_dark_wings">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Duration (+2 minutes per Raise)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>The caster sprouts monstrous wings from his back, resembling those of a bat or other such creature. For the duration of the spell the caster can fly, and is considered to have Swift 3 (as per the creature ability from the Book of Void, L5R 4th Edition core rulebook) while flying.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Dancing With Demons" area="Self;one target creature" mastery="3" element="air" range="500 feet" duration="24 hours" id="maho_dancing_with_demons">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Duration (+6 hours per Raise)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>A ritual spell first used by the notorious Doji Nashiko, this spell is also employed by many other maho-tsukai, and has found its way into the repertoire of several Bloodspeaker Cult cells. The spell is a ritual and requires the caster to dance for at least an hour (rolling Perform: Dance / Awareness at TN 25) while casting  if the dance is interrupted or the Skill roll is unsuccessful, the spell fails. However, if the spell succeeds, the caster may choose either to gain a Physical or Mental Advantage for the duration of the spell, or inflict a Physical or Mental Disadvantage on another person within range for the duration of the spell. (The caster need not be able to see the target so long as he is within range.) The maximum Experience Point value of an Advantage or Disadvantage created by the spell is equal to the casters Air + Insight Rank + Taint Rank, if any. This spell cannot make extreme physical changes to the target, such as removing limbs or organs (e.g. it cannot inflict Disadvantages like Missing Eye). The GM should exercise intelligent judgment in considering its effects.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Mists Of Fear" area="One target creature" mastery="3" element="air" range="50 feet" duration="Instantaneous" id="maho_mists_of_fear">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Special (Increase Fear effect strength by 1 per Raise)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>This spell summons forth a potent illusion of whatever the target fears most in the world. The illusion is present for only a few moments and can only be perceived by the target, who must roll against a Fear 5 effect. If the target suffers from a Phobia the spell will also activate its effects.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Symbol Of The Bloodspeaker" area="50 foot radius" mastery="3" element="air" range="Touch" duration="12 hours" id="maho_symbol_of_the_bloodspeaker">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>None</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>The Bloodspeaker Cult uses this spell to protect their meeting places against unwanted intrusion. The symbol must be inscribed into a fl at surface (wall, floor, etc) when it is cast. The moment anyone who is not a loyal member of the Bloodspeaker Cult enters the symbols radius, the symbol glows a bright sickly green and the intruder is bathed in eerie green flames, inflicting 4k3 damage. The symbol can discharge any number of times against different targets, but each target can only be affected once within the duration of the spell.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] No Pure Breaths" area="One target creature" mastery="4" element="air" range="100 feet" duration="Instantaneous (but see below)" id="maho_no_pure_breaths">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Damage (+1k0 per Raise)</Raise>
      <Raise>Range (+20 feet per Raise)</Raise>
      <Raise>Targets (+1 target per 2 Raises)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>No Pure Breaths was a Mastery 4 maho air spell which allowed the maho-tsukai to summon the Air within a target and force it out. The target literally exploded or more often the spell simply ruptured lungs and stomachs, causing internal bleeding.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Stealing The Soul" area="One target person" mastery="4" element="earth" range="1 mile" duration="1 day" id="maho_stealing_the_soul">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Special (+1 additional Rank of Trait drain per 2 raises)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>Stealing the Soul was a Mastery 4 maho fire spell which allowed the caster to weaken another person's physical and mental abilities. This spell was most notoriously used in the assassination of the legendary Crab Clan Champion Hida Shonojo, weakening him enough to ensure the success of the attack.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Tomb Of Earth" area="One target creature" mastery="4" element="earth" range="50 feet" duration="Conditional (see below)" id="maho_tomb_of_earth">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Damage (+1k0 to damage per Raise)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>This spell is a perverse inversion of the elemental spell Tomb of Jade. Instead of targeting those with the Taint, it targets those who are pure of soul  the spell cannot affect anyone who has at least one full Rank of Taint. The victim of Tomb of Earth is held immobile as he begins turning to stone, beginning with the skin and working its way inward. Each Round (including the Round the spell is cast) on the casters Turn, the caster makes an Opposed Roll of his Insight / Earth against the targets Insight / Air. If the caster wins, the target remains immobilized by the spell (unable to take Actions of any kind) and suffers 2k2 damage. If the target wins, the spells effects end. If the target is killed by the spell, he is turned completely to stone, which crumbles to dust within 24 hours.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Burning Blood" area="One target creature" mastery="4" element="fire" range="50 feet" duration="Instantaneous" id="maho_burning_blood">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Dmage (+1k0 per Raise)</Raise>
      <Raise>Range (+10 feet per Raise)</Raise>
      <Raise>Targets (+1 target per 3 Raises)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>This horrible spell infuses the targets bloodstream with angry Fire kansen, causing his blood to superheat and boil through his skin, emerging as a cloud of reddish vapor. The target suffers Wounds with a DR equal to his Fire, and must roll Willpower at TN 20 or fall Prone due to the unbearable pain. Whether or not the target falls prone, he is considered to be Fatigued on his next two Turns, due to the debilitating effect of the boiling blood.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Blood Armor" area="Caster and one target creature" mastery="5" element="earth" range="50 feet" duration="3 Rounds" id="maho_blood_armor">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Duration (+1 Round per 2 Raises)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>This is an extremely vicious defensive spell which high-ranking Bloodspeaker leaders frequently use to defend themselves. When the spell is cast, the maho-tsukai chooses one living target within range. For the duration of the spell, any time the caster suffers Wounds from any source, he only takes 25% of the damage rolled (rounded down). The target of the spell takes the other 75% (rounded up). Casting this spell does not produce any obvious visual effect, but each time the spell shifts damage to the target, the caster glows with unholy reddish-black energy, while appropriate injuries (burns, cuts, etc) spontaneously appear on the target. This spell works on all Wound damage, even from spells like Jade Strike that normally could not hurt the target.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Fierce Blood Of The Earth" area="Caster" mastery="5" element="earth" range="Touch" duration="Instantaneous" id="maho_fierce_blood_of_the_earth">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Duration (+6 hours per 2 Raises)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>A hideous and blasphemous spell that many Bloodspeakers use to artificially extend their lifespans. The caster touches one living being, who must be either willing or physically helpless (securely bound, asleep, or unconscious). The caster must make an Opposed Earth Roll against an unwilling victim. If the spell is successful, the maho-tsukai consumes the victims life force, killing him instantly. In return, the caster heals all physical injuries, regrows any missing limbs or organs, and extends his life by one year. Although this spell has no obvious or immediate side-effects, using it repeatedly will have a price  the maho-tsukai will acquire a desiccated, almost mummified appearance, making his true nature increasingly difficult to conceal.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Ward of Divine Peace" area="50 foot radius" mastery="1" element="air" range="Touch" duration="8 hours" id="maho_ward_of_divine_peace">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Area of Effect (+10 foot radius)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>This spell is favored by Bloodspeaker cell leaders, who use it to maintain psychological dominance over their followers. The spells name is an ironic joke within the cults ranks. The spell creates a false aura of calm and well-being that lasts for several hours. This makes it difficult for them to focus their attention or resist appeals from others. Anyone who is within the spells area of effect, or who enters it while the spell is in effect, suffers a 1k0 penalty to all Skill and Trait rolls that use Awareness or Willpower. This penalty lasts until the end of the spells duration, but does not stack with itself.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
  <SpellDef name="[MAHO] Take The Body" area="Caster and one target person" mastery="6" element="air" range="500 feet" duration="Permanent" id="maho_take_the_body">
    <Tags>
      <Tag>maho</Tag>
    </Tags>
    <Raises>
      <Raise>Range (+500 feet per Raise)</Raise>
      <Raise>Special (cast as a single Simple Action with 4 Raises)</Raise>
    </Raises>
    <Description>This spell is, to the best of anyones knowledge, known only to two people  Iuchiban and Yajinden. They have guarded its secrets carefully and so far no other maho-tsukai has ever exhibited its power. The spell allows the caster to literally leap his soul into the body of another person within range, instantly and permanently taking their body as his own. The caster must succeed in a Contested Willpower roll against the victim, and if the victim wins, the caster is hurled back into his current body. (The victim will be very much aware that he just fought off some kind of terrible all-consuming power.) The spell does not normally cause the souls to switch the abandoned body simply falls dead. The fate of the original soul is unknown, and some Rokugani believe it may actually be destroyed, a truly horrific and blasphemous act. There are some reports of powerful Lost or maho-tsukai being able to switch into the other body rather than be destroyed, but these tales are not confirmed. The occupied body retains its physical Traits and physical Advantages and Disadvantages, but instantly acquires the mental Traits and Void of the caster, along with all of the casters Skills and any Mental or Spiritual Advantages and Disadvantages the caster may have. (Social Advantages or Disadvantages may or may not persist  the GM should adjudicate such situations.) If the maho-tsukai remains within the same body for an extended period of time (six months or more) it will gradually change to physically resemble the casters original physical form, changing Rings, Traits, and Advantages as appropriate.</Description>
  </SpellDef>
</L5RCM>
