<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<L5RCM>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_balance" name="Balance">
    <Description>This tattoo of the spiritual yin-yang symbol
calms the mind and spirit. While this tattoo is active,
the TN of all Spell Casting Rolls made with you as
the target are increased or decreased by an amount
equal to twice your School Rank plus 5. You determine
whether this is an increase or a decrease when
you activate the tattoo.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_bamboo" name="Bamboo">
    <Description>The bamboo plant is ubiquitous throughout
the Empire, and is well known not only for the speed
with which it grows, but also its durability. While this
tattoo is active, your Armor TN is increased by an
amount equal to twice your School Rank + 5.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_blaze" name="Blaze">
    <Description>The power and fury of fire is unleashed in
the Blaze tattoo. When activated, this tattoo causes
your unarmed strikes to be bolstered with pure fire.
Your unarmed attacks are accompanied by flickering
fl ames that inflict an additional amount of fire damage
equal to your Fire Ring plus your School Rank.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_centipede" name="Centipede">
    <Description>The tiny centipede has hundreds of legs
working in unison, and that power can be commanded
by the monks who bear its image. When this
tattoo is activated, you may make a special Complex
Move Action that allows you to move a distance
equal to your Water Ring x 100'. This effect lasts for
an entire day, essentially allowing you to cross the
face of the Empire in a day. If you stop for more than
one minute, the effect ends. When the effect ends,
you collapse into an exhausted state and can take no
physical actions for a period of twelve hours.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_crab" name="Crab">
    <Description>The tiny crab is resilient beyond all measure
for its size. While this tattoo is active, you gain a
Reduction rating equal to your Earth Ring.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_crane" name="Crane">
    <Description>The crane is a symbol of luck and beauty.
When you activate this tattoo, you gain a number of
bonus dice equal to your School Rank plus your Air
Ring. These dice may be spent on any Social Skill
Rolls. Each die contributes a bonus of +1k0. If these
bonus dice are not used within an hour, they are lost.
You may not add more bonus dice to a single roll
than your Void Ring. This tattoo is considered active
the entire hour, and if another tattoo is activated,
any unspent dice from this tattoo are lost.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_dragon" name="Dragon">
    <Description>The dragon is a fearsome tattoo, and contains
frightening power waiting to be unleashed. As
a Complex Action, you may breathe fire in a cone,
equal to ten feet plus your School Rank in length,
and fi ve feet wide at the end. This fire deals damage
to all in its area of effect, with a DR equal your Fire
Ring. You take damage equal to your Fire Ring upon
each use.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_hawk" name="Hawk">
    <Description>You may borrow the essence of the hawk,
and cover great distances with ease. As a Complex
Action, you may leap a distance equal to your Water
Ring x 25'.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_kirin" name="Ki-Rin">
    <Description>There are few omens of good fortune more
signifi cant than that of the sacred ki-rin. Upon activating
this tattoo, you may immediately re-roll any
one roll per round, keeping the higher of the two
results.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_lion" name="Lion">
    <Description>The lion is a proud and noble warrior. Upon
activating this tattoo, you gain ranks equal to your
School Rank in any Bugei Skill of your choice.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_mantis" name="Mantis">
    <Description>The mantis is a fierce and fearless warrior
out of all proportion to its tiny size. Upon receiving
this tattoo, you are completely immune to all Fear
effects. This tattoo is active at all times, and does not
prevent the use of other tattoos.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_mountain" name="Mountain">
    <Description>The mountain is eternal and unmoving.
When you activate this tattoo, all your Wound
Penalties are reduced by an amount equal to your
School Rank plus 2.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_ocean" name="Ocean">
    <Description>The ocean's boundless depths hold the secrets
of life and rejuvenation. When granted this tattoo,
you no longer have need of food or drink, although
you may still partake of them if you wish. When this
tattoo is activated, you are instantly refreshed as if
you had spent eight hours of sleep, and you regain
all spent Void Points. This tattoo may only be used
once every three days.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_phoenix" name="Phoenix">
    <Description>The Phoenix can never truly be defeated,
rising as it does from the ashes to be born anew. You
must have at least one unspent Void Point for this
tattoo to be triggered. When you are reduced to the
Down Wound Level or below, this tattoo automatically
activates. All unspent Void Points are lost, and
you immediately heal a number of Wounds equal to
your School Rank x 10. This tattoo cannot be activated
more than once per week.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_scorpion" name="Scorpion">
    <Description>The scorpion is silent and deadly. While
this tattoo is active, you roll additional dice on any
Stealth Skill Roll equal to your School Rank. Also,
during this time your unarmed attacks automatically
Daze your opponent if any dice explode on your damage
roll.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_spider" name="Spider">
    <Description>The spider is quick and dexterous, escaping
predators with its speed and agility. While this tattoo
is active, you may move across vertical and inverted
surfaces (such as sheer walls or ceilings) while making
Move Actions. You move at half your normal rate
when doing so.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_storm" name="Storm">
    <Description>The storm is nature's fury, and few can stand
against its raw power. While this tattoo is active,
your unarmed attacks require only one Raise to use
the Knockdown Maneuver.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_void" name="Void">
    <Description>This ink black kanji represents oneness with
all. When this tattoo is activated, you gain awareness
of all life around you. You know the location
and rough details of all living things within a radius
of your School Rank x 10', even if you cannot see
them. You know only rough details, such as “two
warriors” or “a pair of rabbits,” not specifi c identities.
You can recognize individuals well-known to
you, however.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_wind" name="Wind">
    <Description>The wind is swift and moves without hindrance.
While this tattoo is active, you gain an additional
Simple Action per round, which may not be
used to make an attack. Your maximum total movement
is not limited to your Water Ring x 20.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
  <KihoDef type="tattoo" id="tattoo_wolf" name="Wolf">
    <Description>The wolf is the great tracker of the wilds.
When you activate this tattoo, your senses become
superhumanly sharp, allowing you to perceive small
details and even individual scents. You gain a number
of Free Raises on Hunting (Tracking) Skill Rolls
equal to your School Rank. This tattoo's effect lasts a
number of hours equal to your School Rank.</Description>
  </KihoDef>
</L5RCM>
